[
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-001",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 1,
        "question": "12.75% is equivalent to",
        "options": {
            "A": "17/200",
            "B": "41/400",
            "C": "51/400",
            "D": "37/400"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "51/400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-002",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 2,
        "question": "5% of 2% of 3 is equal to",
        "options": {
            "A": "0.03",
            "B": "0.3",
            "C": "3",
            "D": "0.003"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "0.003",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-003",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 3,
        "question": "Which of the following is the least?",
        "options": {
            "A": "12% of 625",
            "B": "15% of 555",
            "C": "10% of 720",
            "D": "9% of 845"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10% of 720",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-004",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 4,
        "question": "If 10% of 24% of x is 240, then x = ?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10000",
            "B": "100",
            "C": "1000",
            "D": "100000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-005",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 5,
        "question": "If 45% of 50% of a number is 27, then what is the number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "160",
            "B": "180",
            "C": "150",
            "D": "120"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "120",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-006",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 6,
        "question": "By how much is 60% of 75 greater than 1/5 of 25?",
        "options": {
            "A": "37",
            "B": "38",
            "C": "40",
            "D": "34"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-007",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 7,
        "question": "What is the ratio between S and T if S is 75% of T?",
        "options": {
            "A": "4 : 3",
            "B": "2 : 3",
            "C": "75 : 1",
            "D": "3 : 4"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "3 : 4",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-008",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 8,
        "question": "If 18 toys out of 75 toys are for boys and the rest are for girls, what is the percentage of girls toys?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18%",
            "B": "67%",
            "C": "57%",
            "D": "76%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "76%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-009",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 9,
        "question": "In a class, the numbers of boys and girls are in the ratio of 3 : 5. What is the percentage of boys?",
        "options": {
            "A": "37.5%",
            "B": "60%",
            "C": "42.5%",
            "D": "12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "37.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-010",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 10,
        "question": "The cost price of an item increased from \u20b92,500 to \u20b93,000. Find the percentage increase.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-011",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 11,
        "question": "If a person's salary increases from \u20b9200 per day to \u20b9234 per day, then the percentage increase in the person's salary is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "17%",
            "C": "14%",
            "D": "16%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "17%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-012",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 12,
        "question": "Mahesh's annual salary increased from \u20b92,00,000 to \u20b92,40,000. Find the percentage increase in the salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "22%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "24%",
            "D": "18%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-013",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 13,
        "question": "Shantanu's income decreased from Rs 42,800 to Rs 37,236. Find the percentage decrease in his income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "13%",
            "B": "14%",
            "C": "11%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "13%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-014",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 14,
        "question": "Monthly expenditure of Ritvik decreases from \u20b912,800 to \u20b911,712. Find the percentage decrease in his expenditure.",
        "options": {
            "A": "9.25%",
            "B": "6.25%",
            "C": "7.7%",
            "D": "8.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "8.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-015",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 15,
        "question": "Last year, Ranjan's monthly salary was \u20b934,500 and this year his monthly salary is \u20b938,640. What is the percentage increase in Ranjan's monthly salary this year over his monthly salary last year?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "13%",
            "C": "12%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-016",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 16,
        "question": "Shiya invests \u20b91,53,000, which is 30% of her annual income, in mutual funds. What is her monthly income (in \u20b9)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "52300",
            "B": "45800",
            "C": "55600",
            "D": "42500"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "42500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-017",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 17,
        "question": "An interval of 2 hours 25 minutes is wrongly estimated by 2 hours 30.5 minutes. The error percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "2 21/29%",
            "B": "3 19/29%",
            "C": "3 23/29%",
            "D": "2 27/29%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "3 23/29%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-018",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 18,
        "question": "The population of a city was 5000000 in 2020. The population grows 7.5% annually. The population in 2022 is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "5778125",
            "B": "5757215",
            "C": "5558875",
            "D": "5887125"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "5778125",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-019",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 19,
        "question": "If an increase of 9% in salary, a person received \u20b96300. What was his salary before increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95000",
            "B": "\u20b95779",
            "C": "\u20b93879",
            "D": "\u20b94000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b95779",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-020",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 20,
        "question": "R gives 3/8 of the toffees he has to S. If now R has k% of the toffees with S, then find the value of k.",
        "options": {
            "A": "200/3",
            "B": "500/3",
            "C": "140/3",
            "D": "230/3"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "500/3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-021",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 21,
        "question": "If 30% of Ravi's income is equal to 40% of Suresh's income, then 50% of Ravi's income is equal to what percentage of Suresh's income?",
        "options": {
            "A": "66 2/3%",
            "B": "33 2/3%",
            "C": "66 1/3%",
            "D": "33 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "66 2/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-022",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 22,
        "question": "A number increased by 20% gives 240. Find the number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "200",
            "B": "280",
            "C": "240",
            "D": "250"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-023",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 23,
        "question": "When a number is increased by 8, it becomes 120% of itself. The number is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "30",
            "B": "60",
            "C": "40",
            "D": "50"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-024",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 24,
        "question": "When 12 is subtracted from a number, it reduces to its 40%. Two-fifth of that number is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "20",
            "B": "8",
            "C": "12",
            "D": "50"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "12",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-025",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 25,
        "question": "If 70 is subtracted from 70% of a number, the remainder is 70. What is the number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "400",
            "B": "100",
            "C": "300",
            "D": "200"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-026",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 26,
        "question": "Two numbers are respectively 10% and 25% more than the third number. Find the ratio of the two numbers.",
        "options": {
            "A": "22 : 25",
            "B": "19 : 25",
            "C": "23 : 25",
            "D": "18 : 25"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "22 : 25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-027",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 27,
        "question": "Two numbers are respectively 61% and 35% less than a third number. The first number is what percent of the second number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "60%",
            "B": "24%",
            "C": "48%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-028",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 28,
        "question": "In an engineering college, the ratio of students in CS, EC, CE, and ME branches is 11 : 5 : 6 : 7. What is the percentage of students belonging to CS and ME branches together?",
        "options": {
            "A": "61.07%",
            "B": "62.37%",
            "C": "62.07%",
            "D": "61.37%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "62.37%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-029",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 29,
        "question": "What number must be added to 20% of 460 to have the sum as 70% of 920?",
        "options": {
            "A": "335",
            "B": "762",
            "C": "926",
            "D": "552"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "552",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-030",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 30,
        "question": "If the income of P is 40% less than Q, then the combined income of P and Q is how much percent more than the income of P?",
        "options": {
            "A": "166 2/3%",
            "B": "164 1/3%",
            "C": "166 1/3%",
            "D": "164 2/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "166 2/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-031",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 31,
        "question": "To increase a number by 25%, by what number should that number be multiplied?",
        "options": {
            "A": "3",
            "B": "2/5",
            "C": "5/4",
            "D": "3/4"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5/4",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-032",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 32,
        "question": "A man multiplied a number by 8/5 instead of 5/8. What is the percentage error in the calculation?",
        "options": {
            "A": "124%",
            "B": "162%",
            "C": "156%",
            "D": "100%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "156%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-033",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 33,
        "question": "A quantity 4/5 is changed to 5/6. How much percentage change is given to the quantity?",
        "options": {
            "A": "4.73%",
            "B": "4.71%",
            "C": "4.17%",
            "D": "4.37%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "4.17%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-034",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 34,
        "question": "A pupil multiplied a figure by 3/5 rather than 5/3. What is the percentage error in the calculation?",
        "options": {
            "A": "64%",
            "B": "47%",
            "C": "58%",
            "D": "52%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "64%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-035",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 35,
        "question": "By mistake, the reciprocal of a positive fraction got typed in place of itself, and thereby its value got reduced by 175/4%. What was the value of the fraction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1/2",
            "B": "4/3",
            "C": "3/4",
            "D": "1/4"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4/3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-036",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 36,
        "question": "A fraction 3/5 is decreased by 2/5. The resulting fraction is then increased by 20%. What is the percentage decrease/increase in the value of the original fraction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Increase 60%",
            "B": "Decrease 50%",
            "C": "Increase 50%",
            "D": "Decrease 60%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Decrease 60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-037",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 37,
        "question": "In a sweet, one-third is sugar. If the price of sugar now is 7/6 of the previous price, what is the effective percentage increase in the cost of the sweet?",
        "options": {
            "A": "100/9%",
            "B": "100/5%",
            "C": "100/18%",
            "D": "100/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "100/18%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-038",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 38,
        "question": "Ramesh spent \u20b930,000 on Diwali shopping and \u20b945,000 on buying a TV set, and spent the remaining 40% of his total amount. What was the total amount he had?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,22,000",
            "B": "\u20b91,25,000",
            "C": "\u20b91,35,000",
            "D": "\u20b91,10,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91,25,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-039",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 39,
        "question": "If the numerator of a fraction is increased by 12% and its denominator is decreased by 8%, it gives a new fraction 16/17. What is the original fraction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "92/119",
            "B": "23/28",
            "C": "28/23",
            "D": "119/92"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "92/119",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-040",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 40,
        "question": "If the numerator of a fraction is increased by 140% and the denominator is decreased by 20%, the resultant fraction is 12/7. Find the original fraction.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4/9",
            "B": "4/7",
            "C": "7/6",
            "D": "8/9"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4/7",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-041",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 41,
        "question": "If the numerator of a fraction be increased by 50% and denominator be diminished by 28%, the value of the fraction is 25/36. Find the original fraction.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5/2",
            "B": "2/3",
            "C": "2/5",
            "D": "1/3"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "1/3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T1-042",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-I",
        "question_number": 42,
        "question": "If the numerator of a fraction is increased by 60% and denominator is increased by 40%, the resultant fraction is 16/63. The original fraction is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "2/9",
            "B": "3/9",
            "C": "2/11",
            "D": "4/9"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2/9",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-043",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 43,
        "question": "The salary of employees in a factory was reduced by 20% due to economic crisis. In order to have their salary back to original amount, it must be raised by:",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "4%",
            "D": "12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-044",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 44,
        "question": "If Ramu's salary is 30% less than Somu's salary, then by how much percent is Somu's salary more than Ramu's salary?",
        "options": {
            "A": "45.47%",
            "B": "42.86%",
            "C": "42.67%",
            "D": "34.56%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "42.86%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-045",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 45,
        "question": "Shyam's income is 20% less than Ram's. How much is Ram's income more than Shyam's income in percentage terms?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "80%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-046",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 46,
        "question": "If the income of Neha is 5% more than that of Monica, then the income of Monica is what percentage less than that of Neha?",
        "options": {
            "A": "4 13/21%",
            "B": "4 16/21%",
            "C": "4 11/21%",
            "D": "4 5/21%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4 16/21%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-047",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 47,
        "question": "Ram's income is 2.5% more than Shyam's income. By what percentage is Shyam's income less than Ram's income?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.43%",
            "B": "3.43%",
            "C": "1.43%",
            "D": "4.43%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2.43%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T2-048",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-II",
        "question_number": 48,
        "question": "What percentage should a racer increase the speed to reduce the time by 25% to cover a fixed distance?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33 1/3%",
            "B": "37 1/3%",
            "C": "41%",
            "D": "31%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "33 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-049",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 49,
        "question": "The radius of a circle is increased by 20%. Find the percentage increase in the circumference of the circle.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-050",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 50,
        "question": "If each side of a cube is decreased by 12%, then the percentage increase in the total surface area is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "25.66%",
            "B": "28.23%",
            "C": "23.56%",
            "D": "26.54%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "23.56%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-051",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 51,
        "question": "If the radius of a sphere is increased by 5%, then by what percentage will the surface area of the sphere increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10.25%",
            "B": "15.25%",
            "C": "13.25%",
            "D": "11.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "11.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-052",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 52,
        "question": "The radius of a sphere is increased by 25%. What is the increase percent in surface area?",
        "options": {
            "A": "56.25%",
            "B": "15.55%",
            "C": "25.25%",
            "D": "36.45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "56.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-053",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 53,
        "question": "If the side of a square is increased by 5%, then the percentage increase in its area will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "10.25%",
            "B": "11%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "10.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-054",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 54,
        "question": "The breadth of a rectangular lawn is decreased by 8% and its length is increased by 15%. Find the percentage change in the lawn area.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8.5% increase",
            "B": "8.5% decrease",
            "C": "5.8% decrease",
            "D": "5.8% increase"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5.8% decrease",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-055",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 55,
        "question": "The radius of a circle is increased in such a way that its circumference increases by 7%. As a result, the area of the circle also increases by:",
        "options": {
            "A": "12.20%",
            "B": "10.25%",
            "C": "14.49%",
            "D": "18.49%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "14.49%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-056",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 56,
        "question": "If the length of a rectangle is decreased by 13% and the breadth is increased by 13%, find the change of percentage in its area.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.69% decrease",
            "B": "1.69% increase",
            "C": "No change",
            "D": "13% decrease"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "No change",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-057",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 57,
        "question": "If radius of a sphere is decreased by 48%, then by what percent does its surface area decrease?",
        "options": {
            "A": "82.91%",
            "B": "72.96%",
            "C": "78.98%",
            "D": "86.26%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "78.98%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-058",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 58,
        "question": "The length and breadth of a rectangle are increased by 8% and 5% respectively. By how much percent will the area of the rectangle increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "13.4%",
            "B": "15.4%",
            "C": "12.4%",
            "D": "16.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-059",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 59,
        "question": "The length and breadth of a rectangle decrease by 8% and 10% respectively. What is the percentage increase or decrease in its area?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease by 1.8%",
            "B": "Increase by 1.8%",
            "C": "Increase by 2.8%",
            "D": "Decrease by 2.8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Increase by 2.8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-060",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 60,
        "question": "The base of a triangle is increased by 40%. By what percentage should its height be increased so that the area increases by 60%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15.54%",
            "B": "20.01%",
            "C": "14.28%",
            "D": "18.62%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "15.54%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-061",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 61,
        "question": "If the radius of a sphere is increased by 16 2/3%, then by what percent would its surface area increase (correct to one decimal place)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33.9%",
            "B": "35.6%",
            "C": "34.8%",
            "D": "36.1%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "36.1%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-062",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 62,
        "question": "Find the percentage increase in surface area of a cube by triple each side.",
        "options": {
            "A": "800%",
            "B": "500%",
            "C": "700%",
            "D": "650%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "800%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-063",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 63,
        "question": "If the radius of a sphere is doubled, then its surface area will be increased by:",
        "options": {
            "A": "200%",
            "B": "100%",
            "C": "300%",
            "D": "400%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "300%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-064",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 64,
        "question": "If the area of a square is decreased by 19%, then the diagonal of the square is decreased by:",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-065",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 65,
        "question": "If the radius of a sphere is increased by 12%, then the volume will be increased by approximately:",
        "options": {
            "A": "42.5%",
            "B": "45.49%",
            "C": "40.49%",
            "D": "41.49%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "40.49%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-066",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 66,
        "question": "If the radius of a sphere is increased by 20%, then find the percentage increase in its volume.",
        "options": {
            "A": "70.6%",
            "B": "75.5%",
            "C": "72.8%",
            "D": "68.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "72.8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-067",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 67,
        "question": "If the length and breadth of a cuboid are increased by 6% and 8% respectively, then the percentage increase in its volume [correct to two decimal places] is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "13.96%",
            "B": "12.96%",
            "C": "14.48%",
            "D": "11.48%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "14.48%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-068",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 68,
        "question": "The radius and the height of a right circular cone is increased by 25%. Find the increase in percentage of volume of the cone (rounded off to 2 decimal places).",
        "options": {
            "A": "94.51%",
            "B": "95.31%",
            "C": "93.51%",
            "D": "94.31%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "95.31%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-069",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 69,
        "question": "The diameter of a sphere is increased by 30%. What is the percentage increase in its volume?",
        "options": {
            "A": "90.5%",
            "B": "41.7%",
            "C": "119.7%",
            "D": "69%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "119.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-070",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 70,
        "question": "If the base radius and height of a right circular cone are increased by 10%, then the percentage increase in the volume is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "33.1%",
            "B": "20.2%",
            "C": "22.1%",
            "D": "30.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "33.1%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-071",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 71,
        "question": "The length and breadth of a cuboid is increased by 20% and 25%, respectively, while its height is reduced by 30%. What must be the total percentage increase/decrease in the volume of the cuboid?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Increase by 5%",
            "B": "Increase by 3%",
            "C": "Decrease by 2%",
            "D": "Decrease by 4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Increase by 5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T3-072",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-III",
        "question_number": 72,
        "question": "The total percentage change in the volume of a cuboid if its length and breadth are decreased by 15% and 25%, respectively, while its height is increased by 60%, is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "5% decrease",
            "B": "2% decrease",
            "C": "5% increase",
            "D": "2% increase"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2% increase",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-073",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 73,
        "question": "Ram's salary was decreased by 50% and subsequently increased by 50%, then how much percent did he lose?",
        "options": {
            "A": "36%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-074",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 74,
        "question": "Two successive price increases of 25% and 25% are equivalent to a single price increase of:",
        "options": {
            "A": "52.25%",
            "B": "50.25%",
            "C": "56.25%",
            "D": "48.50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "56.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-075",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 75,
        "question": "Ravi's salary was increased by 50%. After some time, his new salary was also increased by 50%. Find his gain percent of salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "125%",
            "B": "100%",
            "C": "200%",
            "D": "150%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "125%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-076",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 76,
        "question": "The salary of an employee is increased by 10% and then the increased salary is reduced by 10%. The percentage loss in the salary of the employee is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "1%",
            "B": "3%",
            "C": "2%",
            "D": "4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-077",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 77,
        "question": "A number is increased by 25% and then decreased by 16%. By what percentage is the resulting number less than/more than the original number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Does not change",
            "B": "Decreases by 5%",
            "C": "Increases by 5%",
            "D": "Decreases by 13%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Increases by 5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-078",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 78,
        "question": "The salary of a worker is first increased by 25%, then it is decreased by 12%. The percentage change in his salary is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "10% increase",
            "B": "13% increase",
            "C": "10% decrease",
            "D": "13% decrease"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10% increase",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-079",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 79,
        "question": "In a company, all employees are getting equal wages. If the number of employees is increased by 20% and their wage per head decreases by 18%, what is the percentage decrease in total wages?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.4%",
            "B": "1%",
            "C": "1.6%",
            "D": "1.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1.6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-080",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 80,
        "question": "If price of an article increases successively by 15% and 10%, respectively, then what is the percentage equivalent to a single price increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "26.5%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "23.5%",
            "D": "12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "26.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-081",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 81,
        "question": "The population of a town first decreased by 16% due to migration. The next year, the population increased by 21%. What is the net percentage change (correct to 2 decimal places) in the population?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease by 2.54%",
            "B": "Increase by 2.54%",
            "C": "Increase by 1.64%",
            "D": "Decrease by 1.64%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Increase by 1.64%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-082",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 82,
        "question": "A number is first increased by 44% and then decreased by 30%. The net percentage change (rounded off to the nearest integer) in the original number is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Increase by 1%",
            "B": "Decrease by 4%",
            "C": "Increase by 4%",
            "D": "Decrease by 1%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Increase by 1%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-083",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 83,
        "question": "The price of an article is first increased by 45% and then decreased by 45%. Due to reduction in sales, find the net percentage change in the final price of the article.",
        "options": {
            "A": "-12%",
            "B": "13%",
            "C": "-23%",
            "D": "23%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "-23%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-084",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 84,
        "question": "A number is first decreased by 18% and then increased by 25%. What is the overall percentage change in the original number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease by 2.5%",
            "B": "Increase by 3.5%",
            "C": "Increase by 2.5%",
            "D": "Decrease by 3.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Increase by 2.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-085",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 85,
        "question": "Sumit's income in 2020 was \u20b921,000. He gets an increment of income in 2022. What was his income in 2022?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b925,410",
            "B": "\u20b926,530",
            "C": "\u20b923,100",
            "D": "\u20b929,100"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b925,410",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-086",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 86,
        "question": "Rakesh is the owner of a rectangular field. Because of construction, the length and breadth of his field were reduced by 30% and 20% respectively. What is the percentage decrease in the area of his field?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "33%",
            "C": "35%",
            "D": "37%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "35%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-087",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 87,
        "question": "The price of a product increases by 10% in the first year and 20% in the second year. What is the overall percentage increase in the price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "28%",
            "B": "32%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "36%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "32%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-088",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 88,
        "question": "Ramesh's pocket money was reduced by 25%, and then the reduced money was increased by 20%. Find the net increase or decrease in his original pocket money.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease 12%",
            "B": "Increase 12%",
            "C": "Increase 10%",
            "D": "Decrease 10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Decrease 10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-089",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 89,
        "question": "The price of a car is decreased by 15% and 20% successively. What percentage is the decrease after two years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "32%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "32%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-090",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 90,
        "question": "The strength of a school increases and decreases every alternate year by 20%. What is the strength of the school in 2022 compared to 2018?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease by 16.2%",
            "B": "Increase by 15.2%",
            "C": "Decrease by 15.2%",
            "D": "Increase by 16.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Increase by 15.2%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-091",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 91,
        "question": "When the price of an article was increased by 5% it reduced by 10%. What was net effect on the revenue?",
        "options": {
            "A": "5% increase",
            "B": "5.5% decrease",
            "C": "5.5% increase",
            "D": "5% decrease"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "5.5% decrease",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-092",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 92,
        "question": "The price of a car is first increased by 35% and after that the price is decreased by 25%. What is the net percentage change in final price of the car?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease by 2 1/5%",
            "B": "Increase by 2 1/5%",
            "C": "Decrease by 1 3/5%",
            "D": "Increase by 1 1/4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Increase by 1 1/4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-093",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 93,
        "question": "The price of a scooter increases successively by 10%, 5% and 15%. What is the total percentage increase in price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33 33/40%",
            "B": "34 21/40%",
            "C": "36 11/40%",
            "D": "36 31/40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "33 33/40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-094",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 94,
        "question": "Instead of increasing a number successively by 20 percent and 30 percent, it is decreased by 22 percent. Resultant value is what percentage of the required correct value?",
        "options": {
            "A": "53%",
            "B": "60%",
            "C": "48%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "50%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-095",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 95,
        "question": "The price of an electronic machine decreased by 5%, 10% and 15% during the first three years. What will be the price at the beginning was Rs.80000?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs.68000",
            "B": "Rs.67210",
            "C": "Rs.70000",
            "D": "Rs.58140"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Rs.58140",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-096",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 96,
        "question": "A number is first decreased by 10%, then increased by 30%, and then further decreased by 20%. What is the net decrease percentage in the number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "4 1/5%",
            "B": "6 2/5%",
            "C": "5 3/8%",
            "D": "3 4/5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "6 2/5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-097",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 97,
        "question": "A number is first increased by 12% and then increased by 23%. The number so obtained is now decreased by 34%. What is the net increase or decrease percent in the original number?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10% increase",
            "B": "9% decrease",
            "C": "10% decrease",
            "D": "9% increase"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "9% decrease",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-098",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 98,
        "question": "The price of an AC increases and decreases in every alternate year by 1 3/5%. It started with an increase in 2004. The price of the AC in 2007 compared to that in 2004 is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decreased by 2.57%",
            "B": "Decreased by 1.57%",
            "C": "Increased by 1.57%",
            "D": "Increased by 2.57%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Increased by 1.57%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-099",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 99,
        "question": "Two successive percentage decrease of 25% each is by what percentage less than two successive percentage increase of 25% each?",
        "options": {
            "A": "50%",
            "B": "43.75%",
            "C": "22.22%",
            "D": "56.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "22.22%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-100",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 100,
        "question": "Two successive increments of 30% each is by what percentage more than two successive decrements of 30% each?",
        "options": {
            "A": "32.54%",
            "B": "28.15%",
            "C": "25.25%",
            "D": "35.29%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "35.29%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-101",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 101,
        "question": "An investor invested \u20b92,00,000 in shares. The shares rose by 18% on the first day, fell by 15% on the second day, and then fell by 3% on the third day. What is the net percentage increase or decrease in the value of the investor's shares?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Increase by 2.2%",
            "B": "Increase by 2.7%",
            "C": "Decrease by 2.7%",
            "D": "Decrease by 2.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Decrease by 2.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-102",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 102,
        "question": "The population of a town is 15000. If the population increases by 15% in the first year, by 25% in the second year and decreases by 6% in the third year, what will be its population after 3 years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20269",
            "B": "15269",
            "C": "25269",
            "D": "28269"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20269",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T4-103",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IV",
        "question_number": 103,
        "question": "An employee gets two successive increments in his salary, as a result of which his salary becomes 2.5 times the initial salary. What was his first percentage increment, if the second percentage increment was 4 times as high as the first?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "12%",
            "D": "10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-104",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 104,
        "question": "If the price of petrol is increased by 7%, then by what percentage should the consumption be decreased so that expenditure remains unchanged?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6 54/107%",
            "B": "11 17/107%",
            "C": "4 49/107%",
            "D": "4 99/107%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6 54/107%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-105",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 105,
        "question": "If price is decreased by 25%, then by how much percentage consumption should be increased, so that the expenditure remains same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "37.5%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "33.33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "33.33%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-106",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 106,
        "question": "If the price of rice is raised by 20%, then by what percentage should consumption be reduced so that expenditure remains same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "14.7%",
            "B": "18.7%",
            "C": "16.7%",
            "D": "12.7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-107",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 107,
        "question": "If the price of pulses has increased by 45%, by what percentage should consumption be reduced so that expenditure remains same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "41%",
            "C": "31%",
            "D": "45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "31%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-108",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 108,
        "question": "If the rate is increased by 40%, by how much percentage must consumption decrease so that expenditure remains same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "31 2/9%",
            "B": "35 5/9%",
            "C": "28 4/9%",
            "D": "28 4/7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "28 4/7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-109",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 109,
        "question": "If the price of an article is raised by 35%, by how much percent must a householder reduce his consumption so that his expenditure remains same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25 23/27%",
            "B": "25 22/27%",
            "C": "25 24/27%",
            "D": "25 25/27%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "25 25/27%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-110",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 110,
        "question": "Due to decrease in many power, the production in a factory decreases by 25%. By what percent should the working hours be increased to restore the original production?",
        "options": {
            "A": "43 5/7%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "33 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "33 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-111",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 111,
        "question": "The cost of CNG per liter is increased by 65%. By what percentage must Manish reduce his consumption so that his expenditure remains unchanged?",
        "options": {
            "A": "39.39%",
            "B": "30.13%",
            "C": "45.13%",
            "D": "25.39%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "39.39%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-112",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 112,
        "question": "If the price of a movie ticket increased by 12.5% and the sale of tickets also increased by 8 1/3%, then find % change in income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21.875%",
            "B": "22.875%",
            "C": "20.675%",
            "D": "22.0625%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22.0625%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-113",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 113,
        "question": "On reducing the entry fee by 25%, the number of people coming to the museum increased by 50%. Find the percentage increase in the collection.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10% decrease",
            "B": "12.5% decrease",
            "C": "12% increase",
            "D": "12.5% increase"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12.5% increase",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-114",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 114,
        "question": "Ramanujan's salary was reduced by 3 1/8% and then increased by 7 2/5%. By what percentage is his new salary more or less than his original salary?",
        "options": {
            "A": "3.03% less",
            "B": "4.04% more",
            "C": "4.04% less",
            "D": "3.03% more"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4.04% more",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-115",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 115,
        "question": "A worker has an increase of 12.5% in her wages rate per hour but there is a drop of 10% in number of hours worked per week. If her original weekly wages were \u20b938400, then the percentage increase in her weekly wages is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.25%",
            "B": "1%",
            "C": "2.25%",
            "D": "2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-116",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 116,
        "question": "When the price of an item was reduced by 20%, its sale increased by 25%. In receipt of revenue, then the value of revenue is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "58.35",
            "B": "57.75",
            "C": "54.35",
            "D": "60"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "54.35",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-117",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 117,
        "question": "The income of A is 80% of B and expenditure of A is 60% of B. If A saves 20% of his income and B saves 10% of his income, then by what percentage are the savings of A more than B?",
        "options": {
            "A": "100%",
            "B": "140%",
            "C": "125%",
            "D": "150%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "140%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T5-118",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-V",
        "question_number": 118,
        "question": "A's income is equal to 125% of the income of B, while B's savings are 120% of the savings of A. If the expenditure of B is 75% of the expenditure of A, then how much are B's savings as a percentage of her expenditure?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "22.5%",
            "C": "18.75%",
            "D": "16.67%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T6-119",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VI",
        "question_number": 119,
        "question": "The value of a washing machine depreciated from \u20b940,960 to \u20b921,970 in 3 years. Find the yearly rate of depreciation.",
        "options": {
            "A": "18.75%",
            "B": "16.25%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "18.75%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T6-120",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VI",
        "question_number": 120,
        "question": "The population of a town increased from 100000 to 250000 in 5 years. What is the approximate compounded percent increase of population per year?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "30%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-121",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 121,
        "question": "After decreasing 30%, an article costs Rs.3,500. Find its actual cost.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs.5,000",
            "B": "Rs.4,500",
            "C": "Rs.5,500",
            "D": "Rs.6,500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Rs.5,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-122",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 122,
        "question": "The price of an electric bike was \u20b91,25,000 last year. This year, its price got decreased by 30%. What is the price this year?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b987,000",
            "B": "\u20b986,000",
            "C": "\u20b987,500",
            "D": "\u20b986,500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b987,500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-123",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 123,
        "question": "A car is sold for \u20b95,00,000 which is 20% less than its original price. What was the original price of the car?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96,25,000",
            "B": "\u20b96,50,000",
            "C": "\u20b96,75,000",
            "D": "\u20b96,00,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b96,25,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-124",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 124,
        "question": "If 20% of 35% of a number is 240.8, then 18% of that number (rounded off to 1 decimal place) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "621.8",
            "B": "619.2",
            "C": "623.2",
            "D": "618.2"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "619.2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-125",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 125,
        "question": "During the first year the population of a village increased by 5% and during the second year it diminished by 5%. At the end of the second year its population was 47,880. What was the population at the beginning of the first year?",
        "options": {
            "A": "48000",
            "B": "43500",
            "C": "53000",
            "D": "45000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "48000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-126",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 126,
        "question": "Monthly salary of Jitvik in December 2020 was \u20b924,800. Every year his salary increases by 5% from January. What was his salary in February 2022?",
        "options": {
            "A": "27342",
            "B": "27180",
            "C": "27486",
            "D": "26485"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "27342",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-127",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 127,
        "question": "Mohan gets 12% increase in his sale amount in the first year and 15% increase in the second year, with that his present sale is \u20b91,28,800. What was his sale two years ago?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,75,000",
            "B": "\u20b91,25,000",
            "C": "\u20b91,50,000",
            "D": "\u20b91,00,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b91,00,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-128",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 128,
        "question": "The value of a machine depreciates every year by 5%. If the present value of the machine is \u20b980,000, what will be its value after 2 years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b972,200",
            "B": "\u20b972,000",
            "C": "\u20b974,400",
            "D": "\u20b974,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b972,200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-129",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 129,
        "question": "The price of a motorcycle was $750 last year. The price increased by 20% this year. What is the price this year?",
        "options": {
            "A": "$600",
            "B": "$750",
            "C": "$900",
            "D": "$790"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "$900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-130",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 130,
        "question": "The population of a town increases 8% annually. If its present population is 1,42,560, what was the population one year ago?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1,34,000",
            "B": "1,33,000",
            "C": "1,31,000",
            "D": "1,30,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1,31,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-131",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 131,
        "question": "Two years ago, the population of a town was 9,487,500. Due to migration to big cities, it decreases every year at the rate of 8%. The present population of the town is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "9060110",
            "B": "7060320",
            "C": "8070120",
            "D": "8030220"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "8030220",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-132",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 132,
        "question": "Amit gets 6% increase in his sale amount in the first year and 20% in the second year, with that his present sale is Rs.254400, what was his sale two years ago?",
        "options": {
            "A": "200000",
            "B": "180000",
            "C": "212000",
            "D": "240000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-133",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 133,
        "question": "The price of an article is increased by r%. The new price was decreased by r% later. Now the latest price is \u20b91. What was the original price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10000 / (10000 - r\u00b2)",
            "B": "(10000 - r\u00b2) / 10000",
            "C": "100 / (100 - r\u00b2)",
            "D": "100 / (1 - r\u00b2)"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10000 / (10000 - r\u00b2)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-134",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 134,
        "question": "The population of a city increases every year at the rate of 5%. If the population of the city is 16000, what will be the population after 2 years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "17640",
            "B": "17000",
            "C": "17700",
            "D": "17600"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "17640",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-135",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 135,
        "question": "The population of a village was 4,00,000. It increased by 20% in the first year and increased by 30% in the second year. Its population after two years is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "540000",
            "B": "625000",
            "C": "624000",
            "D": "520000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "624000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-136",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 136,
        "question": "The population of a city was 1,75,000 two years ago. If it had increased by 4% and 5% in the last two years, find the present population of the city.",
        "options": {
            "A": "192100",
            "B": "189200",
            "C": "191100",
            "D": "193200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "191100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-137",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 137,
        "question": "A number is first decreased by 28% and then increased by 28%. The number so obtained is 784 less than the original number. Find the value of the original number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1500",
            "B": "10000",
            "C": "10000",
            "D": "1000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-138",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 138,
        "question": "A city has 10,24,000 inhabitants. If the population increases at the rate of 2.5% per annum, find the number of inhabitants at the end of three years.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1120736",
            "B": "1102736",
            "C": "1075840",
            "D": "1064850"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1102736",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-139",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 139,
        "question": "The price of an electronic watch is first reduced by 25% and then increased by 50%. If the resulting price of the watch is \u20b97650, then what was its original price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6900",
            "B": "6800",
            "C": "6500",
            "D": "6600"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "6800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-140",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 140,
        "question": "On Monday, the sale was decreased by 10% compared to Sunday. On Tuesday, the sale was increased by 10% compared to Monday. If the sale on Tuesday was Rs.1485, what was the sale on Sunday?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1495",
            "B": "1485",
            "C": "1475",
            "D": "1500"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "1500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-141",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 141,
        "question": "During the first year, the population of a town increased by 12%. The next year, it decreased by 8%. At the end of the second year, the population was 64,400. Find the population of the town at the beginning of the first year.",
        "options": {
            "A": "50000",
            "B": "54750",
            "C": "62500",
            "D": "50500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "62500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-142",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 142,
        "question": "20% of the inhabitants of a village having domicile malaria, a panic of the inhabitants left the village. Population was then reduced to 12,000. What was the number of inhabitants before the epidemic?",
        "options": {
            "A": "21000",
            "B": "21428",
            "C": "21500",
            "D": "30428"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "21428",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-143",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 143,
        "question": "On account of corona virus, 5% of the population of a village died, 20% of the remaining population fled due to panic. If the present population is 46,552, then what was the population before the attack?",
        "options": {
            "A": "5995",
            "B": "61225",
            "C": "6000",
            "D": "5985"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "61225",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-144",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 144,
        "question": "The population of a town is 1,25,000. If the annual birth rate is 12.7% and death rate is 2.7%, how much will the population increase after 3 years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "43285",
            "B": "41375",
            "C": "42565",
            "D": "40275"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "41375",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-145",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 145,
        "question": "The number of tourists increased by a machine in 2018 was 25,000, which increased by 20% in 2019. In 2020, the production was reduced by 15%. How many total toys were manufactured in three years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25500",
            "B": "80000",
            "C": "89500",
            "D": "90000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "89500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-146",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 146,
        "question": "During 2021, the population of a city increased by 8% and in 2022, it increased by 10%. At the end of 2022, its population was 47,520. The population of the city at the end of 2021 was:",
        "options": {
            "A": "40000",
            "B": "43200",
            "C": "42300",
            "D": "44000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "43200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-147",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 147,
        "question": "Two years ago, the population of a small town was 60,000. It increased by 5% in the first year but decreased by 10% in the second year. What is its present population?",
        "options": {
            "A": "56700",
            "B": "56900",
            "C": "33500",
            "D": "35700"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "56700",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-148",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 148,
        "question": "The rate of annual growth of a city is 2%. If its population in 2020 was 1,50,000, then what would be its population in 2023?",
        "options": {
            "A": "159000",
            "B": "159181",
            "C": "158413",
            "D": "158765"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "159181",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-149",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 149,
        "question": "In the first year, the population of a town decreased by 5%. In the next year it decreased again by 5% and in the third year it increased by 5%. At the end of the third year the population was 9,47,625. Find the population at the beginning of the first year.",
        "options": {
            "A": "700000",
            "B": "1000000",
            "C": "897993",
            "D": "992519"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1000000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-150",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 150,
        "question": "The strength of a school increases and decreases every alternate year by 15%. If it started with an increase in 2012, then the strength of the school in the beginning of 2015, compared to that in 2012, had:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decreased by 12.41%",
            "B": "Increased by 12.41%",
            "C": "Decreased by 13.85%",
            "D": "Increased by 13.85%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Increased by 12.41%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-151",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 151,
        "question": "If the number of school going children in a town is 64000 and it is increasing annually by 10%, then what will be the number of school going children in the town at the end of 3 years?",
        "options": {
            "A": "85100",
            "B": "85184",
            "C": "85000",
            "D": "80000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "85184",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-152",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 152,
        "question": "The strength of a school increases and decreases every alternate year by 20%. It started with an increase in the year 2015 and the initial strength was 3000. Find the strength of the school in the year 2017 and also the percentage increase strength, respectively.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4556, 17.2%",
            "B": "3556, 16.2%",
            "C": "3456, 15.2%",
            "D": "4456, 14.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "3456, 15.2%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-153",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 153,
        "question": "The population of a place increased to 50,000 from 2016 to 2018 at the rate of 6% per annum, and continued at the same trend for the next 3 years. If A is the population in 2016 and B is the population in 2020, both approximated to the next possible integer, then the value of B - A is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "11680",
            "B": "16270",
            "C": "13320",
            "D": "12850"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "11680",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-154",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 154,
        "question": "Ramgya spends 22% of his salary on house rent and 75% of the rest on household expenses. If he saves \u20b93705, find his total income (in \u20b9).",
        "options": {
            "A": "17000",
            "B": "18000",
            "C": "21000",
            "D": "19000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "19000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-155",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 155,
        "question": "A man spent 60% of his salary on household expenses, 20% on rent and out of remaining salary, he donated 80% to a trust. If he is left with \u20b920000, then what is his salary?",
        "options": {
            "A": "400000",
            "B": "500000",
            "C": "750000",
            "D": "50000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "500000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-156",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 156,
        "question": "A person spends 60% of his salary on family expenses, 10% on medical expenses, 5% on charity, and saves the remaining amount. If the amount on savings is \u20b94000, find his monthly salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "16000",
            "B": "15000",
            "C": "14000",
            "D": "12000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "16000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-157",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 157,
        "question": "Nazeer spends 20% of his monthly income on housing, 25% of the remaining on education, and saves 10% of the remaining. If his monthly salary is \u20b952600, how much money does he save every month?",
        "options": {
            "A": "5260",
            "B": "1578",
            "C": "2367",
            "D": "3156"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "3156",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-158",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 158,
        "question": "A man spent 30% of his monthly income on rent. He spent 15% of the remaining amount on food. 35% of the remaining amount was used for all other expenses. If \u20b9164235 was left with him, find his monthly income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "480000",
            "B": "420000",
            "C": "360000",
            "D": "540000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "420000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-159",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 159,
        "question": "A person spends 25% of his income on goods of daily use. Furthermore, he spends 18% of the rest on house rent and 16% of the rest on travel. After that, only \u20b9861 is left with him. What is his salary?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1852 1/3",
            "B": "1666 2/3",
            "C": "1563 1/3",
            "D": "1426 1/3"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1666 2/3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-160",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 160,
        "question": "A father gives 8% of his monthly income to both his sons as pocket money. The elder son gets 85% of the total amount given to both sons. He spends 90% of the amount and saves \u20b917. What is the monthly income of the father?",
        "options": {
            "A": "5000",
            "B": "4500",
            "C": "3500",
            "D": "2500"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-161",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 161,
        "question": "Three years ago, Raman\u2019s salary was \u20b945000. His salary is increased by 10%, 10% and 20% in the first, second and third year respectively. Raman\u2019s present salary is \u20b983160. What is the value of A?",
        "options": {
            "A": "50%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "54%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T7-162",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 162,
        "question": "70% of students in a class are girls and 70% of girls have chosen soccer as their favourite sport. If 98 girls have chosen soccer as their favourite sport, what is the total number of students in the class?",
        "options": {
            "A": "180",
            "B": "225",
            "C": "175",
            "D": "200"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-163",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 163,
        "question": "If the price of a commodity is increased by 36%, by what percentage should its consumption be decreased so that the expenditure remains the same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "32%",
            "B": "38%",
            "C": "26%",
            "D": "26.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "26.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-164",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 164,
        "question": "The price of tomatoes per kg is increased by 300%. A housewife reduces her consumption by 70%. By what percentage does her expenditure on tomatoes increase or decrease?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decrease 30%",
            "B": "Decrease 20%",
            "C": "Increase 30%",
            "D": "Increase 20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Increase 20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-165",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 165,
        "question": "The cost of rice is increased by 25% but its consumption is decreased by 30%. Find the percentage increase or decrease in expenditure.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Increase 12 1/2%",
            "B": "Increase 13 1/3%",
            "C": "Decrease 12 1/2%",
            "D": "Decrease 13 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Decrease 12 1/2%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-166",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 166,
        "question": "When price of a commodity increases by 23%, consumption reduces so that expenditure increases by 5%. By what percentage is consumption reduced?",
        "options": {
            "A": "14.20%",
            "B": "14.6%",
            "C": "15.8%",
            "D": "15.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "15.8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-167",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 167,
        "question": "The price of diesel is increased by 26%. A person decreases his expenditure by 15% only. By what percentage is consumption decreased?",
        "options": {
            "A": "7.2%",
            "B": "6.5%",
            "C": "9.5%",
            "D": "9.3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "9.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-168",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 168,
        "question": "The price of a commodity is decreased by 25%. By how much should consumption increase so that expenditure remains the same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "60 kg",
            "B": "55 kg",
            "C": "50 kg",
            "D": "45 kg"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "60 kg",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-169",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 169,
        "question": "If price of rice is reduced by 24%, by how much should consumption increase so that expenditure remains the same?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b925",
            "B": "\u20b950",
            "C": "\u20b960",
            "D": "\u20b975"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b960",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-170",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 170,
        "question": "A reduction of 15% in the price of washing powder enables a purchaser to obtain 5 kg more for \u20b91275. What is the original price per kg?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b940",
            "B": "\u20b935",
            "C": "\u20b945",
            "D": "\u20b950"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b945",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-171",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 171,
        "question": "The reduction of 20% in the price of rice enables a person to obtain 50 kg more for \u20b9450. Find the original price per kg.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91",
            "B": "\u20b92.25",
            "C": "\u20b92.50",
            "D": "\u20b92.25"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b92.50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-172",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 172,
        "question": "Price of rice decreases by 25 percent and therefore a person can purchase 30 kg more rice in the same expenditure. If expenditure is \u20b95400, then what was the original price of rice per kg?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b990 per kg",
            "B": "\u20b975 per kg",
            "C": "\u20b950 per kg",
            "D": "\u20b960 per kg"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b960 per kg",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-173",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 173,
        "question": "If a reduction of 10% in the price of rice enables a person to obtain 22 kg more for \u20b9250, then find the original price per kg.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91.26",
            "B": "\u20b91.24",
            "C": "\u20b91.22",
            "D": "\u20b91.20"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91.22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-174",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 174,
        "question": "The reduction of 15% in the price of salt enables a person to buy 2 kg more for \u20b9272. The reduced price of salt per kg is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b920.40",
            "B": "\u20b921.60",
            "C": "\u20b924.25",
            "D": "\u20b925.00"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b925.00",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-175",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 175,
        "question": "A reduction of 20% in the price of bananas enables a customer to buy 6 more bananas for \u20b980. What is the reduced price per dozen bananas?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b932",
            "B": "\u20b936",
            "C": "\u20b935",
            "D": "\u20b940"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b932",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T8-176",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-VIII",
        "question_number": 176,
        "question": "If due to 12% decrease in the price of sugar, a person can buy 7 kg more sugar for \u20b91200, then find the actual price per kg.",
        "options": {
            "A": "23.38",
            "B": "25.79",
            "C": "26.35",
            "D": "28.25"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "28.25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-177",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 177,
        "question": "If an employee\u2019s income is \u20b972000 and his expenditure is 40% higher than his savings, find his savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30000",
            "B": "34000",
            "C": "32000",
            "D": "28000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "34000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-178",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 178,
        "question": "Total savings of X and Y is 40% of their total income. Their average expenditure is \u20b921000. What is total salary of X and Y?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b955000",
            "B": "\u20b965000",
            "C": "\u20b960000",
            "D": "\u20b970000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b970000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-179",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 179,
        "question": "Raman spends 75% of his income. If his income increases by 20% and expenditure also increases by 10%, how much percent Raman\u2019s saving increases?",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "50%",
            "D": "45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-180",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 180,
        "question": "The ratio of Richard\u2019s expenditure and savings is 2:1. If his income and expenditure decrease by 15% and 10% respectively, find percentage increase in his savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-181",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 181,
        "question": "A woman spends 2/3 of her income. If her income increases by 18% and expenditure increases by 24%, then the percentage increase in her saving will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "6%",
            "B": "3%",
            "C": "5%",
            "D": "4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-182",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 182,
        "question": "The proportion of Suresh\u2019s spending to saving is 3:1. His salary rises by 25%. What percentage of his expenditure will increase if his saving grows by 10%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "30%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-183",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 183,
        "question": "Kalyan spends 80% of his income. His income increases by 15% and his expenditure also increases by 5%. The percentage increase in his savings is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "50%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "55%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "55%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-184",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 184,
        "question": "Rahul spends 70% of his income. His income increases by 15% and his expenditure increases by 7.5%. What is the percentage increase in his savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "50%",
            "B": "30.5%",
            "C": "25.5%",
            "D": "32.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "32.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-185",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 185,
        "question": "Ramana spends 75% of his income. His income increases by 25% and he increases his expenditure by 10%. By what percentage are his savings increased?",
        "options": {
            "A": "70%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "60%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "70%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-186",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 186,
        "question": "Rajiv spends 80% of his income. His income increases by 20%, while his spending rises by 10%. What is the percentage increase in his savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "48%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "80%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "80%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-187",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 187,
        "question": "Bhavani spends 68% of her income. Her income increases by 15% and her expenditure increases by 10%. How much is the increase in percentage of saving?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20.57%",
            "B": "25.62%",
            "C": "28.42%",
            "D": "24.80%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25.62%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-188",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 188,
        "question": "Ramesh spends 50% of his income. If his income increases by 30% and his expenditure increases by 20%, then the percentage increase in his savings will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "30%",
            "C": "45%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "45%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-189",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 189,
        "question": "Anita saves 20% of her income. If her income increases by 30% and she saves 25% of the new income, by what percentage will her actual savings increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "83%",
            "B": "62.50%",
            "C": "65.20%",
            "D": "70%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "70%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-190",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 190,
        "question": "Suresh could save 20% of his income. But 4 years later, when his income increased by 40%, he could save the same amount only as before. By how much percentage did his expenditure increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "22%",
            "B": "23%",
            "C": "50%",
            "D": "45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "50%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-191",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 191,
        "question": "Ajay spends 66 2/3% of his income on household items. If his income increases by 25% and expenditure increases by 20%, then the effect on his savings will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "28%",
            "B": "61%",
            "C": "49%",
            "D": "35%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "35%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-192",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 192,
        "question": "The income of a person is \u20b916,500, and his expenditure is \u20b912,000. Next year, his income increases by 24% but his expenditure decreases by 10%. The percentage increase (rounded off to nearest integer) in his savings is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "90%",
            "B": "120%",
            "C": "115%",
            "D": "95%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "115%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-193",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 193,
        "question": "The ratio of expenditure to savings of a woman is 4:1. If her income and expenditure increased by 20% and 10%, respectively, find the percentage change in her savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "60%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-194",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 194,
        "question": "The monthly income of Ramesh in 2021 was \u20b918,600 and his monthly expenditure was \u20b912,400. In 2022 his income increased by 15% and his expenditure increased by 8%. Find the percentage increase in his savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "29%",
            "B": "32%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "27%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "29%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-195",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 195,
        "question": "Suresh\u2019s expenditure and savings are in the ratio 3:1. His income increases by 25%. If his savings increase by 20%, then by how much percentage does his expenditure increase?",
        "options": {
            "A": "27 2/3%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "28 2/3%",
            "D": "26 2/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "26 2/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-196",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 196,
        "question": "The monthly expenditure of a person is 40% more than his monthly savings. If his monthly income increases by 40% and monthly expenditure by 60%, he saves \u20b92,070 more now. What is his initial monthly income?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20250",
            "B": "19320",
            "C": "24150",
            "D": "22425"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "24150",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-197",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 197,
        "question": "Ramesh saves 26 2/3% of his monthly salary. When his expenses increase by 20%, he is able to save \u20b94,080 per month. Find his monthly salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30000",
            "B": "34000",
            "C": "35000",
            "D": "38000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "34000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-198",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 198,
        "question": "Ramu spends 72% of his income. His income increases by 12%, and he increases his saved portion by 5%. If Ramu earlier saved y and after increase now saves x, then what is the value of ((x-y)/y) \u00d7 100?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "22%",
            "C": "27%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "30%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-199",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 199,
        "question": "A person saves 45% of his income. Next year, his income increases by 200%. He increases his savings by five times the previous year's savings. By what percentage has his income increased or decreased?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Decreased by 63.4%",
            "B": "Decreased by 36.4%",
            "C": "Increased by 63.4%",
            "D": "Increased by 36.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Increased by 36.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T9-200",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-IX",
        "question_number": 200,
        "question": "Rumi used to save 20% of her income. If her income went up by 30% and her expenditure went up by 40%, her nominal saving went down by \u20b9750. Find Rumi\u2019s initial income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "36000",
            "B": "37500",
            "C": "35000",
            "D": "38500"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "37500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-201",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 201,
        "question": "If the income of a person increases by 20% and expenditure increases by 10%, what is the percentage increase in savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-202",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 202,
        "question": "If the expenditure of a person decreases by 20% and income increases by 10%, what is the percentage increase in savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "18%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-203",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 203,
        "question": "If the income increases by 25% and savings increase by 50%, what is the percentage increase in expenditure?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-204",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 204,
        "question": "If the savings increase by 40% and income increases by 20%, what is the percentage increase in expenditure?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-205",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 205,
        "question": "If income increases by 30% and expenditure increases by 20%, what is the percentage increase in savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "50%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "50%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-206",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 206,
        "question": "If income increases by 15% and expenditure increases by 10%, what is the percentage increase in savings?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "35%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-207",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 207,
        "question": "If savings increase by 25% and income increases by 10%, what is the percentage increase in expenditure?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-208",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 208,
        "question": "The income of Raju is 25% more than that of Monju. Raju gets a 25% rise in income and Monju gets a 40% rise in income. What is the percentage increase in their combined income?",
        "options": {
            "A": "51.72%",
            "B": "31.67%",
            "C": "22.43%",
            "D": "41.26%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "31.67%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-209",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 209,
        "question": "The ratio of number of boys and girls in a school is 3:4. If number of boys increases by 10% and number of girls increases by 15%, what will be the new ratio of boys to girls?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33:45",
            "B": "35:46",
            "C": "33:46",
            "D": "35:33"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "33:46",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-210",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 210,
        "question": "In a class, the ratio of boys to girls is 11:9. 30% of boys and 20% of girls passed an exam. Find the percentage of students who passed the exam.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3.92%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "24.5%",
            "D": "25.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "25.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-211",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 211,
        "question": "In an institute, 35% are boys and the rest are girls. If 30% of the boys failed and 60% of the girls passed an examination, then the percentage of students who failed is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "35.5%",
            "B": "36.5%",
            "C": "35%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "36.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-212",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 212,
        "question": "In an examination, 45% of all students are boys and the rest are girls. If 60% of the boys and 70% of the girls passed, what is the percentage of students who failed?",
        "options": {
            "A": "36%",
            "B": "35.4%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "34.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "34.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-213",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 213,
        "question": "In a class, 60% of the students are girls and the rest are boys. 45% of the girls pass an examination and 40% of the boys fail. If the number of girls who failed is 66, find the number of boys who passed the examination.",
        "options": {
            "A": "36",
            "B": "48",
            "C": "54",
            "D": "60"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "48",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-214",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 214,
        "question": "The average pass percentage of girls in class X examination in a school is 85% and that of boys is 83%. The overall pass percentage is 83.7%. Find the percentage of girls in class X of that school.",
        "options": {
            "A": "45%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "35%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "35%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-215",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 215,
        "question": "In a class, out of the total number of students, 8 1/3% are girls and the remaining are boys. If 60% of boys and 80% of girls are present, then what percentage of total students are absent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "26 2/3%",
            "B": "22 2/3%",
            "C": "23 1/3%",
            "D": "12 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "23 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-216",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 216,
        "question": "In January 2022, Kriti paid an EMI which was 22% of her monthly salary. She spent the remaining salary on shopping in the ratio 7:5. If her February salary increased by 16%, then what was her salary in February?",
        "options": {
            "A": "66350",
            "B": "68520",
            "C": "70250",
            "D": "64960"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "64960",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T10-217",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-X",
        "question_number": 217,
        "question": "Sunita pays tax at 30% on her entire income of \u20b990,000. Ritu pays tax at 40% on her entire income of \u20b970,000. If overall tax rate on combined income is 37%, find the value of Y.",
        "options": {
            "A": "204000",
            "B": "216000",
            "C": "213000",
            "D": "210000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "210000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T11-218",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XI",
        "question_number": 218,
        "question": "Pass percentage of an examination is 35%. If a student who got 210 marks failed by 14 marks, then what are the maximum marks of the examination?",
        "options": {
            "A": "660",
            "B": "640",
            "C": "620",
            "D": "600"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "620",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T11-219",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XI",
        "question_number": 219,
        "question": "John got 20% marks and failed by 10 marks. In the same examination, Jack got 35% marks which is 20 more than minimum passing marks. Find the percentage marks required to pass.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T11-220",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XI",
        "question_number": 220,
        "question": "In an examination, a student who got 20% marks failed by 30 marks. But another student who got 32% marks got 42 marks more than required to pass. Find the maximum marks.",
        "options": {
            "A": "500",
            "B": "700",
            "C": "600",
            "D": "400"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T11-221",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XI",
        "question_number": 221,
        "question": "Rajiv scored 20 percent marks in an exam and failed by 25 marks. If he scores 50 percent marks, then he gets 20 marks more than passing marks. What is the passing marks for the exam?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40",
            "B": "35",
            "C": "45",
            "D": "55"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "45",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T11-222",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XI",
        "question_number": 222,
        "question": "R targets to score 85% marks in exams. He scores 450 marks and misses the target by 35%. How much increment in percentage should be there in his target?",
        "options": {
            "A": "70%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "53%",
            "D": "45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "70%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-223",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 223,
        "question": "Two persons contest an election and got 1136 and 7636 votes respectively. What was the winning candidate's percentage of the total votes?",
        "options": {
            "A": "57%",
            "B": "59%",
            "C": "52%",
            "D": "61%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "57%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-224",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 224,
        "question": "The difference between 31% and 26% of the votes for the same party at two different places is 2350. What is 7% of the votes?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2270",
            "B": "3090",
            "C": "4090",
            "D": "3290"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "3290",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-225",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 225,
        "question": "Two candidates contested an election. One of them got 64% of the votes and won by 434 votes. What was the total number of votes polled?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1550",
            "B": "1345",
            "C": "1680",
            "D": "1684"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1550",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-226",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 226,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, the one who gets 88% of the votes is elected by a majority of 634 votes. What is the total number of votes polled?",
        "options": {
            "A": "900",
            "B": "800",
            "C": "850",
            "D": "750"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-227",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 227,
        "question": "In an election, a candidate secured 41% of the votes polled and lost the election by 97,632 votes. What is the number of votes obtained by the winning candidate?",
        "options": {
            "A": "320016",
            "B": "542400",
            "C": "222384",
            "D": "360072"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "320016",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-228",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 228,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates A and B, A got 33% of total votes casted and still lost by 55,522 votes. Find the total number of votes cast.",
        "options": {
            "A": "109114",
            "B": "109141",
            "C": "104911",
            "D": "109411"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "109411",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-229",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 229,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one candidate gets 72% of the total votes cast. If total votes are 1000, how many votes does the winner get?",
        "options": {
            "A": "360",
            "B": "250",
            "C": "720",
            "D": "440"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "440",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-230",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 230,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, a candidate who gets 78% of the votes is elected by a majority of 448 votes. What is the total number of votes polled?",
        "options": {
            "A": "800",
            "B": "750",
            "C": "850",
            "D": "700"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-231",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 231,
        "question": "In an election contested by two candidates, one candidate got 42% of the total votes and still lost by 800 votes. Find the total number of votes cast.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2000",
            "B": "5000",
            "C": "8000",
            "D": "7000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "5000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-232",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 232,
        "question": "In an election there were only two candidates. One candidate secured 35% of the votes and was defeated by the other candidate by 381 votes. Find the total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1270",
            "B": "1028",
            "C": "635",
            "D": "514"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1270",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-233",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 233,
        "question": "In an election, candidate secures 40% of the votes, but is defeated by the only other candidate with a majority of 298 votes. Find the total number of votes recorded.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1470",
            "B": "1490",
            "C": "1270",
            "D": "1290"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1490",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-234",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 234,
        "question": "In an election, there were only two candidates. One of the candidates secured 44% of the votes and was defeated by the other candidate by 1440 votes. If there were no invalid votes, find the total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "14000",
            "B": "12000",
            "C": "15000",
            "D": "13000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-235",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 235,
        "question": "In an election a candidate secured 47% of the votes and lost his only opponent by 276 votes. Find the total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4000",
            "B": "3800",
            "C": "4600",
            "D": "4600"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "4600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-236",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 236,
        "question": "In an election there were three candidates. The first candidate got 40% votes and second candidate got 35% votes. If total votes in the election were 50,000, find the number of votes obtained by the third candidate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "13500",
            "B": "12500",
            "C": "12000",
            "D": "13000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-237",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 237,
        "question": "In an election, the candidate who gets 35% of the votes polled is defeated by 15,900 votes. Find the total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "53000",
            "B": "45000",
            "C": "35000",
            "D": "43000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "53000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-238",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 238,
        "question": "Vinod and Sanjay were fighting against each other for the post of a village Pradhan. Sanjay got 47.5% votes and lost the election by 270 votes. How many votes did Vinod get?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2385",
            "B": "2835",
            "C": "2565",
            "D": "2655"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2835",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-239",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 239,
        "question": "In an election, the candidate who gets 90% votes is elected by a margin of 800 votes. What is the total number of votes cast?",
        "options": {
            "A": "900",
            "B": "1000",
            "C": "1050",
            "D": "950"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-240",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 240,
        "question": "In an election between R and S, R gets 110% of the votes of S and beats S by 770 votes. If there were no invalid votes, then the total number of votes polled is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "17610",
            "B": "17160",
            "C": "16170",
            "D": "16710"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16170",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-241",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 241,
        "question": "A total of 7,50,000 voters participated in an election. A candidate received 3,82,500 votes which was 60% of the total valid votes. What was the percentage of invalid votes in the election?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "12%",
            "D": "18%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "15%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-242",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 242,
        "question": "In an election, 95% of the total voters cast their votes. There were only two candidates. The winner obtained 75% of the total votes and defeated his contestant by 5500 votes. Find the total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "11000",
            "B": "10000",
            "C": "13000",
            "D": "12000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "10000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-243",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 243,
        "question": "In an election, A received 27% of the votes and B received 1,25,982 votes. 19% did not cast their votes. Find the number of votes received by A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "44327",
            "B": "188973",
            "C": "57827",
            "D": "62991"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "62991",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-244",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 244,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one got 60% of the total valid votes, and 90% of the votes were valid. If total votes were 12,000, find the number of valid votes that the other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8840",
            "B": "4320",
            "C": "10800",
            "D": "6200"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4320",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-245",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 245,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 15% of the votes were invalid and one candidate got 52% of the total valid votes. If total votes were 8000, find the number of valid votes that the other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3840",
            "B": "3536",
            "C": "6800",
            "D": "3264"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "3264",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-246",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 246,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 10% of registered voters did not vote. The winning candidate got 60% of the votes cast and defeated the other candidate by 1242 votes. Find the total number of registered voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8640",
            "B": "9600",
            "C": "6200",
            "D": "6900"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-247",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 247,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one got 65% of the total valid votes. 20% of the votes were invalid. If total votes were 7500, find the number of valid votes that the other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4300",
            "B": "1700",
            "C": "1900",
            "D": "2100"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-248",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 248,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, Anant got 55% of the total valid votes and 20% of votes were invalid. If total votes were 30000, find the number of valid votes that Arvind got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10800",
            "B": "1080",
            "C": "13200",
            "D": "24000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-249",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 249,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one got 60% of the total valid votes and 15% votes were invalid. If total votes were 8400, find the number of valid votes that the other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2998",
            "B": "2856",
            "C": "3213",
            "D": "3117"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2856",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-250",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 250,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one got 60% of total valid votes and 25% votes were invalid. If total votes were 15000, find the number of valid votes that the other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5550",
            "B": "4500",
            "C": "6750",
            "D": "5000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-251",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 251,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, the voter who did not cast their vote was 20%. The winner by obtaining 60% of total votes defeated his opponent by 1200 votes. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3750",
            "B": "3570",
            "C": "4000",
            "D": "5730"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "3750",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-252",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 252,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, the first gets 75% of total valid votes. 20% votes are invalid among 2,48,000 votes. Find number of votes in favour of second candidate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "56000",
            "B": "46800",
            "C": "53800",
            "D": "49600"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "49600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-253",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 253,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 75% of voters cast their votes, of which 4% were invalid. A candidate got 9504 votes which were 50% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12375",
            "B": "12672",
            "C": "13200",
            "D": "13500"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "13500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-254",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 254,
        "question": "Two candidates A and B contested an election. 80% voters cast votes, 4% votes were invalid. A got 9408 votes which were 60% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12000",
            "B": "22000",
            "C": "21000",
            "D": "13000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "21000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-255",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 255,
        "question": "In a constituency, 90% of total people cast votes. 15% votes were declared invalid. Jeeta secured 60% of valid votes. If Jeeta secured 91800 valid votes, find total number of people in constituency.",
        "options": {
            "A": "216000",
            "B": "225000",
            "C": "180000",
            "D": "200000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "200000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-256",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 256,
        "question": "In a constituency, 85% of total people cast votes and 5% votes were declared invalid. If 30000 people cast vote, find percentage of total valid votes did Bhamini get.",
        "options": {
            "A": "50.5%",
            "B": "70.2%",
            "C": "45.9%",
            "D": "60%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-257",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 257,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, candidate got 60% valid votes. If invalid votes were 850 and 10% votes were invalid, find valid votes that other candidate got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3816",
            "B": "3168",
            "C": "3681",
            "D": "3618"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "3168",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-258",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 258,
        "question": "In an election, 8% voters did not cast vote. Winning candidate got 48% of total votes and won by 1100 votes. Find total number of votes cast.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25500",
            "B": "26500",
            "C": "27500",
            "D": "28500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "27500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-259",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 259,
        "question": "In an election, 12% voters did not cast votes. Winning candidate got 68% votes and won by 2880 votes. Find total number of voters who cast vote.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5280",
            "B": "8000",
            "C": "4000",
            "D": "6000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "5280",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-260",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 260,
        "question": "In an election, 65% voters cast votes, out of which 3% votes were invalid. Winning candidate got 81965 votes which were 65% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "200000",
            "B": "190000",
            "C": "215000",
            "D": "185000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-261",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 261,
        "question": "In a two-candidate election, 10% of voters did not cast their ballots, and 10% of votes cast were invalid. The winning candidate received 54% of valid votes and won by a majority of 1620 votes. Find the number of people on the voter list.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25000",
            "B": "24500",
            "C": "26000",
            "D": "25500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "25000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-262",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 262,
        "question": "In an assembly election, a candidate got 60% of total valid votes. 2% of total votes were declared invalid. If total voters were 1,50,000, find number of valid votes polled in favour of candidate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "90000",
            "B": "78000",
            "C": "86400",
            "D": "88200"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "88200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-263",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 263,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 85% voters cast votes, out of which 4% votes were invalid. Candidate got 6936 votes which were 85% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10500",
            "B": "10800",
            "C": "10000",
            "D": "10700"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-264",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 264,
        "question": "In an election between Sunita and Mamata, 85% voters cast their votes but 2% of votes were invalid. If Sunita got 64974 votes which is 78% of valid votes, find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "125000",
            "B": "100000",
            "C": "165000",
            "D": "180000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "100000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-265",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 265,
        "question": "Two candidates contested an election. 80% voters cast votes, out of which 5% votes were invalid. Winning candidate got 70% valid votes and won by a majority of 36480 votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "115000",
            "B": "120000",
            "C": "125000",
            "D": "118000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "120000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-266",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 266,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, P received 42% valid votes and Q received 45360 votes. 20% people did not cast vote. If 10% of votes cast were invalid, find total number of registered voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "393750",
            "B": "359000",
            "C": "393600",
            "D": "353790"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "393750",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-267",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 267,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 80% voters cast votes, out of which 4% votes were invalid. Candidate got 15360 votes which were 80% of total valid votes. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20000",
            "B": "18000",
            "C": "25000",
            "D": "23000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-268",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 268,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 10% voters did not cast vote and 5% votes were invalid. Successful candidate got 52.5% valid votes and won by majority of 1710 votes. Find number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "36000",
            "B": "40000",
            "C": "42000",
            "D": "48000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-269",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 269,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, A gets 63% of valid votes. If total votes polled were 8750, find number of votes secured by other candidate if 20% votes were invalid.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4410",
            "B": "2590",
            "C": "3560",
            "D": "6450"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2590",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-270",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 270,
        "question": "In an assembly election, candidate got 60% of total valid votes. 3% votes were declared invalid. If total voters were 240000, find number of votes polled in favour of candidate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "193680",
            "B": "139680",
            "C": "139860",
            "D": "139608"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "139680",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-271",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 271,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 30% of electorate did not cast their votes. 20% of votes polled were invalid. Winning candidate got 64% valid votes and won by majority of 3136 votes. Find number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "24000",
            "B": "20000",
            "C": "25000",
            "D": "30000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-272",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 272,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 80% voters cast their votes, out of which 5% votes were declared invalid. Candidate got 9500 votes which were 80% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "14780",
            "B": "15625",
            "C": "16100",
            "D": "15100"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15625",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-273",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 273,
        "question": "In a village election between three candidates, 80% voters cast votes, out of which 3% votes were invalid. Winning candidate got 42680 votes which were 55% of valid votes. Find number of valid votes received by third candidate who got 10% of valid votes.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7760",
            "B": "7700",
            "C": "7670",
            "D": "7680"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "7760",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-274",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 274,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 10% voters did not cast vote, candidate got 56% valid votes and won by margin of 1458 votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "14000",
            "B": "15000",
            "C": "16000",
            "D": "13000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-275",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 275,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 20% voters did not cast vote and 40% votes were invalid. Winning candidate got 72% valid votes and won by margin of 112 votes. Find number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1200",
            "B": "1500",
            "C": "1800",
            "D": "3800"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-276",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 276,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 10% voters did not cast vote and valid votes were 59.375% of total votes. Winning candidate got 2484 votes. Find number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7000",
            "B": "8400",
            "C": "16000",
            "D": "8240"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-277",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 277,
        "question": "In an election, 2% voters did not participate and 500 votes were found invalid. A and B fought election and A defeated B by 200 votes. If 43% voters voted in favour of A, find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2450",
            "B": "2800",
            "C": "3000",
            "D": "3250"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2450",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-278",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 278,
        "question": "In an election between candidates P and Q, P got 78% valid votes. If total votes were 756000 and 15% votes were invalid, find valid votes secured by Q.",
        "options": {
            "A": "141372",
            "B": "147132",
            "C": "141732",
            "D": "147312"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "141732",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-279",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 279,
        "question": "In a Panchayat election, A, B and C contested. 75% voters cast votes and 10% voters voted NOTA. A got least votes with only 300 votes. B got 66% of total votes. Find number of votes B got.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3960",
            "B": "4080",
            "C": "4200",
            "D": "4560"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "3960",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-280",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 280,
        "question": "Raju, Ravi and Ashok contested an election. 5% votes were invalid. Raju got 30% of total votes, Ravi got 32% of total votes and winner got 51% more votes than runner-up. Find total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "171200",
            "B": "64200",
            "C": "171220",
            "D": "172100"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "171200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-281",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 281,
        "question": "In an election, three candidates A, B and C contested. Out of total voters, 45% voted for A, 35% for B and remaining for C. 30% of votes polled were invalid. If all valid votes were cast for C and A got 882 more valid votes than B, find valid votes secured by C.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5020",
            "B": "5040",
            "C": "5050",
            "D": "5060"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "5040",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-282",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 282,
        "question": "Chamanlal, Arshad and Jagjit Singh contested an election. Arshad got 35 votes, Chamanlal got 14 votes and Jagjit Singh got 4950 more votes than the person with least votes. Find total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "13378",
            "B": "38000",
            "C": "99000",
            "D": "33000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "33000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-283",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 283,
        "question": "Three candidates X, Y and Z contested election. X got 30% votes more than Y, and Z got 25% votes more than Y. X and Z together got 5000 votes. If 71% votes were cast and no invalid votes, find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "500000",
            "B": "405000",
            "C": "350000",
            "D": "450000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "500000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-284",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 284,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 30% voters did not cast votes and 200 votes were declared invalid. Winner got 65% of valid votes. If winner got 1200 votes, find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "9000",
            "B": "6000",
            "C": "7000",
            "D": "8000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "6000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-285",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 285,
        "question": "In an election involving two candidates, 68 voters were declared invalid. Winning candidate got 52% of valid votes and won by 98 votes. Find total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2475",
            "B": "2518",
            "C": "2500",
            "D": "2250"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2518",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-286",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 286,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, one got 54% valid votes and won by 88 votes. If 58 votes were invalid, find total number of votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1850",
            "B": "1800",
            "C": "1156",
            "D": "2000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-287",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 287,
        "question": "In an election, defeated candidate secured 42% of valid votes polled and lost the election by 254800 votes. If 365500 people were declared invalid and 30% did not cast vote, find number of people who did NOT cast vote.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5 million",
            "B": "8 million",
            "C": "6 million",
            "D": "7 million"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "7 million",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-288",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 288,
        "question": "In an election, winner was supported by 46% of voters in voter list and got 41% of votes cast. If total voters were 17445 and 600 votes were blank, find number of voters in voter list.",
        "options": {
            "A": "17445",
            "B": "16550",
            "C": "17500",
            "D": "15750"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "17500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-289",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 289,
        "question": "In an election, 12% voters did not cast votes and 84 voters cast blank ballot papers. Ramagya got 54% votes and won by margin of 1456 votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5690",
            "B": "6670",
            "C": "7860",
            "D": "6860"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6860",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-290",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 290,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 10% voters did not cast vote and 75 votes were invalid. Winning candidate got 50% votes and won by 170 votes. Find number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "800",
            "B": "855",
            "C": "850",
            "D": "950"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "950",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-291",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 291,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 20% voters did not cast votes and 80 voters cast blank ballots. Winner secured 45% of total voters and got 280 votes more than rival. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2000",
            "B": "2800",
            "C": "2500",
            "D": "1500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-292",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 292,
        "question": "In an election between A and B, some votes were declared invalid. A won by 2500 votes which was 10% of total votes polled. If 90% of invalid votes were in favour of B, what would have been the result?",
        "options": {
            "A": "B would have won by 8%",
            "B": "B would have won by 3%",
            "C": "A would have won by 3%",
            "D": "A would have won by 8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "B would have won by 8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-293",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 293,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 64% voters cast votes and 4% votes were invalid. Candidate got 12288 votes which were 64% of valid votes. Find total number of voters enrolled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "31250",
            "B": "30250",
            "C": "32152",
            "D": "30152"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "31250",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-294",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 294,
        "question": "In an election, 15% voters did not cast votes and 100 votes were declared invalid. Winner got 630 votes more than rival. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1200",
            "B": "1000",
            "C": "1100",
            "D": "900"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-295",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 295,
        "question": "In an election, defeated candidate secured 42% valid votes and winner got 76.8% of valid votes. Invalid votes were 52560 which were 20% of total votes. Find percentage of people who did NOT cast vote.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10.6%",
            "B": "9.8%",
            "C": "12.9%",
            "D": "6.7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-296",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 296,
        "question": "In an election between two candidates, 15% voters did not cast vote and 100 votes were declared invalid. Winner got 45% votes and won by margin of 400 votes. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6000",
            "B": "6500",
            "C": "3600",
            "D": "3500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-297",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 297,
        "question": "Rajit, Pooja and Abhi participated in election. Total votes were 40000. Rajit got 36% valid votes and Pooja got 40% valid votes. Find votes secured by Abhi.",
        "options": {
            "A": "9245",
            "B": "1024",
            "C": "8640",
            "D": "5760"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "8640",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-298",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 298,
        "question": "In an election, 83% voters cast votes and 4% votes were invalid. Party A got 156611 votes which were 83% of valid votes. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "258233",
            "B": "234888",
            "C": "236807",
            "D": "234687"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "236807",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-299",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 299,
        "question": "In an election between P, R and S, 10% votes were invalid. R and S got equal votes. Due to machine fault, half votes in favour of R counted in favour of S. Find overall percentage of votes secured by R.",
        "options": {
            "A": "37.55%",
            "B": "41.55%",
            "C": "38.55%",
            "D": "42.55%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "42.55%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-300",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 300,
        "question": "Hari, Kamal and Lalit contested election. 6050 votes were polled and 10% votes were invalid. Kamal got 42% more votes than Lalit. Lalit got 9% votes more than Hari. Find number of votes secured by Hari.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1912",
            "B": "1556",
            "C": "1916",
            "D": "1668"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1912",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-301",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 301,
        "question": "In an election between three candidates Arjun, Bhaskar and Saral, Arjun got 50% more votes than Saral and Saral got 2% votes less than Bhaskar. The difference between Bhaskar and Saral votes is 1296. Find half of the difference between Arjun and Bhaskar votes.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3888",
            "B": "13988",
            "C": "7766",
            "D": "15228"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "15228",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-302",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 302,
        "question": "Two candidates P and Q contested an election. 70% registered voters support P. If 60% of P supporters and 30% of Q supporters vote for P, find percentage of registered voters expected to vote for P.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "51%",
            "C": "26%",
            "D": "47%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "51%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-303",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 303,
        "question": "In an election, votes of three candidates are 6 times NOTA votes. Winner got twice second runner-up votes and first runner-up got 9000 more votes than NOTA. Winner defeated second runner-up by 150 votes. Find total votes polled.",
        "options": {
            "A": "17715",
            "B": "15177",
            "C": "11025",
            "D": "11577"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "11025",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-304",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 304,
        "question": "Three candidates P, Q and R participated in an election. P got 35% more votes than Q and R got 15% more votes than Q. P overtook R by 2412 votes. If 90% voters voted, find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "46900",
            "B": "42800",
            "C": "42210",
            "D": "48500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "46900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-305",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 305,
        "question": "28% people eligible to vote are between 20 and 25 years. 75% voted and 20 to 25 age group voted. Find percentage of eligible voters who did not vote.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "21%",
            "C": "28%",
            "D": "22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "21%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-306",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 306,
        "question": "In election, 35% voted for A and 50% of remaining voted for B. Remaining voted for C. Difference between voters for A and non-voters was 1000. Find total number of voters.",
        "options": {
            "A": "40000",
            "B": "60000",
            "C": "75000",
            "D": "55000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "40000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-307",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 307,
        "question": "In survey, 55% voters are male and rest female. 40% males and 33.33% females are literate. Find percentage of voters literate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "52%",
            "B": "48%",
            "C": "54%",
            "D": "37%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "52%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-308",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 308,
        "question": "In constituency, 55% voters are males and rest females. 40% males and 40% females are illiterate. Find percentage by which illiterate females exceed illiterate males.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21.5%",
            "B": "20.8%",
            "C": "16.4%",
            "D": "22.7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-309",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 309,
        "question": "In constituency, 45% voters male and rest female. 60% males and 60% females literate. Find percentage by which literate males exceed literate females.",
        "options": {
            "A": "19.11%",
            "B": "27.23%",
            "C": "30.24%",
            "D": "22.22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22.22%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T12-310",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XII",
        "question_number": 310,
        "question": "Candidate scored 75% marks in Paper A, 80% in Paper B and 60% in Paper C. Weightage ratio is 50%, 40% and 10%. Find weighted percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "77%",
            "B": "74%",
            "C": "72%",
            "D": "76%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "76%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-311",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 311,
        "question": "In a school, total students who play tennis and cricket together is 180. Students who play tennis are 70% of total students and cricket players are 60%. Students who do not play any game are 25%. Find total number of students.",
        "options": {
            "A": "500",
            "B": "480",
            "C": "400",
            "D": "680"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-312",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 312,
        "question": "40% students passed Maths, 50% passed English, and 14% passed both. If total students are 1400, find number of students who passed only one subject.",
        "options": {
            "A": "600",
            "B": "700",
            "C": "490",
            "D": "560"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "700",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-313",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 313,
        "question": "In village, 200% speak English only and Hindi speakers double of those who did not speak any language. Find number of students who speak both languages.",
        "options": {
            "A": "320",
            "B": "160",
            "C": "200",
            "D": "180"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "160",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-314",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 314,
        "question": "Survey shows people like Hindu and Times of India newspapers. Total surveyed 1750. Given data about readers, find number of people who like only Hindu.",
        "options": {
            "A": "40",
            "B": "25",
            "C": "30",
            "D": "35"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-315",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 315,
        "question": "In examination, 60% passed Physics, 37.5% passed Chemistry and 12.5% passed both. If total students 240, find percentage who failed.",
        "options": {
            "A": "16%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-316",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 316,
        "question": "In college, 43 passed accounts, 42 digital marketing, 40 science, 22 accounts and digital marketing, 23 accounts and science, 16 digital marketing and science, 10 passed none. Find percentage who passed only one subject.",
        "options": {
            "A": "93.99%",
            "B": "9.3%",
            "C": "11.11%",
            "D": "95%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "93.99%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-317",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 317,
        "question": "53% passed Maths, 61% Physics, 60% Chemistry. 24% passed Maths and Physics, 35% Physics and Chemistry, 27% Maths and Chemistry, 5% none. Find ratio of Maths & Chemistry only to Physics & Chemistry only.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7:5",
            "B": "5:7",
            "C": "4:5",
            "D": "5:4"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "5:7",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T13-318",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIII (Venn Diagram)",
        "question_number": 318,
        "question": "In class of 50 students, given numbers playing hockey, cricket, football and overlaps. If 18 play none, find ratio of students who play all sports to exactly two sports.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1:3",
            "B": "1:7",
            "C": "1:5",
            "D": "4:3"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1:5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-319",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 319,
        "question": "Agent gets 5% commission up to \u20b910000 and 4% above that. He gives \u20b928700 after deducting commission. Find total sales.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30000",
            "B": "24000",
            "C": "28000",
            "D": "32000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "30000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-320",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 320,
        "question": "Salesman allowed 12% commission up to \u20b915000 and 1% additional above. Total earnings \u20b97650. Find total sales.",
        "options": {
            "A": "56000",
            "B": "50000",
            "C": "60000",
            "D": "64000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "60000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-321",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 321,
        "question": "A company allows 7% commission on total sales. If salesman is appointed on fixed salary of \u20b93000 and 4% commission on sales more than \u20b910000, then salesman gets \u20b98000 more. Find total sales made by salesman.",
        "options": {
            "A": "60000",
            "B": "75000",
            "C": "56000",
            "D": "64000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "60000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-322",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 322,
        "question": "A company allows 13% commission on total sales. But if salesman is appointed on fixed salary of \u20b94700 and 7% commission on sales more than \u20b912000, salesman gets \u20b9620 more. Find total sales made by salesman.",
        "options": {
            "A": "50000",
            "B": "52000",
            "C": "57000",
            "D": "54000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "54000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-323",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 323,
        "question": "A marketing agent earns commission of 2% on first \u20b9200000, 1.5% on next \u20b9200000, and 1% on remaining amount. If total sales were \u20b9568000, find commission earned.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8860",
            "B": "7730",
            "C": "8240",
            "D": "7105"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "8860",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-324",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 324,
        "question": "Two saleswomen Kavitha and Kalyani earned 12% and 15% commission respectively. Kavitha gets 3% and Kalyani gets 5% extra bonus on sales more than \u20b920000. If difference in earnings is \u20b97600, find Kavitha's total earnings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "19200",
            "B": "21600",
            "C": "17800",
            "D": "23400"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "23400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T14-325",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Commission)",
        "question_number": 325,
        "question": "A salesman makes commission of x% on first \u20b93000 and y% on remaining sales. Commission from \u20b97000 was \u20b9960 and from \u20b98000 was \u20b91110. Find values of x and y.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12%, 15%",
            "B": "15%, 12%",
            "C": "10%, 15%",
            "D": "12%, 10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "12%, 15%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T15-326",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XV (Income Tax)",
        "question_number": 326,
        "question": "If rate of income tax increases by 27% and net income increases by 3%, find decrease in tax rate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6%",
            "B": "8%",
            "C": "12%",
            "D": "10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T15-327",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XV (Income Tax)",
        "question_number": 327,
        "question": "Income tax rate increased by x% but net income increased by 12% and gross income decreased by 3%. Find increase in tax rate.",
        "options": {
            "A": "22.4%",
            "B": "21.6%",
            "C": "20.8%",
            "D": "24.8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "22.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T15-328",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XV (Income Tax)",
        "question_number": 328,
        "question": "Income increased by \u20b91800 and payable tax decreased from 18% to 15%. Both tax amounts same. Find income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "9000",
            "B": "15000",
            "C": "12000",
            "D": "10000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "9000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T15-329",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XV (Income Tax)",
        "question_number": 329,
        "question": "Income increased by \u20b92000. Tax rate increased from 14% to 12%. Tax amount same. First \u20b92000 and next \u20b93000 tax-free. Find current income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6000",
            "B": "8000",
            "C": "5000",
            "D": "9000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "8000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T15-330",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XV (Income Tax)",
        "question_number": 330,
        "question": "Person income increased by \u20b928800 but tax reduced from 12% to 10%. Tax-free limit same. Find increase in income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1440",
            "B": "5760",
            "C": "6000",
            "D": "6500"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "5760",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-331",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 331,
        "question": "Income decreases by \u20b93000 and tax rate increases from 15% to 18%. Ratio of paid tax is 3:2. If 29% income is tax free, find initial income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6750",
            "B": "5550",
            "C": "7750",
            "D": "6250"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6750",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-332",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 332,
        "question": "A is 25% more than B, and B is 40% less than C. If C is 20% more than D, find percentage less than C that D is.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "9%",
            "D": "11%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "11%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-333",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 333,
        "question": "A is 25% more than B and B is 30% less than C. If C is 20% more than D, find percentage more than A that D is.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3%",
            "B": "6%",
            "C": "5%",
            "D": "2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-334",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 334,
        "question": "Sum of two numbers is 450. If greater increases by 4% and smaller decreases by 20%, resulting numbers equal. Find smaller number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "144",
            "B": "164",
            "C": "200",
            "D": "176"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-335",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 335,
        "question": "A is 25% more than B, and B is 40% less than C. If C is 20% more than D, find percentage less than A that D is.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-336",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 336,
        "question": "If number increases by 15% then decreases by 15%, result is 782. Same number increases by 25% then decreases by 20%. Find resulting number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "712",
            "B": "150",
            "C": "750",
            "D": "600"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-337",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 337,
        "question": "If 70% of number subtracted from second number makes second number 70% of first number, find ratio of first to second.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3:2",
            "B": "4:3",
            "C": "2:3",
            "D": "3:4"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "3:2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-338",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 338,
        "question": "Sum of two numbers is 660. If bigger increases by 15% and smaller decreases by 15%, resulting numbers equal. Find smaller number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "307",
            "B": "285",
            "C": "289",
            "D": "304"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "289",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-339",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 339,
        "question": "A invested 40% less than B and C invested \u20b98000. Average investment of A, B and C is \u20b96347. Find total investment.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6347",
            "B": "6417",
            "C": "6215",
            "D": "6143"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6347",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-340",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 340,
        "question": "Income of A is 30% less than B and income of B is 137.5% more than C. If income of A is \u20b928500 less than B, find income of C.",
        "options": {
            "A": "40000",
            "B": "50000",
            "C": "48000",
            "D": "36000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "40000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-341",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 341,
        "question": "A, B and C divided a sum. Average amount is \u20b94520. A\u2019s share is 10 2/3% more than B and 33 1/3% less than C. Find B\u2019s share.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3500",
            "B": "5976",
            "C": "3600",
            "D": "9384"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "3600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-342",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 342,
        "question": "A is 80% more than B and C is 48 4/7% less than sum of A and B. Find what percent C is less than A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-343",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 343,
        "question": "Number decreased by 20% gives second number. Second increased by 200% gives third number. Find percentage difference between first and third number.",
        "options": {
            "A": "More, 15.7%",
            "B": "Less, 15.7%",
            "C": "More, 12.5%",
            "D": "Less, 12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Less, 12.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-344",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 344,
        "question": "11/5 of number A is 22% of B. Number B is 2.5% of C. If C = 5500, find sum of 80% of A and 40% of B.",
        "options": {
            "A": "88",
            "B": "75",
            "C": "45",
            "D": "66"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "66",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-345",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 345,
        "question": "Student A got 25 marks more than B and marks of A were 60% of sum of their marks. Find marks of A and B respectively.",
        "options": {
            "A": "75, 100",
            "B": "75, 50",
            "C": "45, 120",
            "D": "55, 80"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "75, 50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-346",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 346,
        "question": "If Ram\u2019s income exceeds Shyam\u2019s by 70% and Shyam\u2019s income is 30% less than Sohan\u2019s income, find ratio of Ram and Sohan.",
        "options": {
            "A": "119:100",
            "B": "119:102",
            "C": "120:101",
            "D": "118:99"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "119:100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-347",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 347,
        "question": "Petrol price increased by 5%. Man travels 3045 km monthly, mileage 15 km/litre. Find increase in monthly expense (nearest \u20b9).",
        "options": {
            "A": "832",
            "B": "859",
            "C": "758",
            "D": "944"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "832",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-348",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 348,
        "question": "45% students passed history, 60% passed Hindi, 8% passed both. Find percent passed in both subjects.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "13%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "13%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-349",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 349,
        "question": "1/10 of total toffees wasted, 35% of rest given to N, 1/8 of total given to S, remaining to N. N has 10 more than S. Find toffees given to S.",
        "options": {
            "A": "126",
            "B": "110",
            "C": "135",
            "D": "100"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "126",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-350",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 350,
        "question": "Ravi gave 10% chocolates to sister, Bhanu gave 25% to friend. Bhanu had 54 chocolates left. Find chocolates Ravi gave to sister.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3",
            "B": "6",
            "C": "5",
            "D": "4"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-351",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 351,
        "question": "Mridula started her job with certain monthly salary and earns fixed increment every year. Salary was \u20b928400 after 6 years and \u20b952997 after 15 years. Find annual increment.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b912002",
            "B": "\u20b91200",
            "C": "\u20b92733",
            "D": "\u20b91824"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b92733",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-352",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 352,
        "question": "In group of 250 persons, 40% males and 60% females. If 30 more females join, find percentage of females in group.",
        "options": {
            "A": "72.25%",
            "B": "90.25%",
            "C": "64.29%",
            "D": "62.58%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "64.29%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-353",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 353,
        "question": "Price increased twice successively. Final price \u20b92295 and initial price \u20b91000. Second increase percent was twice first increase percent. Find second increase percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "65%",
            "C": "70%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "70%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-354",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 354,
        "question": "Price increases by 20% every year. If price at end of third year \u20b9324, find price at end of second year.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1350",
            "B": "1250",
            "C": "1260",
            "D": "1180"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1350",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-355",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 355,
        "question": "Person buys 10 chairs at \u20b94500. Later cost decreases by 20% and buys 10 more chairs. Find total purchase cost.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3260",
            "B": "3960",
            "C": "4100",
            "D": "3900"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "3960",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-356",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 356,
        "question": "Population increases annually by 20%. Present population 30 lakh. Find population difference after 3 years.",
        "options": {
            "A": "75592.6",
            "B": "85592.6",
            "C": "65592.6",
            "D": "92592.6"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "92592.6",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-357",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 357,
        "question": "Share price increased 10%, then decreased 8%, then decreased 8%. Final value \u20b912420. Find purchase value.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21080",
            "B": "21200",
            "C": "1260",
            "D": "1140"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "21080",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-358",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 358,
        "question": "Person loses 75% money, then 75% of remaining, then 75% again. If left \u20b9100, find initial money.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6400",
            "B": "2400",
            "C": "1600",
            "D": "3200"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-359",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 359,
        "question": "Man spends 60% salary on expenses. Salary increases by 30% and expenses by 60%. Savings increases by 250%. Find expenditure percentage of increased salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "32.7%",
            "B": "43.6%",
            "C": "29.5%",
            "D": "36.6%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "32.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-360",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 360,
        "question": "Units in Company A decreased from 12500 to 10625. Company B decreased from 34000 to 30600. Find ratio of percentage decreases.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5:3",
            "B": "3:4",
            "C": "3:2",
            "D": "8:5"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "3:2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-361",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 361,
        "question": "Labour cost increased by 25% and labour cost went from 30% to 38% of raw material cost. Find percentage decrease required in raw material cost to keep labour cost same.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20.7%",
            "B": "30.2%",
            "C": "24.6%",
            "D": "25.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "24.6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-362",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 362,
        "question": "Software company has 3 divisions with employees 20, 30, and 40. Weekend working percentages were 20%, 30%, and 40%. Find overall working percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "0.0032%",
            "B": "3.2%",
            "C": "0.032%",
            "D": "32%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "32%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-363",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 363,
        "question": "Businessman donated 50% profit first year. Remaining capital doubled over next two years. Final amount \u20b915360. Find initial investment.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20000",
            "B": "30000",
            "C": "25000",
            "D": "32000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "30000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-364",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 364,
        "question": "Fruit seller sells 45% oranges. Remaining sold in stages 20%, 90%, and 5. Find initial number of oranges.",
        "options": {
            "A": "100",
            "B": "120",
            "C": "111",
            "D": "121"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "120",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-365",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 365,
        "question": "Vipul spends 30% income on rent, 60% of remaining on groceries, 40% of remaining on others. Savings \u20b97056. Find total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "18323",
            "B": "15233",
            "C": "22386",
            "D": "17640"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "22386",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-366",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 366,
        "question": "Person spends 10% on groceries, 10% medicines, 20% education, 15% rent and saves remaining. Income \u20b930000. Find savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15500",
            "B": "13500",
            "C": "16500",
            "D": "12500"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "13500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-367",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 367,
        "question": "Ram spends 30% on food, 10% house rent, 7% entertainment, 6% conveyance. Savings \u20b91880. Find total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4000",
            "B": "4450",
            "C": "5000",
            "D": "5550"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "4000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-368",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 368,
        "question": "Software engineer spends 15% rent, 25% groceries, 25% income tax, 15% remaining. Savings \u20b910404. Find income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "22600",
            "B": "24600",
            "C": "25600",
            "D": "23600"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-369",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 369,
        "question": "Pranav gave 30% to wife, 86% remaining to children, half remaining spent. Balance \u20b998000 deposited. Find initial amount.",
        "options": {
            "A": "200000",
            "B": "400000",
            "C": "100000",
            "D": "300000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-370",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 370,
        "question": "Man spends 35% income on food and 4/13 of remaining on transport. Saves \u20b96300 equal to 20% of remaining. Find income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "67500",
            "B": "72000",
            "C": "70000",
            "D": "63000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "70000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-371",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 371,
        "question": "Swati earns \u20b940000 and saves 25%. Remaining is spent on food and education in ratio 3:2. Find percentage expenditure on education relative to total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "60%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "30%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-372",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 372,
        "question": "Person spends 40% salary on food, 50% of remaining on transport, and 30% of remaining on clothes. Saves \u20b91260. Find monthly salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10000",
            "B": "6000",
            "C": "7000",
            "D": "8000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "6000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-373",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 373,
        "question": "Swastik saves 20%, spends remaining in ratio food:education:shopping = 3:2:2. If food expense \u20b97200, find monthly income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "9600",
            "B": "12000",
            "C": "15000",
            "D": "10800"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-374",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 374,
        "question": "Family earns \u20b975000, saves 10%. Remaining expenditure on education \u20b930375, rest on food. Find food expenditure percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "21.5%",
            "C": "31.5%",
            "D": "32.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "31.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-375",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 375,
        "question": "Akshay spends 25% food, 26% recreation, 23% education. Remaining \u20b926600 saved. Find total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "195000",
            "B": "183000",
            "C": "162000",
            "D": "171000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "171000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-376",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 376,
        "question": "Family saves 15% and spends rest in ratio health:education:food = 17:34:34. If education expense \u20b93300 less than savings, find health expenditure.",
        "options": {
            "A": "300",
            "B": "350",
            "C": "250",
            "D": "500"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "300",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-377",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 377,
        "question": "Monthly income \u20b980000. Expenses include education, household, savings, GPF, EMI. EMI equals savings. Find EMI.",
        "options": {
            "A": "14000",
            "B": "16000",
            "C": "20000",
            "D": "18000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "16000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-378",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 378,
        "question": "Bhavani spends 15% kids education, 20% food, 40% house rent, 30% transport. Left \u20b910257. Find total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "45800",
            "B": "48000",
            "C": "52600",
            "D": "81965"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "52600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-379",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 379,
        "question": "Shiva salary \u20b975000. Expenses and savings given. Savings \u20b921000. Rest donated. Find donation percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3%",
            "B": "6%",
            "C": "8%",
            "D": "4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-380",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 380,
        "question": "Raju spends 10% transport, 20% food, 30% clothing. Savings \u20b926460. Find total food and clothing expenditure.",
        "options": {
            "A": "26420",
            "B": "22140",
            "C": "23440",
            "D": "24480"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "22140",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-381",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 381,
        "question": "A family saves 30% of total income and savings amount \u20b9600 is less than half of expenditure. Expenditure is spent on health, food, and education in ratio 3:5:6. Find amount spent on education.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3600",
            "B": "1800",
            "C": "7200",
            "D": "8400"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "3600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-382",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 382,
        "question": "Mr. Stark gave 30% of money to Bruce. He gave 30% of remaining amount to Natasha, Captain and Vision each. Half of remaining amount spent and remaining \u20b914000 deposited. Find initial money.",
        "options": {
            "A": "390000",
            "B": "400000",
            "C": "370000",
            "D": "300000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "400000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-383",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 383,
        "question": "Aman gave 30% income to father. Of remaining, 30% to daughter and 25% to wife. Remaining equally invested in 3 schemes giving \u20b942000 each. Find total income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "300000",
            "B": "400000",
            "C": "200000",
            "D": "500000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "400000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-384",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 384,
        "question": "Ramesh spends 40% salary on food, 18% rent, 12% entertainment, and 5% conveyance. He borrowed \u20b916000 to meet total expenses \u20b920000. Find salary.",
        "options": {
            "A": "18000",
            "B": "16500",
            "C": "16000",
            "D": "15000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-385",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 385,
        "question": "Family income \u20b935000. Health expense 50% more than food. Food half of entertainment. Health half of education. Education one-third of total expenditure. Find education expense.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12600",
            "B": "8400",
            "C": "13200",
            "D": "7700"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "12600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-386",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 386,
        "question": "Passing marks 32 for exam of 80 marks. Find student scoring minimum marks if conditions given.",
        "options": {
            "A": "19%",
            "B": "17%",
            "C": "72%",
            "D": "160%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "19%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-387",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 387,
        "question": "Students passed 30%, failed 20%. From passed group 30% appeared second exam. If 90% passed both, find percentage who failed first exam.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8.3%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "6.4%",
            "D": "5.7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-388",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 388,
        "question": "Two papers equal marks. Weight ratio 2:1. Student scored 8/10 in paper B. Find score in paper A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6.5",
            "B": "5.5",
            "C": "5",
            "D": "6"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-389",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 389,
        "question": "Vikas marks ratio in exams 3:5:6. Percentage ratio 7:11:10. Find number of exams scoring more than 50%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "None",
            "B": "2",
            "C": "3",
            "D": "1"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-390",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 390,
        "question": "Grade based on Internal 30%, Assignment 30%, External 40%. Student scored 90%, 95%, 75%. Find overall grade.",
        "options": {
            "A": "86.25%",
            "B": "85.25%",
            "C": "86%",
            "D": "85.50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "85.50%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-391",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 391,
        "question": "Some students appeared for an Olympiad exam. 20% of boys and 15% of girls failed. Number of boys passed was 70 more than girls passed. Total failed students were 90. Find total students.",
        "options": {
            "A": "420",
            "B": "400",
            "C": "500",
            "D": "350"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-392",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 392,
        "question": "B obtained 20% more marks than A. A obtained 10% less than C. D obtained 20% more than B. Find percentage D more than A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "33 1/3%",
            "B": "13 1/3%",
            "C": "15 1/3%",
            "D": "23 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "33 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-393",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 393,
        "question": "Students counts are 25, 30, 45, 60 with pass percentages 20%, 30%, 35%, 40%. Find overall pass percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "67%",
            "B": "63%",
            "C": "53%",
            "D": "79%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "53%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-394",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 394,
        "question": "Students appeared from X and Y. 50% from X failed. 150% more from Y than X. If 60% of total appeared from X passed, find percentage failed from Y.",
        "options": {
            "A": "18%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "16%",
            "D": "24%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-395",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 395,
        "question": "Income of A is 45% more than B. B is 60% less than sum of A and B. D is 20% more than C. Find income of D.",
        "options": {
            "A": "75000",
            "B": "73500",
            "C": "72500",
            "D": "72000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "73500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-396",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 396,
        "question": "Three persons donate 10%, 7%, and 9%. Monthly salary A and B equal. Difference in donation \u20b9900. Total donation \u20b9600 more than C. Find salary of C.",
        "options": {
            "A": "60000",
            "B": "50000",
            "C": "45000",
            "D": "55000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "50000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-397",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 397,
        "question": "Workshop with 80 students and 10 resources. Sweet amount equals amount per resource person which equals 40% of total students. Find sweet distribution total.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2420",
            "B": "2240",
            "C": "2400",
            "D": "2240"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2240",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-398",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 398,
        "question": "Salary last year \u20b912000 and \u20b910000. This year \u20b914400 and \u20b912500. Find (x\u2212y)/y \u00d7 100.",
        "options": {
            "A": "24",
            "B": "25",
            "C": "26",
            "D": "28"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "28",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-399",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 399,
        "question": "Decreasing 180 by x% equals increasing 60 by x%. Find x% of 410 more than (x+20)% of 210.",
        "options": {
            "A": "37.57%",
            "B": "36.57%",
            "C": "39.46%",
            "D": "31.67%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "39.46%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-400",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 400,
        "question": "Decreasing 110 by x% equals increasing 50 by x%. Find x% of 650 more than (x+20)% of 108.",
        "options": {
            "A": "80%",
            "B": "90%",
            "C": "136%",
            "D": "154%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "136%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-401",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 401,
        "question": "If (x + 20)% of 250 is 25% more than x% of 220, then 10% of (x + 50) is what percent less than 15% of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "13 1/3%",
            "B": "8 1/3%",
            "C": "16 2/3%",
            "D": "33 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16 2/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-402",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 402,
        "question": "Pranjal division mistake: divisor 25% more, dividend 10% less. Wrong quotient 25 remainder 0. Find correct quotient.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21.75",
            "B": "22",
            "C": "28.75",
            "D": "22.25"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22.25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-403",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 403,
        "question": "Mistaken dividend 10% less, divisor 20% less. Wrong quotient 24 remainder 0. Find correct quotient.",
        "options": {
            "A": "27",
            "B": "30",
            "C": "26.4",
            "D": "31.6"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "27",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-404",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 404,
        "question": "42% income equals 56% Bhaskar income. Bhaskar raised \u20b9200 weekly. Find Ranjita income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4200",
            "B": "3600",
            "C": "3000",
            "D": "4000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "4000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-405",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 405,
        "question": "57% income equals 76% Bhaskar income. Ranjita income reduced \u20b9400. Find Bhaskar income.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2800",
            "B": "2400",
            "C": "3000",
            "D": "3200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "3000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-406",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 406,
        "question": "Monthly salary \u20b9160000. P=50%, E=20%, T=15%, B=5%. Later salary increases 20%, E and T remain percentage. B becomes 20% of E. Find sum of savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "211680",
            "B": "128160",
            "C": "118620",
            "D": "162810"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "128160",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-407",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 407,
        "question": "Salary \u20b975000. Expense percentages given. After 40% increase, expense percentages adjusted. Find ratio of old savings to new savings.",
        "options": {
            "A": "655:644",
            "B": "325:337",
            "C": "644:655",
            "D": "337:325"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "655:644",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-408",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 408,
        "question": "Population 7640. Male increased 25%, female 15%. Total becomes 9214. Find difference between present male and female.",
        "options": {
            "A": "940",
            "B": "960",
            "C": "820",
            "D": "920"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "920",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-409",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 409,
        "question": "Population 18000. Next year male increases 5%, female 7%. Total becomes 19200. Find ratio male:female.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2:5",
            "B": "1:5",
            "C": "4:3",
            "D": "3:5"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "1:5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-410",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 410,
        "question": "Population 15280. Male increases 25%, female 15%. Total becomes 18428. Find difference between present male and female.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1840",
            "B": "1380",
            "C": "920",
            "D": "2760"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1840",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-411",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 411,
        "question": "In a factory with 400 employees, male:female ratio is 5:3. 87.5% employees are regular. 92% male employees are regular. Find percentage of regular female employees.",
        "options": {
            "A": "80%",
            "B": "78%",
            "C": "87.5%",
            "D": "85%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "80%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-412",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 412,
        "question": "Population of country A decreases by p% and country B decreases by q%, p > q. Let x be ratio of A:B. Find percentage decrease in x.",
        "options": {
            "A": "100(p\u2212q)/(100\u2212q)",
            "B": "100(p\u2212q)/(100+p)",
            "C": "100(p\u2212q)/(100\u2212p)",
            "D": "100(p\u2212q)/(100+q)"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "100(p\u2212q)/(100\u2212q)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-413",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 413,
        "question": "Rajesh had 500 eggs. Each day he sold 20% eggs and added b% next morning. After 3 days he had 1024 eggs. Find b.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20",
            "B": "10",
            "C": "50",
            "D": "100"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-414",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 414,
        "question": "35% employees science, 20% arts, rest commerce or illiterate. Illiterate = 300 = half commerce. Find science or arts employees.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1500",
            "B": "1200",
            "C": "1100",
            "D": "1300"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-415",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 415,
        "question": "Government distributed rice but distributor cheated using 3.75 kg instead of 4.5 kg and sold saved rice at double price. Distributed 2700 kg rice. Find fine amount.",
        "options": {
            "A": "36000",
            "B": "45000",
            "C": "28000",
            "D": "54000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "45000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PERC-T16-416",
        "chapter": "Percentage",
        "type": "Type-XVI (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 416,
        "question": "Monthly consumption rice 20kg and wheat 8kg. Rice price 20% of wheat price. Total expense \u20b9300. Wheat price increases 20%. Find reduction in rice consumption to maintain same expense.",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "38%",
            "C": "24%",
            "D": "22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-001",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 1,
        "question": "A wrist watch was purchased for \u20b93,000 and sold for \u20b93,500. Find the profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "19.58%",
            "B": "18.33%",
            "C": "16.66%",
            "D": "20.50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16.66%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-002",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 2,
        "question": "A table was bought for \u20b93,000 and sold for \u20b93,200. Find the gain or loss.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain 200",
            "B": "Loss 200",
            "C": "Gain 100",
            "D": "Loss 150"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Gain 200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-003",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 3,
        "question": "Mihir buys a book for \u20b9625 and sells it for \u20b9550. Find loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "14%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-004",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 4,
        "question": "Ranvijay sells vegetables worth \u20b94,960 for \u20b94,712 due to weather conditions. Find loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "5%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-005",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 5,
        "question": "A man buys 10 identical articles for \u20b915 and sells each for \u20b91.7. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4.33%",
            "B": "12.76%",
            "C": "13.33%",
            "D": "10.50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "13.33%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-006",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 6,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought an oven for \u20b925,000 and sold it for \u20b929,500 after spending \u20b91,500. Find gain/loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain 13%",
            "B": "Gain 15%",
            "C": "Loss 13%",
            "D": "Loss 15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Gain 15%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-007",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 7,
        "question": "An article is sold at profit of 250%. Find ratio of cost price and selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2:5",
            "B": "5:2",
            "C": "2:7",
            "D": "7:2"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "2:7",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-008",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 8,
        "question": "An HP printer was bought for \u20b94,800 and \u20b9500 spent on repair. Sold for \u20b96,360. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "18%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-009",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 9,
        "question": "Cost price is \u20b96,450. Profit is 16%. Find selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7482",
            "B": "7428",
            "C": "7842",
            "D": "7728"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "7482",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-010",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 10,
        "question": "Seller made 22% profit selling oven at \u20b98,540. Find cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6500",
            "B": "6000",
            "C": "7000",
            "D": "7500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "7000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-011",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 11,
        "question": "From the given data, find the ratio of the cost prices of a shirt and a trouser. Shirt SP = 1200, Profit = 20%. Trouser SP = 660, Profit = 10%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2:1",
            "B": "3:4",
            "C": "1:3",
            "D": "5:3"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5:3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-012",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 12,
        "question": "Skirt purchased at \u20b9650 and sold at profit of 26%. Find selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "819",
            "B": "813",
            "C": "823",
            "D": "829"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "819",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-013",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 13,
        "question": "Shopkeeper charges customer 14% more than cost price. If customer paid \u20b918,240, find cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20793.60",
            "B": "16000",
            "C": "16600",
            "D": "15686.40"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "16000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-014",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 14,
        "question": "Selling hair oil product at \u20b9336 gives 12% gain. If gain reduced to 9%, find new selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "330",
            "B": "300",
            "C": "327",
            "D": "339"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "327",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-015",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 15,
        "question": "Car sold at \u20b92,78,000 gives 35% gain. If gain reduced to 18%, find selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "262432",
            "B": "265432",
            "C": "272432",
            "D": "260432"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "262432",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-016",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 16,
        "question": "If article sold for \u20b9702 gives loss 33%, find SP for 37% profit.",
        "options": {
            "A": "911",
            "B": "846",
            "C": "822",
            "D": "781"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "822",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-017",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 17,
        "question": "Article sold for \u20b9480 gives loss 16\u2154%. To gain 8\u2153%, find SP.",
        "options": {
            "A": "620",
            "B": "605",
            "C": "624",
            "D": "750"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "605",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-018",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 18,
        "question": "Man sells cow for \u20b922000 and gains 10%. At what price should sell to gain 14%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "23000",
            "B": "23800",
            "C": "22900",
            "D": "23200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "22900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-019",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 19,
        "question": "Selling price \u20b92200 gives profit 10%. If sold at \u20b92600, find profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "37%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "30%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-020",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 20,
        "question": "Man loses 28% selling article for \u20b9288. Find gain/loss percent if sold for \u20b9144.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain 41%",
            "B": "Loss 43%",
            "C": "Gain 44%",
            "D": "Loss 46%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Gain 44%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-025",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 25,
        "question": "If books bought at prices ranging from \u20b9200 to \u20b9260 are sold at prices ranging from \u20b9250 to \u20b9300, what is the greatest possible profit that might be made in selling 25 books?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2300",
            "B": "2500",
            "C": "1800",
            "D": "2700"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-026",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 26,
        "question": "A mobile phone dealer buys a phone for \u20b910000 and sells it for \u20b912000. Later, he realizes that he could have sold it for \u20b913000. What is the percentage loss that he incurs?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-027",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 27,
        "question": "Manjeet bought a second-hand motorbike for \u20b922000 and spent \u20b93000 on overhauling and maintenance. He then sold it with 12% profit. If he had sold it for \u20b9500 less, what would have been his profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "10.5%",
            "C": "8%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-028",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 28,
        "question": "A merchant sells 195 kg of wheat for \u20b910260 at a profit of \u20b94.50 per kg of wheat. What is the cost price (\u20b9, to nearest integer) of 15 kg of wheat?",
        "options": {
            "A": "722",
            "B": "682",
            "C": "595",
            "D": "750"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "722",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-029",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 29,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought 288 oranges for \u20b9115.20. He sold 50 oranges at 70 paise each and the remaining at \u20b946.20. Find his profit or loss.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit \u20b925",
            "B": "Loss \u20b934",
            "C": "Profit \u20b937",
            "D": "Loss \u20b936"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss \u20b934",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-030",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 30,
        "question": "A shopkeeper buys 1800 kg wheat for \u20b932400. If 20% of wheat is spoiled due to rain, at what rate (\u20b9/kg) should he sell the rest to earn 20% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "29",
            "B": "26",
            "C": "25",
            "D": "27"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "27",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-031",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 31,
        "question": "A trader buys 500 kg cotton for \u20b98,000. If 10% of this cotton is spoiled due to rain, at what rate (\u20b9/kg) should he sell the rest to earn a 20% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "21 $\\frac{1}{3}$",
            "B": "22 $\\frac{1}{3}$",
            "C": "25 $\\frac{1}{3}$",
            "D": "23 $\\frac{1}{3}$"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "21 $\\frac{1}{3}$",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-032",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 32,
        "question": "A retailer purchased a batch of goods for \u20b95,000. Due to a manufacturing defect, 5% of the goods were damaged. If the retailer wants to make a profit of 20% on the remaining goods, at what price should the undamaged goods be sold?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95,700",
            "B": "\u20b95,800",
            "C": "\u20b96,000",
            "D": "\u20b95,900"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b95,700",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-033",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 33,
        "question": "A grocer purchased 10 kg rice for \u20b9700. He spends some amount on transportation and then sells it for \u20b91,400. If the percentage of profit made by the grocer is 30%, then what is the amount (in) he spends on transportation? (Round off to the nearest integer)",
        "options": {
            "A": "350",
            "B": "380",
            "C": "300",
            "D": "377"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "377",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-034",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 34,
        "question": "A vendor buys 20 laptop bags for \u20b913,000 and sells them at 15 for \u20b910,125. How many laptop bags should be bought and sold to earn a profit of \u20b93,225?",
        "options": {
            "A": "123",
            "B": "129",
            "C": "120",
            "D": "127"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "129",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T1-035",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 35,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought 95 dozen oranges at \u20b94.50 each. 7 dozen oranges were rotten and so were discarded. He sold the remaining oranges at \u20b978 per dozen. What is his profit or loss per cent (to the nearest integer)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Loss, 45%",
            "B": "Profit, 34%",
            "C": "Loss, 34%",
            "D": "Profit, 45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Profit, 34%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-036",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 36,
        "question": "The difference between the cost price and the selling price of an article is \u20b91,800. If there is a profit of 20%, then the cost price of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b99,000",
            "B": "\u20b98,000",
            "C": "\u20b911,000",
            "D": "\u20b97,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b99,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-037",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 37,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sold an article at a 26% profit. On selling it for \u20b92,250 more, he would get a profit of 41%. If this article is sold at 12% profit, then the selling price would be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b916,800",
            "B": "\u20b915,000",
            "C": "\u20b915,800",
            "D": "\u20b916,120"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b916,800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-038",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 38,
        "question": "A trader sells an article at 16% below its cost price. Had he sold it for \u20b9192.20 more, he would have gained 15%. The new selling price (in \u20b9) of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "742",
            "B": "731",
            "C": "713",
            "D": "724"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "713",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-039",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 39,
        "question": "A man sold his cycle at 17% loss. If he had sold it for 1,056 more, he would have made 5% profit. The cost price of the cycle is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b94,700",
            "B": "\u20b94,800",
            "C": "\u20b95,100",
            "D": "\u20b93,800"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b94,800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-040",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 40,
        "question": "A seller sold a bag at a profit of 12%. If he had sold it for \u20b9900 more, he would have gained 27%. What is the CP of the bag?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96,000",
            "B": "\u20b96,500",
            "C": "\u20b95,560",
            "D": "\u20b97,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b96,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T2-041",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-II (Difference Between SP & CP)",
        "question_number": 41,
        "question": "On selling a table for \u20b9210 and \u20b9420 there will be loss of $L_{1}$% and $L_{2}$% respectively. If $L_{1} - L_{2} = 7$, then what is the cost price of table?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95,000",
            "B": "\u20b93,000",
            "C": "\u20b97,000",
            "D": "\u20b94,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b93,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-042",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 42,
        "question": "If the cost price of 28 oranges is equal to selling price of 24 oranges, then the profit percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
            "B": "16 $\\frac{1}{3}$%",
            "C": "18 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
            "D": "18 $\\frac{1}{3}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-043",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 43,
        "question": "If the selling price of 40 articles is equal to the cost price of 50 articles, then the percentage gain is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "35%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-044",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 44,
        "question": "If the selling price of 100 pens is equal to the cost price of 140 pens, find the profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "36%",
            "B": "45%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-045",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 45,
        "question": "The selling price of 84 items is equal to the cost price of 105 items. What is the percentage of profit gained in the transaction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "28%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "21%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-046",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 46,
        "question": "The selling price of 80 items is equal to the cost price of 72 items. What is the percentage of loss incurred in the transaction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "12%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "9%",
            "D": "11 $\\frac{1}{9}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-047",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 47,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought 30 books and sold 25 books for same price. What percentage had he gained or lost?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20% loss",
            "B": "20% gain",
            "C": "25% gain",
            "D": "25% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20% gain",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-048",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 48,
        "question": "If the selling price of 50 articles is equal to the cost price of 42 articles, then what is the approximate loss or profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "8% profit",
            "B": "16% loss",
            "C": "10% loss",
            "D": "20% profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "16% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-049",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 49,
        "question": "The cost price of 36 articles is the same as the selling price of N articles. If the profit is 20%, then the value of N is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "25",
            "B": "42",
            "C": "40",
            "D": "30"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "30",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-050",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 50,
        "question": "The selling price of y items is equal to the cost price of 540 items. If the profit made is 44%, then find the value of y.",
        "options": {
            "A": "375",
            "B": "400",
            "C": "360",
            "D": "380"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "375",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-051",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 51,
        "question": "The cost price of 240 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If profit is 20%, find the value of x.",
        "options": {
            "A": "200",
            "B": "210",
            "C": "180",
            "D": "240"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-052",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 52,
        "question": "The cost price of 44 items is the same as the selling price of x items. If the profit is 10%, then what is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "55",
            "B": "40",
            "C": "60",
            "D": "50"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T3-053",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-III (CP of X = SP of Y)",
        "question_number": 53,
        "question": "If 70% of the cost price of an article is equal to 40% of its selling price, what is the profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "85%",
            "B": "80%",
            "C": "70%",
            "D": "75%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "75%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-054",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 54,
        "question": "By selling 42 m of cloth, Vijay gains the selling price of 7 m of cloth. Find the profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "30%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-055",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 55,
        "question": "By selling 60 pens, a man gain an amount equal to the selling price of 12 pens. What is his gain percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "22%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "27%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-056",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 56,
        "question": "By selling 22 items, Rohit gains the selling price of 6 items. His gain per cent is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "37 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
            "B": "37 $\\frac{1}{3}$%",
            "C": "33 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
            "D": "33 $\\frac{1}{3}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "37 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-057",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 57,
        "question": "In a medical transaction, 17 times the cost price is equal to 8 times the sum of the cost price and the selling price. What is the gain or loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Loss 15%",
            "B": "Gain 17.5%",
            "C": "Gain 12.5%",
            "D": "Loss 30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Gain 12.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-058",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 58,
        "question": "By selling two articles for \u20b9800, a person gains the cost price of three articles. The profit percent is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "125%",
            "B": "140%",
            "C": "120%",
            "D": "150%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "150%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T4-059",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IV (Profit/Loss = CP/SP of Some Articles)",
        "question_number": 59,
        "question": "By selling 30 meters of cloth a shopkeeper makes a profit equivalent to the selling price of 10 meters of cloth. Find the selling price of 1 meter of cloth when the cost price of 1 meter of cloth is \u20b9480.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9520",
            "B": "\u20b9720",
            "C": "\u20b9960",
            "D": "\u20b9820"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9720",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-060",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 60,
        "question": "If loss is $\\frac{1}{8}$th of the selling price, then the actual loss percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "8 $\\frac{8}{9}$%",
            "B": "11 $\\frac{1}{9}$%",
            "C": "10 $\\frac{1}{9}$%",
            "D": "7 $\\frac{1}{9}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "11 $\\frac{1}{9}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-061",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 61,
        "question": "On selling an article for \u20b9800, a person loses 20% of its selling price. At what price should he sell it to gain 25% on its cost price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91280",
            "B": "\u20b91152",
            "C": "\u20b91250",
            "D": "\u20b91200"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b91200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-062",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 62,
        "question": "A man purchased a cell phone for \u20b924,500 and sold it at a gain of 12.5% calculated on the selling price. The selling price of the cell phone was:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b925,000",
            "B": "\u20b928,000",
            "C": "\u20b927,500",
            "D": "\u20b925,500"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b928,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-063",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 63,
        "question": "By selling an article for \u20b9640, a person loses 15% of its selling price. At what price (in \u20b9) should he sell it to gain 15% on its cost price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9835",
            "B": "\u20b9832",
            "C": "\u20b9836.60",
            "D": "\u20b9846.40"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9846.40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-064",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 64,
        "question": "Find the gain percentage, given that Priya sold her scooter for \u20b942564 gaining $\\frac{1}{6}$th of the selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "40%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-065",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 65,
        "question": "Find the gain percentage, given that Siddhi sold her scooter for \u20b971785 gaining $\\frac{1}{5}$th of the selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-066",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 66,
        "question": "Find the gain percentage, given that Anubha sold her scooter for \u20b923358 gaining $\\frac{1}{6}$th of the selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-067",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 67,
        "question": "Find the gain percentage, given that Aditi sold her scooter for \u20b940620 gaining $\\frac{1}{5}$th of the selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "35%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T5-068",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-V (Profit/Loss on Selling Price)",
        "question_number": 68,
        "question": "An article is sold at a loss of 40%. The nominal amount of loss is approximately what percentage of the selling price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "66.67%",
            "B": "38.33%",
            "C": "41.33%",
            "D": "51.33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "66.67%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-069",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 69,
        "question": "On selling a painting at \u20b91,498 the gain is 25% more than the loss incurred on selling it at \u20b91,300. In order to gain 25%, the selling price will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,735",
            "B": "\u20b91,335",
            "C": "\u20b91,398",
            "D": "\u20b91,388"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b91,735",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-070",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 70,
        "question": "The profit obtained by a vendor on selling goods at \u20b93,200 is equal to $\\frac{7}{5}$th of the profit obtained by selling the same goods at \u20b93,000. What is the cost price (in \u20b9) of the goods?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2,500",
            "B": "2,700",
            "C": "2,900",
            "D": "2,400"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2,500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-071",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 71,
        "question": "Ravi sells a laptop bag to Reeta for \u20b91,920 and he sells another similar laptop bag to Vinay for \u20b91,280. The percentage profit earned in selling the laptop bag to Reeta is equal to the percentage loss in selling the laptop bag to Vinay. At what price (in \u20b9) should Ravi sell the laptop bag to make a profit of 25%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2,000",
            "B": "1,600",
            "C": "1,800",
            "D": "1,650"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-072",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 72,
        "question": "The profit obtained by selling an article for \u20b986 is twice the loss obtained by selling the same article for \u20b953. Find the cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b933",
            "B": "\u20b922",
            "C": "\u20b964",
            "D": "\u20b975"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b964",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-073",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 73,
        "question": "The percentage profit earned by selling an article for \u20b92,100 is equal to the percentage loss incurred by selling the same article for \u20b91,460. At what price should the article be sold to make 20% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92156",
            "B": "\u20b92256",
            "C": "\u20b92136",
            "D": "\u20b92056"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b92136",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-074",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 74,
        "question": "By selling a watch for \u20b91600, a person gets profit is equal to the loss of selling the same watch for \u20b91400. If the person wants to get a profit of 20%, at what price should he sell the watch?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1700",
            "B": "1600",
            "C": "1800",
            "D": "1500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-075",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 75,
        "question": "By selling an article for \u20b91,170, Elisa suffers as much loss as she would have gained by selling it at a profit of 22%. If she sells it for \u20b91,450, then her profit/loss percent (correct up to one decimal place) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit, 3.33",
            "B": "Profit, 3.33",
            "C": "Profit, 26.2",
            "D": "Loss, 26.2"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Profit, 3.33",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T6-076",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VI (Butterfly Concept)",
        "question_number": 76,
        "question": "A man sells a mobile phone for Rs 680 and loses something. If he had sold it for Rs 1070, his gain would have been double the former loss. The cost price (in \u20b9) of the mobile phone is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "820",
            "B": "800",
            "C": "830",
            "D": "810"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "810",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-077",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 77,
        "question": "If oranges are bought at 11 for \u20b910 and sold at 10 for \u20b911, what is the gain or loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain 11%",
            "B": "Loss 11%",
            "C": "Loss 21%",
            "D": "Gain 21%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Gain 21%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-078",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 78,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought 60 pencils at a rate of 4 for \u20b95 and another 60 pencils at a rate of 2 for \u20b93. He mixed all the pencils and sold them at a rate of 3 for \u20b94. Find his gain or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit 2 $\\frac{7}{8}$%",
            "B": "Loss 3 $\\frac{1}{33}$%",
            "C": "Loss 2 $\\frac{7}{8}$%",
            "D": "Profit 3 $\\frac{1}{33}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss 3 $\\frac{1}{33}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-079",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 79,
        "question": "A retail fruit vendor buys a score of apples for Rs 400 and retails them for Rs 264 at a dozen. What was his loss/gain percent? (a score = 20 no's)",
        "options": {
            "A": "20% profit",
            "B": "10% loss",
            "C": "10% profit",
            "D": "5% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10% profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-080",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 80,
        "question": "A vendor buys 20 dozen bananas for \u20b91,200 and sells 5 dozen for \u20b9350. Then his gain percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "21 $\\frac{1}{3}$%",
            "B": "15 $\\frac{1}{3}$%",
            "C": "13 $\\frac{1}{3}$%",
            "D": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-081",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 81,
        "question": "A shopkeeper buys oranges at the rate of 10 oranges for \u20b950 and sells them at the rate of 12 oranges for \u20b974. Find his gain or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "23 $\\frac{1}{3}$% gain",
            "B": "25% gain",
            "C": "30% loss",
            "D": "25 $\\frac{1}{3}$% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "23 $\\frac{1}{3}$% gain",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-082",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 82,
        "question": "A vendor buys 20 pens for \u20b915 and sells them at 15 for \u20b920. How many pens should be bought and sold to earn a profit of \u20b9245?",
        "options": {
            "A": "280",
            "B": "540",
            "C": "320",
            "D": "420"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "420",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-083",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 83,
        "question": "A shopkeeper buys 60 oranges at 10 for \u20b972, and an equal number at 12 for \u20b990. He spends \u20b9118 on the transaction and sells all the oranges that he buys. If there is a profit of 26% in the entire transaction, then what is the selling price of 32 oranges?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9336",
            "B": "\u20b9313.60",
            "C": "\u20b9316.80",
            "D": "\u20b9320"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9336",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T7-084",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VII (Number of Articles)",
        "question_number": 84,
        "question": "A shopkeeper buys some notebooks at the rate of 12 for \u20b9222, and an equal number of notebooks at 10 for \u20b9225. If he sells all the notebooks at a profit of 20%, then the selling price of 15 notebooks is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9369",
            "B": "\u20b9376.5",
            "C": "\u20b9360",
            "D": "\u20b9302.40"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9369",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-085",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 85,
        "question": "Shopkeeper bought 40 pieces of an article at a rate of \u20b950 per item. He sold 35 pieces with 20% profit. The remaining 5 pieces were found to be damaged and he sold them with 10% loss. Find his overall profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "32.5%",
            "D": "16.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "16.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-086",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 86,
        "question": "Mukesh sells 80% part of a commodity at a profit of 20% and rest of the part at a loss of 5% and in this way earns a profit of \u20b99,300. What was the cost price of the commodity for Mukesh?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b961,000",
            "B": "\u20b958,000",
            "C": "\u20b962,000",
            "D": "\u20b960,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b960,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-087",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 87,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought certain number of apples for \u20b93,600. He sold one-fifth of them at a loss of 10%, one-fourth of the remaining apples at a loss of 5%, and two-third of the rest at a profit of 15%. At what price (in \u20b9) should he sell the remaining apples to earn a profit of 27% overall?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,548",
            "B": "\u20b91,584",
            "C": "\u20b91,845",
            "D": "\u20b91,864"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91,584",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-088",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 88,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sold $\\frac{5}{8}$ of his articles at a gain of 20% and the remaining at the cost price. What is his gain percentage in the whole transaction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "16 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
            "B": "14 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
            "C": "13 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
            "D": "12 $\\frac{1}{2}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12 $\\frac{1}{2}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-089",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 89,
        "question": "Ramesh purchased 130 books at the rate of \u20b9200 each and sold half of them at the rate of \u20b9300 each, $\\frac{1}{5}$ of them at the rate of \u20b9350 each and the rest at the cost price. Find his profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "38%",
            "D": "44%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-090",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 90,
        "question": "A merchant bought two watches for \u20b99,000 each. He sold one watch at a loss of 10%. At what price (in \u20b9) should he sold the other watch to earn a profit of 18% overall?",
        "options": {
            "A": "14,130",
            "B": "14,310",
            "C": "13,140",
            "D": "13,410"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "13,140",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-091",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 91,
        "question": "A vegetable vendor bought 100 kg of potatoes at the rate of \u20b919 per kg and spent \u20b9100 as cartage. He sold 60 kg of potatoes with a 50% profit and half of the remaining stock with a 40% profit. He sold half of the still remaining potatoes with a 25% profit. What profit percentage should he aim for when selling the ultimate remaining potatoes to achieve an overall profit of 42%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "0.16",
            "B": "0.1",
            "C": "0.12",
            "D": "0.15"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "0.15",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-092",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 92,
        "question": "On two items of equal prices, T gets 12% profit on one item and incurs 8% loss on other. What is his overall profit or loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit, 2%",
            "B": "Profit, 4%",
            "C": "Loss, 4%",
            "D": "Loss, 2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Profit, 2%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-093",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 93,
        "question": "A shopkeeper purchased 1600 mangoes at the rate of \u20b9120 per dozen. Out of these, he sold 900 mangoes at \u20b915 per mango and the remaining mangoes at \u20b914 per mango. His gain percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "45.625%",
            "B": "38.265%",
            "C": "35.625%",
            "D": "48.765%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "45.625%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-094",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 94,
        "question": "A person bought 80 pens at the rate of \u20b980 per pen. He sells 40 pens at a loss of 20%. If profit of 20 percent is earned on the all pens together, then what will be the profit percentage on the remaining 40 pens?",
        "options": {
            "A": "60%",
            "B": "80%",
            "C": "70%",
            "D": "90%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-095",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 95,
        "question": "A trader buys two articles for \u20b93000 each article, while selling, he earns a profit of 10 percent on one and loses 20 percent on the other. What will be his overall loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-096",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 96,
        "question": "Shivam purchased two watches, first for \u20b912,000 and the second for \u20b920,000. He sold both the watches, first one at the profit of 10 percent and the second at a loss of 20 percent. What is the overall profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit = \u20b92600",
            "B": "Loss = \u20b92800",
            "C": "Loss = \u20b92400",
            "D": "Profit = \u20b92200"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss = \u20b92800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-097",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 97,
        "question": "A man bought two bicycles for \u20b93,000 each. If he sells one bicycle at a profit of 10% then for how much percentage profit should he sell the other bicycle so that he makes a profit of 20% on the whole?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "30%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-098",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 98,
        "question": "Two similar pieces of an item were purchased by paying the same amount for each, and they were sold, respectively, for a profit of 25% and a loss of 20%. What was his profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.5",
            "B": "2",
            "C": "4.5",
            "D": "5"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-099",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 99,
        "question": "A trader purchased 500 kg of sugar at \u20b940 per kg. He sold 200 kg of it at a profit of 10% and 120 kg at a loss of 5%. At what rate per kg (in \u20b9, correct to 2 decimal places) should he sell the remaining sugar to gain 12% on his initial investment?",
        "options": {
            "A": "44.80",
            "B": "48.67",
            "C": "50.22",
            "D": "53.33"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "50.22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T8-100",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-VIII (Average Concept when CP is same)",
        "question_number": 100,
        "question": "A fruit merchant bought some bananas. $\\frac{1}{5}$th of them got rotten and were thrown away. He sold remaining $\\frac{2}{5}$th of the bananas with him at 15% profit and the remaining bananas at 10% profit. Find his overall loss or profit percent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit 9.6%",
            "B": "Loss 10.4%",
            "C": "Loss 9.6%",
            "D": "Profit 10.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss 10.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-101",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 101,
        "question": "A person sold two cars for \u20b960,000 each. On one, he gained 20% while on the other he lost 20%. Find the percentage of his gain or loss.",
        "options": {
            "A": "No profit and no loss",
            "B": "4% Loss",
            "C": "2% Loss",
            "D": "4% Profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4% Loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-102",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 102,
        "question": "Pradeep sells two fans at 480 each and by doing so he gains 20% on one fan and loses 20% on the other. His loss on the whole (in) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "30",
            "B": "10",
            "C": "20",
            "D": "40"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-103",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 103,
        "question": "A merchant sold two refrigerators for \u20b910,000 each. On one refrigerator, he incurred a 20% loss, and on the other, he gained 20%. What was his profit/loss percentage on the whole transaction?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit of 4%",
            "B": "Loss of 2%",
            "C": "Loss of 4%",
            "D": "Profit of 2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Loss of 4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-104",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 104,
        "question": "A person bought two goods for \u20b919,500. He sold one at a loss of 20% and the other at a profit of 15%. If the selling price of each goods is the same, find the cost price of goods sold at profit.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b911,475",
            "B": "\u20b99,750",
            "C": "\u20b911,500",
            "D": "\u20b98,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b98,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-105",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 105,
        "question": "A person bought two buffaloes for \u20b911,520. One is sold at a loss of 15% and the other is sold at a gain of 19%. If the selling price of both buffaloes is equal, find the cost price of the first one.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96,700",
            "B": "\u20b96,715",
            "C": "\u20b96,720",
            "D": "\u20b96,710"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b96,720",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-106",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 106,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sold 3 wristwatches for \u20b92,800 each. If he has sold the watches with 40%, 25% and 12% profit, respectively, then find his overall profit percentage (correct to 2 decimal places).",
        "options": {
            "A": "24.19",
            "B": "24.63",
            "C": "24.55",
            "D": "24.75"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "24.63",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-107",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 107,
        "question": "Two articles were sold for \u20b93,000 each, with no loss and profit in the entire transaction. If one was sold at a profit of 25%, then the loss incurred on the second article is ______.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "18 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
            "C": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
            "D": "15 $\\frac{2}{3}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16 $\\frac{2}{3}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-108",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 108,
        "question": "A person sold two items selling each for \u20b942,600. On the first item, He made a loss of 25% while on the second, he gained 20%. Find his overall percentage gain or loss, (giving your answer correct to one place of decimal.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "7.7% gain",
            "B": "7.7% loss",
            "C": "8.3% loss",
            "D": "8.2% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "7.7% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-109",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 109,
        "question": "Both A and B sells their watch at the rate of \u20b95,400 per watch. A earned a profit of 10 percent while B incurred a loss of 25 percent. What is the ratio of cost prices of A and B?",
        "options": {
            "A": "19 : 23",
            "B": "15 : 22",
            "C": "15 : 19",
            "D": "18 : 25"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15 : 22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-110",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 110,
        "question": "Manoj bought two T.V. for \u20b92,280. He sold one at a loss of 20 percent and other at a profit of 10 percent. If each T.V. was sold for the same price, then what is the cost price of the T.V which was sold at loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,380",
            "B": "\u20b91,320",
            "C": "\u20b91,050",
            "D": "\u20b91,440"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91,320",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-111",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 111,
        "question": "A man sells two cows for \u20b915,640 each, gaining 15% on one and losing 15% on the other. Find his total gain or loss.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9720 loss",
            "B": "\u20b9360 loss",
            "C": "\u20b9720 gain",
            "D": "\u20b9360 gain"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9720 loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-112",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 112,
        "question": "The selling prices of articles A and B are the same. A is sold at a profit of 28 percent and B is sold at a loss of 24 percent. If the total selling price of the both articles is \u20b948640, then what is the cost price of A and B, respectively?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b926000, \u20b940000",
            "B": "\u20b917000, \u20b928000",
            "C": "\u20b919000, \u20b932000",
            "D": "\u20b924000, \u20b938000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b919000, \u20b932000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-113",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 113,
        "question": "Aditya sells two wrist watches from his personal collection for \u20b912,600 each. On the first watch, he gains 26% and, on the second, he loses 10%. Find the overall gain or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain of 16%",
            "B": "Gain of 5%",
            "C": "Loss of 5%",
            "D": "Gain of 12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Gain of 5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-114",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 114,
        "question": "A man buys two watches 'A' and 'B' at a total cost of \u20b9800. He sells both watches at the same selling price, and earn a profit of 18% on watch 'A' and incurs a loss of 22% on watch 'B'. What are the cost prices of the two watches? (two place after decimal).",
        "options": {
            "A": "A = \u20b9350.32 and B = \u20b9450.68",
            "B": "A = \u20b9318.37 and B = \u20b9481.63",
            "C": "A = \u20b9220 and B = \u20b9580",
            "D": "A = 317 and B = 483"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "A = \u20b9318.37 and B = \u20b9481.63",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T9-115",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-IX (When SP is Same)",
        "question_number": 115,
        "question": "A man sold two gifts at \u20b930 each. On one gift he gained 18%, and on the other gift he lost 18%. What is his overall gain/loss (in \u20b9)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Loss of \u20b92.00",
            "B": "Gain of \u20b92.00",
            "C": "Loss of \u20b92.50",
            "D": "Gain of \u20b91.75"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Loss of \u20b92.00",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T10-116",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-X (CP of 1st ARTICLE = SP of 2nd ARTICLE)",
        "question_number": 116,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sold two items. The selling price of the first item equals the cost price of the second item. He sold the first item a profit of 20% and the second item at a loss of 10%. What is his overall profit/loss percent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Loss 4 $\\frac{6}{11}$%",
            "B": "Profit 3 $\\frac{7}{11}$%",
            "C": "Profit 4 $\\frac{6}{11}$%",
            "D": "Loss 8 $\\frac{1}{3}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Profit 3 $\\frac{7}{11}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-117",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 117,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer decided to sell his goods at cost price, but uses a weight of 960 grams for a kilogram weight. His gain percent is.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4 $\\frac{1}{6}$%",
            "B": "2 $\\frac{1}{4}$%",
            "C": "1 $\\frac{1}{4}$%",
            "D": "3 $\\frac{1}{6}$%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "4 $\\frac{1}{6}$%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-118",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 118,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer announces selling his articles with 22% loss, but uses 35% lighter weights. What is the percentage of his profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "13% loss",
            "B": "20% profit",
            "C": "20% loss",
            "D": "13% profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20% profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-119",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 119,
        "question": "A dishonest trader marks up his goods by 50% and then allows a discount of 20% on its marked price. Additionally, he uses a faulty scale which measures 900 gm. for 1 kg. shows. What will be his net profit percentage (rounded off to the nearest integer)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33",
            "B": "36",
            "C": "27",
            "D": "24"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "33",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-120",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 120,
        "question": "A grocer professes to sell rice at the cost price, but uses a fake weight of 870 gm for 1 kg. Find his profit percentage (correct to two decimal places).",
        "options": {
            "A": "15.11%",
            "B": "14.94%",
            "C": "18.21%",
            "D": "11.11%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "14.94%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-121",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 121,
        "question": "A dishonest shopkeeper claims to sell salt at a rate of \u20b925/kg. The cost price of the salt is \u20b925/kg. Not satisfied with this, he tries to make profit by removing 200 gm from each 1 kg. What is the shopkeeper's gain percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-122",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 122,
        "question": "A dishonest merchant sells his grocery using weights that are 12% less than the true weights and marked the price 10% above. Find his total gain percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-123",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 123,
        "question": "Ramesh sells rice at \u20b936 per kg, which he purchased for \u20b930 per kg. Moreover, he gives only 800 gm of rice instead of 1 kg while selling. Find the actual profit percentage of Ramesh.",
        "options": {
            "A": "46%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "48%",
            "D": "52%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "50%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-124",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 124,
        "question": "A dishonest fruit-seller sells fruits at 20% profit but he uses 950 gm weight in place of 1 kg. What is the profit percent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "$\\frac{500}{17}$ %",
            "B": "$\\frac{500}{19}$ %",
            "C": "$\\frac{500}{32}$ %",
            "D": "$\\frac{700}{19}$ %"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "$\\frac{500}{19}$ %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-125",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 125,
        "question": "A seller sold 19 cookies for \u20b995 instead of 20 cookies in 1 kg, cheating a customer. What is the gain (in \u20b9) if the seller bought the cookies for \u20b976?",
        "options": {
            "A": "28.2",
            "B": "26.2",
            "C": "22.8",
            "D": "25.8"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "22.8",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-126",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 126,
        "question": "A vendor started selling vegetables at Rs.10 per kg, but couldn't find buyers at this rate. So he reduced the price to Rs.7.2 per kg, but uses a faulty weight of 900 gm instead of 1 kg. Find the percentage change in the actual price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-127",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 127,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells rice at the rate of \u20b944 per kg whose cost price is \u20b940 per kg. Not satisfied with this, he tries to increase his profit by removing 200 grams of rice from each packet. What is the shopkeeper's overall gain percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "35%",
            "B": "37.5%",
            "C": "37%",
            "D": "35.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "37.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-128",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 128,
        "question": "A shopkeeper has a fault of 100 gm in a 3 kg weight. He sold 3 kg of potatoes to Charu using the same faulty weight for Rs.46. The cost price of the potatoes for the seller was Rs.12 per kg. How much profit (in Rs.) did he earn on the potatoes?",
        "options": {
            "A": "11.6",
            "B": "10.2",
            "C": "11.2",
            "D": "10"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "11.2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-129",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 129,
        "question": "A shopkeeper cheats 25% in weight while buying rice and cheats 25% while selling it. If he sells the rice at 12.5% profit, then find his net profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "82.5%",
            "B": "62.5%",
            "C": "87.5%",
            "D": "92.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "87.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-130",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 130,
        "question": "A vendor sells his goods using weights 19% less than true weights and makes a profit of 35%. His net gain percentage (rounded off to 2 decimal places) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "66.67%",
            "B": "66.33%",
            "C": "81.33%",
            "D": "81.67%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "66.67%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-131",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 131,
        "question": "Ravi sells his goods at a 25% loss on cost price but uses 45% less weight. What is his percentage profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit, 47 $\\frac{9}{10}$ %",
            "B": "Loss, 36 $\\frac{4}{11}$ %",
            "C": "Loss, 47 $\\frac{9}{10}$ %",
            "D": "Profit, 36 $\\frac{4}{11}$ %"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Profit, 36 $\\frac{4}{11}$ %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-132",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 132,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells goods at 40% loss on cost price but uses 25% less weight. What is his percentage profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit, 20%",
            "B": "Loss, 10%",
            "C": "Loss, 20%",
            "D": "Profit, 10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Loss, 20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-133",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 133,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer professes to sell his goods at the cost price, but he uses a false weight of 850 grams per 1 kg weight. Find the percentage of his gain. (Correct up to two decimal places)",
        "options": {
            "A": "17.65%",
            "B": "17.54%",
            "C": "17.56%",
            "D": "17.45%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "17.65%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-134",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 134,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer sells his goods at 20% loss on the cost price but uses a faulty weight that weighs 25% less. His profit or loss percentage (rounded off to 2 decimal places) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "6.67%, loss",
            "B": "3.33%, profit",
            "C": "3.33%, loss",
            "D": "6.67%, profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6.67%, profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-135",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 135,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer professes to sell his goods at cost price but uses a false weight of 950 grams instead of 1 kilogram. His gain percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "4 $\\frac{5}{19}$ %",
            "B": "6 $\\frac{5}{19}$ %",
            "C": "5 $\\frac{5}{19}$ %",
            "D": "7 $\\frac{5}{19}$ %"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5 $\\frac{5}{19}$ %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-136",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 136,
        "question": "A trader sells pulses at a 32% profit and uses weights 20% less than the actual measure. Find his gain percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "65%",
            "B": "58%",
            "C": "72%",
            "D": "62%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "65%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-137",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 137,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer sells an article at a 10% loss on the cost price but uses a weight of 40 gm instead of 50 gm. What is his percentage of profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "12.5%",
            "B": "11.5%",
            "C": "10.0%",
            "D": "18.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-138",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 138,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer claims to sell his products at 24% loss on the cost price but uses 100 gm weight instead of 200 gm weight. His profit percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "52%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "48%",
            "D": "55%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "52%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-139",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 139,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells goods at 82% loss on cost price but uses 28% less weight. What is his percentage profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "54% loss",
            "B": "54% profit",
            "C": "75% profit",
            "D": "75% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "75% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-140",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 140,
        "question": "A shopkeeper purchased groundnuts at \u20b964/kg and sells at \u20b980/kg. While selling, he uses faulty weights and gives 800 gm instead of 1 kg. Find his actual profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "32.25%",
            "B": "28.75%",
            "C": "36.65%",
            "D": "56.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "56.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-141",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 141,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer professes to sell grains at cost price, but he uses a weight of 925 g for 1 kg weight. Find his gain percentage. (Approximate to two decimals.)",
        "options": {
            "A": "8.11",
            "B": "7.75",
            "C": "8.50",
            "D": "7.50"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "8.11",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-142",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 142,
        "question": "A dishonest shopkeeper sells goods to a customer at a profit of T % over the cost price and also weighs 800g instead of 1kg. His total profit percentage is 40%. What is the value of T?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40",
            "B": "24",
            "C": "10",
            "D": "12"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-143",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 143,
        "question": "A shopkeeper claims to sell 450 kg rice at a cost price of \u20b940/kg but uses a weight of 900 grams instead of a 1 kg weight. He makes a profit of \u20b92,520 by selling the remaining rice in the black market. The ratio of the black-market price to the original price per kg of rice is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "9 : 4",
            "B": "4 : 3",
            "C": "10 : 7",
            "D": "7 : 5"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "7 : 5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-144",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 144,
        "question": "A shopkeeper normally makes a profit of 20% in a certain transaction; he weighed 900 gm instead of 1 kg due to an error in the weighing machine. If he charges 15% less than what he normally charges, then what is his actual profit or loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18.33% Profit",
            "B": "13.33% Profit",
            "C": "13.33% Loss",
            "D": "18.00% Loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "13.33% Profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-145",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 145,
        "question": "Sohan sells sugar at cost price but he uses faulty weight and thus earns a profit of 28%. How many g (grams) of sugar is he giving in exchange of 3.2 kg of sugar?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1900",
            "B": "1500",
            "C": "2500",
            "D": "2200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "2500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-146",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 146,
        "question": "A dishonest shopkeeper sells rice at a cost price but makes a 25% profit by using faulty weights. He decides to give a discount to attract more customers. What percent of discount should he offer to make 10% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "9%",
            "B": "11%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-147",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 147,
        "question": "B purchased 15 kg apples at the rate of \u20b9180 per kg from a wholesaler who uses a weight of 950 grams for the kg weight. B sold all these apples at \u20b9180 per kg but used a weight of 750 grams for the kg weight. Find the percentage profit earned by B in the transaction (correct to 2 places of decimal).",
        "options": {
            "A": "25.75%",
            "B": "26.67%",
            "C": "22.55%",
            "D": "33.33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "26.67%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-148",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 148,
        "question": "The cost price of pulses is 12% less than the selling price. Using a faulty weighing machine, shopkeeper is able to earn 25% profit. How much percent of the faulty machine shows more weight as compared to the actual weight (Rounded off to the nearest integer)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "14%",
            "C": "13%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-149",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 149,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells sugar at \u20b940 per kg, which he purchased at \u20b936 per kg. His weighing machine is faulty and it weighs only 800 gm while selling. His percentage profit (correct to 2 decimal places) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "37.58%",
            "C": "38.89%",
            "D": "39.28%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "38.89%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-150",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 150,
        "question": "A dishonest shopkeeper professes to sell grains at the cost price, but he uses a weight of 920 gm for 1 kg weight. Find his gain percentage (round up to two decimal places).",
        "options": {
            "A": "7.90%",
            "B": "8.70%",
            "C": "8.50%",
            "D": "7.80%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "8.70%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-151",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 151,
        "question": "A tailor buys lining clothes from a wholesale merchant and cheats him by using a measurement tape which is 5 cm longer than the normal tape. The tailor offer the customer at cost price while stitching different garments and uses measurement tape which is 5 cm shorter than the normal tape. The gain percent is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "10 10/25 %",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "10 10/19 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "10 10/19 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-152",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 152,
        "question": "A man sells rice at 8% profit and uses weight 25% less than the actual measure. What is his percentage profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "44%",
            "B": "41%",
            "C": "23%",
            "D": "36%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "44%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-153",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 153,
        "question": "A shopkeeper does a faulty weighing of an item of 930 gram instead of 1 kg and sells it at its cost price. Find his profit percentage on selling 15 kg of the item.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8 79/93 %",
            "B": "5 20/93 %",
            "C": "7 49/93 %",
            "D": "6 19/93 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "7 49/93 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-154",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 154,
        "question": "A shopkeeper uses 940 gm weight in place of one kg weight. He sells it at 4% profit. What will be the actual profit percentage? (rounded off to two decimal places)",
        "options": {
            "A": "9.25%",
            "B": "10.32%",
            "C": "10.64%",
            "D": "10.96%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10.64%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-155",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 155,
        "question": "The cost price and selling price of rice are the same. Due to a faulty weighing machine, the seller earns a 15% profit. If \u20b9x is the cost price of 1000 gm rice and the machine is changed which shows 1000 gm instead of 950 gm, what should be the selling price (in \u20b9) now to get the same percentage of profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.0295x",
            "B": "1.0259x",
            "C": "1.0925x",
            "D": "1.0950x"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1.0925x",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-156",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 156,
        "question": "If a weighing machine shows 400 gm when the actual weight is 350 gm. The cost price of almonds is \u20b9880 per kg and packets of 200 gm are made using the faulty machine. What should be the selling price (in \u20b9) of each packet to get a profit of 25%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "197.50",
            "B": "175.50",
            "C": "182.50",
            "D": "192.50"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "192.50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-157",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 157,
        "question": "A dishonest dealer sells articles at 15% loss on cost price but uses the weight of 20 gm instead of 25 gm. What is his profit or loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6.25% Profit",
            "B": "6.50% Profit",
            "C": "7.55% Loss",
            "D": "5.25% Loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6.25% Profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-158",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 158,
        "question": "In a grocery shop, Samarth sold 950 g of sugar to a customer in place of 1 kg for \u20b954. The cost price of 1 kg sugar was \u20b936. How much profit (in \u20b9) did he earn on selling the sugar?",
        "options": {
            "A": "16.2",
            "B": "18.7",
            "C": "20.2",
            "D": "19.8"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "19.8",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-159",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 159,
        "question": "A businessman cheats by using faulty weights, to the tune of 12% each time, when buying and selling material. What is the rise in his profit percentage using faulty weights only?",
        "options": {
            "A": "22%",
            "B": "25.44%",
            "C": "24%",
            "D": "26.32%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25.44%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-160",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 160,
        "question": "A faulty weighing machine reads 1 kg when 900 gm is actually weighted on it. The shopkeeper marked the price of his goods by 10%, but unfortunately he was caught by the metrology department and then they ordered him to repair his weighing machine and gave punishment to sell the goods at 10% discount on cost price for a month. If each customer is now paying \u20b920 for 1 kg, then before the raid ____ amount they have paid for same quantity. (Rounded off to two places of decimal)",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b927.16",
            "B": "\u20b927.84",
            "C": "\u20b928.05",
            "D": "\u20b928.15"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b927.16",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T11-161",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XI (DISHONEST SHOPKEEPER)",
        "question_number": 161,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells his items using a faulty balance which measures 25% less. He then marks up his items 15% above the cost price. If he also gives a discount of 10% then find his net profit percentage on 1 kg items.",
        "options": {
            "A": "32%",
            "B": "41%",
            "C": "44%",
            "D": "38%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "38%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-162",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 162,
        "question": "A man bought an article and sold it at a gain of 10%. If he had bought the article at 20% less and sold it for \u20b91,000 more, he would have made a profit of 40%. The cost price of the article (in \u20b9) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "50,000",
            "B": "60,000",
            "C": "25,000",
            "D": "40,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "50,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-163",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 163,
        "question": "Anu fixes the selling price of an article at 25% above its cost of production. If the cost of production goes up by 20% and she raises the selling price by 10%, then her percentage profit is (correct to one decimal place):",
        "options": {
            "A": "16.4%",
            "B": "14.6%",
            "C": "13.8%",
            "D": "15.2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "14.6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-164",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 164,
        "question": "The profit gained on selling a certain product is 320% of the cost. If the cost increases by 10% but the selling price remains constant, then what percentage of the selling price is the profit (correct to one decimal place)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "70.2%",
            "B": "73.8%",
            "C": "75.7%",
            "D": "63.8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "73.8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-165",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 165,
        "question": "An article is sold at 10 percent loss. If its cost price is decreased by \u20b95 and selling price is increased by \u20b98, then profit of 10 percent is earned on it. What is the original selling price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b968.5",
            "B": "\u20b967.5",
            "C": "\u20b962.5",
            "D": "\u20b960.75"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b960.75",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-166",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 166,
        "question": "A trader sells an article at 20 percent profit. If he buys it at half of the cost price and sells at the same selling price as before, then what will be the profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "240%",
            "B": "40%",
            "C": "140%",
            "D": "60%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "140%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-167",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 167,
        "question": "A man earns a profit of 20 percent by selling a calculator for a certain price. If he sells that calculator at double the price, then what will be the profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "140%",
            "B": "160%",
            "C": "60%",
            "D": "120%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "140%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-168",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 168,
        "question": "The initial profit percentage on the sale of an item was 55%. If the cost price of the item went up by 24% but the selling price remained the same, what would be the new profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "36%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "28%",
            "D": "33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-169",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 169,
        "question": "An article is sold at 25 percent loss. If its cost price is doubled and selling price is increased by \u20b9660, then there is a profit of 20 percent. What is the original cost price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9360",
            "B": "\u20b9500",
            "C": "\u20b9480",
            "D": "\u20b9400"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-170",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 170,
        "question": "A person sells an article for a loss of 18 percent. If he increases the selling price by \u20b9144 and decreases the cost price by 30 percent, then there is profit of 20 percent. What is the original selling price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96036",
            "B": "\u20b95904",
            "C": "\u20b96124",
            "D": "\u20b95068"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b95904",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-171",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 171,
        "question": "An article is sold at a certain price. If it is sold at 70% of this price, then there is a loss of 10%. What is the percentage profit, when it is sold at the original selling price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "200/7 %",
            "B": "300/7 %",
            "C": "50/7 %",
            "D": "100/7 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "200/7 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-172",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 172,
        "question": "An article is sold at a profit of 25%. If both the cost price and the selling price of the article are increased by \u20b9200, then the profit percentage is 20%. What is the original cost price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9750",
            "B": "\u20b9900",
            "C": "\u20b9800",
            "D": "\u20b9840"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b9800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T12-173",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XII (CHAR MINAR CONCEPT)",
        "question_number": 173,
        "question": "A person sold an article at a loss of 16%. Had he sold it for \u20b9660 more, he would have gained 8%. What should be the selling price (in \u20b9) to gain a profit of 12%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "3,080",
            "B": "3,200",
            "C": "2,750",
            "D": "2,970"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "3,080",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-174",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 174,
        "question": "A merchant has 1000 kg of sugar, part of which he sells at a 10% profit and the rest at a 40% profit. He gains 20% on the whole. The quantity sold at 40% profit is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "543 1/3 kg",
            "B": "383 1/3 kg",
            "C": "333 1/3 kg",
            "D": "443 1/3 kg"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "333 1/3 kg",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-175",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 175,
        "question": "Ramendra purchased some watermelons for \u20b91,500. He sold one-fourth of them at a loss of 12%. At what gain percentage should the remaining watermelons be sold so as to gain 25% on the whole transaction (correct up to two decimal places)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "37.33%",
            "B": "33.73%",
            "C": "37.65%",
            "D": "33.43%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "37.33%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-176",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 176,
        "question": "The cost price of two articles is equal. One article is sold at a profit of 12% and the other article for \u20b93,600 more than the first. If the net profit is 15 27/51 %, then what is the cost price of each article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b950,000",
            "B": "\u20b951,000",
            "C": "\u20b950,990",
            "D": "\u20b952,150"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b951,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-177",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 177,
        "question": "Reyan purchased a laptop for \u20b956,000 and a scanner-cum-printer for \u20b922,000. He sold the laptop for a 20% profit and the scanner-cum-printer for a 15% profit. What is his profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18 21/37 %",
            "B": "18 23/39 %",
            "C": "12 23/39 %",
            "D": "12 21/37 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "18 23/39 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-178",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 178,
        "question": "Arvind has 650 kg of wheat. A part of which he sells at 9% profit and the rest at 19% profit to get 15% profit on the whole. What is the quantity (in kg) of wheat sold by Arvind at 9% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "260 kg",
            "B": "390 kg",
            "C": "195 kg",
            "D": "455 kg"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "260 kg",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-179",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 179,
        "question": "A medical store owner purchased medicines worth \u20b918,000 from a company. He sold 2/5 part of the medicine at a 35% loss. On which gain, he should sell the rest of the medicines so that he has neither gain nor loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "23 1/3 %",
            "B": "20 2/3 %",
            "C": "23 2/3 %",
            "D": "20 1/3 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "23 1/3 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T13-180",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIII (BASED ON ALLIGATION)",
        "question_number": 180,
        "question": "Shivam purchased two watches, first for \u20b9 12000 and the second for \u20b9 10000. He sold both the watches, first one at the profit of 10% and the second at a loss of 10%. What is the overall profit or loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.25 percent profit",
            "B": "2.25 percent loss",
            "C": "0.909 percent profit",
            "D": "0.909 percent loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "0.909 percent profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-181",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 181,
        "question": "Ram purchases two watches for \u20b93500. By selling one watch at a profit of 25% and the other at a loss of 10% he neither earns profit nor suffers loss in whole transaction. What is the cost price of each watch?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91500 and \u20b92000",
            "B": "\u20b91500 and \u20b91720",
            "C": "\u20b91800 and \u20b91700",
            "D": "\u20b91250 and \u20b92250"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91800 and \u20b91700",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-182",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 182,
        "question": "A shopkeeper earns 10% on an investment but loses 20% on another investment. If the ratio of two investments is 2:3, then the combined percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "5.5%",
            "B": "7%",
            "C": "8%",
            "D": "6%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-183",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 183,
        "question": "A shopkeeper has 220 kg of rice. A part of the rice is sold at 12% loss and the rest at 18% gain. He gains 18% on the whole. Find quantity sold at 12% profit/loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "555",
            "B": "1210",
            "C": "165",
            "D": "425"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "555",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-184",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 184,
        "question": "Ramesh purchases a table and chair for \u20b93900. He sells the table at a profit of 8% and chair at a profit of 16%. He earns profit of \u20b9540. Find difference between CP of table and chair.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92000",
            "B": "\u20b91900",
            "C": "\u20b91800",
            "D": "\u20b91700"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-185",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 185,
        "question": "A bought a bag and bottle at profit of 12% and 20%. Total profit \u20b9160.80. Find cost of bottle.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9320",
            "B": "\u20b9300",
            "C": "\u20b9280",
            "D": "\u20b9240"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9240",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-186",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 186,
        "question": "A trader bought 640 kg rice. He sold part at 20% profit and remaining at 5% loss. Total profit 15%. Find ratio of quantities sold.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1:3",
            "B": "4:1",
            "C": "1:4",
            "D": "3:1"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1:4",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-187",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 187,
        "question": "Suresh bought tables and chairs for \u20b912000. He sold tables at profit of 15% and chairs at loss of 10%. Total gain \u20b9300. Find cost of tables.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96000",
            "B": "\u20b95000",
            "C": "\u20b94500",
            "D": "\u20b94800"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b96000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-188",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV (Based on Expenditure)",
        "question_number": 188,
        "question": "A person buys 5 tables and 9 chairs for \u20b915400. He sells tables at 10% profit and chairs at 20% profit. Total profit \u20b92800. Find cost of 3 chairs.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91890",
            "B": "\u20b91740",
            "C": "\u20b91800",
            "D": "\u20b91860"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-189",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 189,
        "question": "By selling 90 balls for \u20b960 a person loses 20%. How many balls must be sold for \u20b996 to gain 20%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "36",
            "B": "37",
            "C": "46",
            "D": "47"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "36",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-190",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 190,
        "question": "A person bought apples at \u20b93 each. At what price must he sell to gain 10%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b956",
            "B": "\u20b957",
            "C": "\u20b958",
            "D": "\u20b959"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b957",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-191",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 191,
        "question": "By selling 30 dozen eggs for \u20b9405, trader loses 25%. How many eggs must be sold for \u20b9288 to gain 20%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "16",
            "B": "15",
            "C": "18",
            "D": "12"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "16",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-192",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 192,
        "question": "By selling 32 oranges for \u20b91, person loses 40%. How many for \u20b91 to gain 20%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "12",
            "B": "16",
            "C": "20",
            "D": "24"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "16",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-193",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 193,
        "question": "After selling 4 articles for \u20b91, seller loses 4%. How many for \u20b91 to gain 15%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "24",
            "B": "28",
            "C": "32",
            "D": "36"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "28",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-194",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 194,
        "question": "By selling 70 articles for \u20b960, person loses 20%. How many for \u20b996 to gain 20%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "24",
            "B": "28",
            "C": "36",
            "D": "40"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "28",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T14-195",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XIV",
        "question_number": 195,
        "question": "By selling 18 tables for \u20b91664, seller loses 10%. How many for \u20b91742 to gain 10%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "23",
            "B": "18",
            "C": "20",
            "D": "22"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-196",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous)",
        "question_number": 196,
        "question": "A sells article to B at 33% profit and B sells to C at 20% loss. If C paid \u20b9532, find price paid by A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9400",
            "B": "\u20b9600",
            "C": "\u20b9700",
            "D": "\u20b9800"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-197",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV",
        "question_number": 197,
        "question": "A sells object to B at 10% profit and B sells to C at 60% profit. Find CP of A if C paid \u20b929.40.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b930",
            "B": "\u20b932",
            "C": "\u20b928",
            "D": "\u20b934"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b930",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-198",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV",
        "question_number": 198,
        "question": "A sells bike to B at 45% profit. B sells to C at 30% profit. C paid \u20b943,355. Find CP of A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b929,000",
            "B": "\u20b923,000",
            "C": "\u20b927,000",
            "D": "\u20b921,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b923,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-199",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV",
        "question_number": 199,
        "question": "P sells laptop to Q at loss of 25% and Q sells to R at profit of 20%. R paid \u20b922500. Find CP of laptop for P.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b925000",
            "B": "\u20b924800",
            "C": "\u20b923200",
            "D": "\u20b923800"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b925000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-200",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV",
        "question_number": 200,
        "question": "Advait sells study table to Aadarth at 25% profit. Aadarth sells at loss. Find CP of study table for Advait.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92100",
            "B": "\u20b92000",
            "C": "\u20b91900",
            "D": "\u20b91800"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91900",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-201",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 201,
        "question": "Akash sold a motorcycle to Navin at a profit of 10%. Navin sold it to Vinay at a profit of 20%. Vinay sold it to Vishal at a loss of 5%. If Vishal paid \u20b962,700 for the motorcycle, then what was the cost of the motorcycle for Akash?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b948,000",
            "B": "\u20b949,000",
            "C": "\u20b947,000",
            "D": "\u20b950,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b950,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-202",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 202,
        "question": "A sold an article to B at 25% profit and B further sold it to C by earning a certain profit. If the cost price of C is 30% more than the cost price of A, then find the profit percentage earned by B.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5\u00bd%",
            "B": "4%",
            "C": "5%",
            "D": "4\u00bd%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-203",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 203,
        "question": "A tea seller used to make 50% profit by selling tea at \u20b99 per cup. When the cost of ingredients increased by 25%, he started selling tea at \u20b910 per cup. What is his profit percentage now?",
        "options": {
            "A": "33\u2154%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "33\u2153%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "33\u2153%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-204",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 204,
        "question": "Aditya buys 300 mangoes for \u20b91,100. Some mangoes he sells and throws away some. He sells remaining mangoes at \u20b95 each and makes a profit of \u20b9150. Find percentage of mangoes thrown away.",
        "options": {
            "A": "16\u2154%",
            "B": "15\u2153%",
            "C": "16\u2154%",
            "D": "15\u2153%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "16\u2154%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-205",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 205,
        "question": "The cost of manufacturing an item was \u20b924,000 and 20% of it was spent on packaging and shipment to retailer. The manufacturer made a profit of 50%, while retailer incurred a loss of 20% on selling it to customer. At what price was the item sold by the retailer?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b935,268",
            "B": "\u20b934,560",
            "C": "\u20b937,664",
            "D": "\u20b932,400"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b934,560",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-206",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 206,
        "question": "A company buys raw materials for \u20b910,000 and manufacturing costs additional \u20b95,000. Product is sold to distributor at \u20b925,000, who marks it up by 20% and sells to retailer. Retailer marks up another 25% and sells to end customer. What is overall percentage profit made by company, distributor and retailer combined?",
        "options": {
            "A": "135%",
            "B": "125%",
            "C": "150%",
            "D": "150%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "150%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-207",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 207,
        "question": "Sukhen purchased 50 perishable items and sold half of them at loss and rest at profit of 19%. Overall profit was 19%. At what percentage above cost price did he sell items which did not go bad?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "42%",
            "C": "34%",
            "D": "36%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "40%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-208",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 208,
        "question": "Cost prices of two articles A and B are in ratio 4:5. Selling prices are such that shopkeeper gains 10% on A and loses 20% on B. Difference between cost prices is \u20b9450. Find difference between selling prices.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9250",
            "B": "\u20b9300",
            "C": "\u20b9400",
            "D": "\u20b9350"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9300",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-209",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 209,
        "question": "A costs three times as much as B and is sold at loss of 10%, while B is sold at gain of 20%. If selling price of A is \u20b95,800 more than selling price of B, find cost price of A.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b94,000",
            "B": "\u20b912,000",
            "C": "\u20b915,000",
            "D": "\u20b99,600"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b912,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-210",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 210,
        "question": "The cost prices of two articles A and B are in ratio 4:5. While selling these articles, shopkeeper gains 10% on A and 20% on B. Difference in selling prices is \u20b9480. Find 30% of total cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1,000",
            "B": "900",
            "C": "810",
            "D": "1,250"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "810",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-211",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 211,
        "question": "A wrist watch is sold for \u20b91,200 at a profit percent equal to its cost price. Find the cost price of the wrist watch.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9400",
            "B": "\u20b9250",
            "C": "\u20b9350",
            "D": "\u20b9300"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9300",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-212",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 212,
        "question": "By selling an article for \u20b9131.25, a trader gains as much as the number representing the cost price. At what price should he sell to earn 40% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "100",
            "B": "140",
            "C": "175",
            "D": "150"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "175",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-213",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 213,
        "question": "Madhav purchased an item for \u20b942,000 and sold it at a loss of 20%. With that amount, he purchased another item and sold it at a gain of 30%. What is the overall gain?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6720",
            "B": "4200",
            "C": "2520",
            "D": "3360"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "2520",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-214",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 214,
        "question": "If a shopkeeper sells sugar at \u20b948.8 per kg, he is able to make 12% profit. Due to water seepage, 1/5 of the sugar is damaged. What should now be the selling price per kg of the rest to have 5% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b949.5",
            "B": "\u20b952.5",
            "C": "\u20b948.5",
            "D": "\u20b951.5"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b952.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-215",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 215,
        "question": "An article passing through two hands is sold at total profit of 40% of original cost price. First dealer makes profit of 30%. Find percentage profit made by second dealer.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6 6/13 %",
            "B": "6 3/13 %",
            "C": "7 1/13 %",
            "D": "7 9/13 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "7 9/13 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-216",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 216,
        "question": "Ramu fixes selling price 16% above cost price. He sells goods at 12% less than fixed price. Find actual profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.07%",
            "B": "2.08%",
            "C": "0.08%",
            "D": "3.01%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2.08%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-217",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 217,
        "question": "Aarav owns a watch worth \u20b910,000. He sells it to Bhavin at 15% profit. Bhavin sells it back to Aarav at 15% loss. Find Aarav\u2019s net profit or loss.",
        "options": {
            "A": "17.25% Loss",
            "B": "17.25% Profit",
            "C": "18.25% Profit",
            "D": "18.75% Loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "17.25% Profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-218",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 218,
        "question": "Reduction of 7.5% in cost price allows purchase of 15 kg more for same amount. If original price was \u20b974,000, find new price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "54",
            "B": "53",
            "C": "52",
            "D": "51"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "53",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-219",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 219,
        "question": "Price of item increased by 15% and then decreased by 12%. Find effective percentage change.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.2% increase",
            "B": "3% increase",
            "C": "1.8% increase",
            "D": "1.8% decrease"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1.8% increase",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-220",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 220,
        "question": "Dealer buys article for \u20b9250 and gets successive discounts of 12% and 10%. He spends 10% on transport. At what price should he sell to earn 25% profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9274.10",
            "B": "\u20b9254.10",
            "C": "\u20b9244.10",
            "D": "\u20b9264.10"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9254.10",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-221",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 221,
        "question": "First shirt sold at 8% profit and second shirt sold at 3% loss. Find overall profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4.60%",
            "B": "4.07%",
            "C": "3.86%",
            "D": "4.86%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4.07%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-222",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 222,
        "question": "Sukhvir purchased items and sold part at loss and rest at profit. Overall profit was 19%. Find selling price percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "49%",
            "B": "63%",
            "C": "70%",
            "D": "75%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "63%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-223",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 223,
        "question": "Aditya sold article X at profit of 23% and article Y at loss of 13%. Overall profit \u20b9180. Find cost price of Y.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2007",
            "B": "2050",
            "C": "2100",
            "D": "2020"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "2007",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-224",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 224,
        "question": "Vendor marked price \u20b95760. Sold at 12% profit after reducing price. Find new selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4570",
            "B": "4608",
            "C": "4810",
            "D": "4704"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "4704",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-225",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 225,
        "question": "Ankita sold items at various profit/loss. Find total profit or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "15.25% profit",
            "B": "18.75% loss",
            "C": "18.75% profit",
            "D": "15.25% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "18.75% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-226",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 226,
        "question": "Selling price \u20b916,800 gives profit of 20%. Find selling price to gain 20% if production cost increased by 20%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b918,160",
            "B": "\u20b918,480",
            "C": "\u20b920,160",
            "D": "\u20b920,480"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b920,160",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-227",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 227,
        "question": "A man buys item at \u20b9320/kg and sells at \u20b96 per 25 grams. Find profit/loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20% loss",
            "B": "25% loss",
            "C": "25% profit",
            "D": "20% profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-228",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 228,
        "question": "Market price \u20b915,750 equals 50% above cost price. Discount 40%. Find profit/loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit 20%",
            "B": "Loss 10%",
            "C": "Loss 20%",
            "D": "Profit 10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss 10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-229",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 229,
        "question": "Person bought boxes of grapes. After loss and transport charges, find overall gain.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Gain \u20b92050",
            "B": "Loss \u20b91000",
            "C": "Gain \u20b92750",
            "D": "Loss \u20b91500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Gain \u20b92750",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T15-230",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 230,
        "question": "Fruit seller buys bananas and throws some away. He sells remaining bananas and makes \u20b9396 profit. Find percentage thrown away.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6%",
            "B": "4.5%",
            "C": "5%",
            "D": "4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-231",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 231,
        "question": "The marked price of mustard oil is 25% more than its cost price. At what percentage less than the marked price should it be sold to have no profit and no loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "18%",
            "D": "22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-232",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 232,
        "question": "If the selling price of an article is doubled, then the profit becomes four times. What was the original profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "75%",
            "B": "100%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "100%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-233",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 233,
        "question": "A shopkeeper purchases six small cold drink bottles for \u20b9100. For how much should he sell one such bottle to get a profit of 20%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b922",
            "B": "\u20b923",
            "C": "\u20b920",
            "D": "\u20b921"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b923",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-234",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 234,
        "question": "Ram bought a cell phone and paid 30% less than its original price and sold it at 50% profit on the price he paid. What percent profit did he earn on the original price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-235",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 235,
        "question": "A shopkeeper incurs a loss of cost price of 4 pens while selling 20 pens at \u20b910 each. If he had purchased 20 pens at 10% less price and sold 20 pens at 25% more than the selling price, find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "8%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "11.1%",
            "D": "12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-236",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 236,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought articles A and B for \u20b92540. He sold A at 15% gain and B at 25% loss. Selling price of A was \u20b9170 more than B. Find overall profit or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Loss, 8.3%",
            "B": "Profit, 8.3%",
            "C": "Profit, 9.5%",
            "D": "Loss, 9.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Loss, 8.3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-237",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 237,
        "question": "Cost price of two articles A and B is same. A sold at 24% loss and B sold at profit of \u20b9270. If net profit is 12%, find selling price of B.",
        "options": {
            "A": "645",
            "B": "575",
            "C": "705",
            "D": "610"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "575",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-238",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 238,
        "question": "2/5 of marked price equals 5/8 of selling price. What is the discount percent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "40%",
            "B": "42%",
            "C": "36%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "36%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-239",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 239,
        "question": "Cost price of 15 bananas is \u20b930. After selling 15 bananas at \u20b912 per dozen and remaining at \u20b95 per dozen, find loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "22.5%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "37.5%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "37.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-240",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 240,
        "question": "Ritika purchased 8 kg wheat at \u20b930/kg and sold at \u20b945/kg and remaining at \u20b945/kg. Find quantity sold at \u20b945/kg.",
        "options": {
            "A": "18 kg",
            "B": "16 kg",
            "C": "10 kg",
            "D": "14 kg"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "10 kg",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-241",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 241,
        "question": "A man buys machine at \u20b95000, sells at \u20b96000, buys again at \u20b98000 sells at \u20b910000. Find profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20.23%",
            "B": "23.08%",
            "C": "18.75%",
            "D": "15.23%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "23.08%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-242",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 242,
        "question": "A producer passes goods through 3 traders each marking profit. Find producer profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9330.55",
            "B": "\u20b9136.55",
            "C": "\u20b9240.55",
            "D": "\u20b9137.55"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9136.55",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-243",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 243,
        "question": "Article passes through 3 hands with profit 20% and 25%. Find overall profit.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "12.5%",
            "C": "16%",
            "D": "8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-244",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 244,
        "question": "Microwave oven bought and sold between cities with discounts and profit. Find profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "6305.8",
            "B": "6258.8",
            "C": "6285.7",
            "D": "6527.9"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "6285.7",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-245",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 245,
        "question": "What will be the actual profit percent when loss of 45% at certain SP?",
        "options": {
            "A": "17%",
            "B": "37%",
            "C": "47%",
            "D": "27%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "47%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-246",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 246,
        "question": "Shopkeeper increases SP by 15%. Profit increases from 5% to 15%. Find increase in CP.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-247",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 247,
        "question": "P buys article \u20b9280 sells to Q at profit 25%. Q sells to R and R sells at profit 40%. Find Q profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "32%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "26%",
            "D": "14%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "14%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-248",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 248,
        "question": "Harsh purchased scooter \u20b948000 loss 15% then profit 22.5%. Find overall profit/loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit 4.125%",
            "B": "Profit 2.25%",
            "C": "Loss 4.125%",
            "D": "Loss 2.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Profit 4.125%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-249",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 249,
        "question": "Sugar purchased at different rates mixed and sold \u20b952.5/kg. Find profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5%",
            "B": "7.25%",
            "C": "4.25%",
            "D": "6.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-250",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 250,
        "question": "CP of X and Y same. X sold 20% profit and Y sold \u20b9126 less. Net profit 14%. Find CP.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1260",
            "B": "840",
            "C": "1050",
            "D": "1080"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1050",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-251",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 251,
        "question": "Article sold at 33\u2153% of SP gives 33\u2153% loss. Find profit when sold at 60%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "33\u2153%",
            "B": "17\u2153%",
            "C": "30%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-252",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 252,
        "question": "Man sells goods with 20% profit. Cost increases 10% and SP increases 8%. Find new profit percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21.8%",
            "B": "23.4%",
            "C": "21.4%",
            "D": "22.7%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "22.7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "PL-T0-253",
        "chapter": "Profit and Loss",
        "type": "Type-XV (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 253,
        "question": "Marked price \u20b9315 sold \u20b9288 loss 4%. Find markup percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "5%",
            "B": "8%",
            "C": "6\u00bd%",
            "D": "5\u00bd%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-01",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 1,
        "question": "In a clearance sale, a sari whose marked price was \u20b910,490 is now sold for \u20b99,441. What is the discount percentage on the sari?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "18%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-02",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 2,
        "question": "In a store, an item with marked price of \u20b982,500 is available at a discounted price of \u20b979,200. What is the percentage of discount given on that item?",
        "options": {
            "A": "4%",
            "B": "3%",
            "C": "1%",
            "D": "2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-03",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 3,
        "question": "A coat marked at Rs. 145 is offered at Rs. 127.6. The rate of retail discount offered is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "11%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "10%",
            "D": "13%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-04",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 4,
        "question": "The marked price of a table lamp is Rs. 2,165. During the festive season, it is sold for Rs. 1,710.35. Find the percentage discount offered.",
        "options": {
            "A": "21%",
            "B": "20.5%",
            "C": "18%",
            "D": "22.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "21%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-05",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 5,
        "question": "A merchant advertise 10% off on the items bought from his store. Find the discount got by a customer who bought a bag worth \u20b9560, an exercise book worth \u20b990 and a pen worth \u20b945.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b959",
            "B": "\u20b969.50",
            "C": "\u20b965",
            "D": "\u20b967.50"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b969.50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-06",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 6,
        "question": "The marked price of an electronic watch in a store is Rs. 15,620 and it is available at a discount of 27%. What is the price (in Rs., to the nearest tens) that a customer pays if he buys from the store?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b912,500",
            "B": "\u20b911,400",
            "C": "\u20b99,880",
            "D": "\u20b910,880"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b911,400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-07",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 7,
        "question": "The marked price of an immersion rod in an electronic store is \u20b9900. The store offers a discount of 12% on its sale. At what price (in \u20b9) can a customer buy it from the electronic store?",
        "options": {
            "A": "787",
            "B": "792",
            "C": "782",
            "D": "797"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "792",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-08",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 8,
        "question": "At a clearance sale, a shopkeeper gives 45% discount. If a customer paid \u20b9330 during the sale, then what is the marked price of that shirt?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9550",
            "B": "\u20b9600",
            "C": "\u20b9500",
            "D": "\u20b9650"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-09",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 9,
        "question": "If the selling price of an article is \u20b91,792 after a 20% discount, then the marked price of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,140",
            "B": "\u20b92,240",
            "C": "\u20b92,160",
            "D": "\u20b92,260"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b92,240",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-10",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 10,
        "question": "A shopkeeper announced 17% rebate on the marked price of an article. If the selling price of the article is \u20b91,245, then the marked price (in \u20b9) of the article is :",
        "options": {
            "A": "1500",
            "B": "1820",
            "C": "1780",
            "D": "1600"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-11",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 11,
        "question": "The marked price of one pen is \u20b9x. The selling price of one packet of x pens, after a discount of 15%, is \u20b91,360. What is the value of 'x'?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20",
            "B": "40",
            "C": "30",
            "D": "45"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-12",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 12,
        "question": "The MP of an article was Rs. 180 and it was sold at a discount of 15%, the discount in Rs. is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "12",
            "B": "15",
            "C": "27",
            "D": "18"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "27",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-13",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 13,
        "question": "On the occasion of Republic Day, a retail store offers a scheme where customers can avail a discount of 26% on their total purchase. If Manish buys items worth Rs. 2,050, how much money (in) will he save through the scheme discount?",
        "options": {
            "A": "533",
            "B": "544",
            "C": "522",
            "D": "511"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "533",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-14",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 14,
        "question": "A shopkeeper has announced a 25% rebate on the prices of stationery items. If anyone needs to have a rebate of \u20b940, then how many stationery items costing \u20b932 should be purchased?",
        "options": {
            "A": "5 items",
            "B": "6 items",
            "C": "4 items",
            "D": "3 items"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "5 items",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-15",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 15,
        "question": "Lakshita purchased a sofa set at discount of 25%. As per her calculations, she noticed that if she would have not been given this discount, she would have paid \u20b922,400 more as the cost of this sofa set. How much did Lakshita pay for the sofa set?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b922,400",
            "B": "\u20b933,600",
            "C": "\u20b967,200",
            "D": "\u20b967,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b967,200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T01-16",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-I (Basic Questions)",
        "question_number": 16,
        "question": "A seller marks up his goods at 40% over the cost price. If the difference between the profits if he allows a 15% discount on the marked price and if he allows a discount of 20% on the marked price is \u20b994.85, find the cost price (in \u20b9).",
        "options": {
            "A": "1295",
            "B": "1326",
            "C": "1355",
            "D": "1254"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1355",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T02-17",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-II (Buy X Get Y Free)",
        "question_number": 17,
        "question": "Murlidhar, the owner of a grocery store, offers a discount scheme 'buy 5 water bottles get 1 for free' to his customers. What is the effective percentage discount offered by Murlidhar? (correct up to two decimal places)",
        "options": {
            "A": "13.67%",
            "B": "20.00%",
            "C": "13.33%",
            "D": "16.67%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "16.67%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T02-18",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-II (Buy X Get Y Free)",
        "question_number": 18,
        "question": "During a new-year sale, a shopkeeper offers a discount scheme to his customers, 'Buy 5 Sweaters, Get 2 Sweaters Free'. Find the effective percentage discount given by the shopkeeper.",
        "options": {
            "A": "28 4/7%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "22 2/9%",
            "D": "21%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "28 4/7%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T02-19",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-II (Buy X Get Y Free)",
        "question_number": 19,
        "question": "On buying 24 bangles Meena gets 6 bangles free of cost. By what percentage does Meena get a discount?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T02-20",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-II (Buy X Get Y Free)",
        "question_number": 20,
        "question": "To clear the old stock, Arshad offers a discount scheme to his customers - on buying 24 glass tumblers get 12 glass tumblers free. What is the effective percentage discount given by Arshad to his customers?",
        "options": {
            "A": "32 2/3%",
            "B": "30 1/3%",
            "C": "34 2/3%",
            "D": "33 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "33 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T02-22",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-II (Buy X Get Y Free)",
        "question_number": 22,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers the following two discount schemes. A. Buy 3 get 4 free B. Buy 5 get 6 free. Which scheme has the maximum discount percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "A",
            "B": "A does not give any discount",
            "C": "A and B both have the same discount percentage",
            "D": "B"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-23",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 23,
        "question": "Two successive discounts of 40% and 30% are equal to a single discount of:",
        "options": {
            "A": "70%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "58%",
            "D": "60%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "58%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-24",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 24,
        "question": "A single discount equivalent to two successive discount of 20% and 10% on the marked price of an article is?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18%",
            "B": "28%",
            "C": "24%",
            "D": "22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "28%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-25",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 25,
        "question": "If the successive discount of 10%, 15%, then the single equivalent rate of discount is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "32.3%",
            "B": "24.2%",
            "C": "43.4%",
            "D": "23.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "23.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-26",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 26,
        "question": "A discount series of 10% and 16% on an invoice is the same as a single discount of:",
        "options": {
            "A": "24.4%",
            "B": "22.4%",
            "C": "21.4%",
            "D": "23.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "24.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-27",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 27,
        "question": "A shopkeeper allows 40% discount on his goods. He further gives 20% discount. What is the single discount equivalent to these two successive discounts?",
        "options": {
            "A": "62%",
            "B": "52%",
            "C": "60%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "52%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-28",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 28,
        "question": "A person first increases the price of a commodity by 8% and then he announces a discount of 18%. The actual discount (in %) on the original price is?",
        "options": {
            "A": "11.44",
            "B": "14.44",
            "C": "9.44",
            "D": "8.44"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "11.44",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-29",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 29,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b950,000. From three shopkeepers, the first one allows two successive discounts of 25% and 15%. The second one allows two successive discounts 20% and 20%. The third shopkeeper allows two successive discounts of 30% and 10%. From which shopkeeper does the customer get more profit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "First",
            "B": "Same for all the shopkeepers",
            "C": "Third",
            "D": "Second"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Third",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-30",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 30,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers the following discount schemes for buyers on an article: I. Two successive discounts of 15% each II. A discount of 25% followed by a discount of 5% III. Two successive discounts of 20% and 10% IV. A discount of 30%. Under which scheme will the selling price be maximum?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Scheme IV",
            "B": "Scheme III",
            "C": "Scheme II",
            "D": "Scheme I"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Scheme I",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-31",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 31,
        "question": "A trader offers the following discount schemes on the purchase of a refrigerator. (i) A discount of 10% followed by a discount of 8% (ii) Successive discounts of 12% and 10% (iii) Two successive discounts of 12% (iv) A discount of 20%. In which scheme is the selling price the lowest?",
        "options": {
            "A": "(iv)",
            "B": "(i)",
            "C": "(ii)",
            "D": "(iii)"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "(iii)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-32",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 32,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers the following discount schemes for buyers. I. Two successive discounts of 15% and 20% II. successive discount of 25% and 10% III. A discount of 33%. The selling price will be minimum under the scheme:",
        "options": {
            "A": "I",
            "B": "I or II",
            "C": "III",
            "D": "II"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "III",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-33",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 33,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers 3 schemes of discounts to his customers. Which of the following schemes will fetch the minimum discount percentage? (A) Two successive discounts of 24% and 27%. (B) Buy 5 get three free. (C) Buy 6 and get 10.",
        "options": {
            "A": "A",
            "B": "C",
            "C": "Both A and C",
            "D": "B"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-34",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 34,
        "question": "Which of the following schemes will yield maximum discount on purchase of \u20b9x? (1) 2 successive discounts of 25% and 15% (2) Single discount of 20% (3) 2 free on purchase of 3 items (4) 3 free on purchase of 7 items",
        "options": {
            "A": "Scheme 2",
            "B": "Scheme 3",
            "C": "Scheme 4",
            "D": "Scheme 1"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Scheme 3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-35",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 35,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers the following discount schemes for the purchase of his goods. Find the schemes which has the maximum discount. (i) Two successive discounts of 20% and 10% (ii) Discount of 10% (iii) Buy 8 and get 4 free (iv) Buy 9 and get 6 free",
        "options": {
            "A": "(iii)",
            "B": "(ii)",
            "C": "(i)",
            "D": "(iv)"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "(iv)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-36",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 36,
        "question": "A shopping mart offers four different discounts schemes on the sale of an object as follows: (1) A discount of 30% (2) Two successive discounts of 15% (3) Buy 2, get 1 free (4) Buy 5, get 3 free. Which discount scheme offers the maximum discount to a customer?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1",
            "B": "4",
            "C": "2",
            "D": "3"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-37",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 37,
        "question": "Kamlesh offers the following two discount schemes to his customers on the sale of an article: (i) Two successive discounts of 25% and 5% (ii) Two successive discounts of 20% and 10%. What is the difference between the selling price (Rs. in) of the article under these two discount schemes if its marked price is Rs. 1,000?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6.5",
            "B": "8.0",
            "C": "7.5",
            "D": "7.0"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "7.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-38",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 38,
        "question": "Marked price of an article is \u20b928000. It can be sold at one of the following ways: Way A : A single discount of 24 percent. Way B : Two successive discounts of 16 percent and 10 percent. Which way will have lowest selling price and what will be the value of it?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Way B, \u20b921168",
            "B": "Way B, \u20b921280",
            "C": "Way A, \u20b921168",
            "D": "Way A, \u20b921280"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Way B, \u20b921168",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-39",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 39,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers the following two discount schemes on the sale a watch having marked price \u20b93,600. (1) Two successive discounts of 15%. (2) A discount of 10% followed by a discount of 20%. What is the difference between the selling price of the watch in case (1) and case (2)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b911",
            "B": "\u20b99",
            "C": "\u20b98",
            "D": "\u20b910"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b99",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-40",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 40,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers three schemes as given below to sell a particular type of product. Which of the following schemes offer(s) the maximum discount percentage? A. Buy 6, get 4 free B. Buy 5, get 5 free C. Two successive discounts of 18% and 24%",
        "options": {
            "A": "Only B",
            "B": "Only B and C",
            "C": "Only A and C",
            "D": "Only A"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Only B",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-41",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 41,
        "question": "A retailer offers the following discount schemes for buyers on an item. (i) Two successive discount of 20%. (ii) A discount of 25% followed by a discount of 15%. (iii) A discount of 40%. Under which scheme will the selling price be minimum?",
        "options": {
            "A": "(i) and (ii)",
            "B": "(iii)",
            "C": "(ii)",
            "D": "(i)"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "(iii)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-42",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 42,
        "question": "The company offers the following four types of successive discounts on a computer which is listed at \u20b9 6000. (i) 25% and 15% (ii) 30% and 10% (iii) 35% and 5% (iv) 20% and 20% Which of these offers is best for a customer?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Fourth offer",
            "B": "First offer",
            "C": "Third offer",
            "D": "Second offer"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Third offer",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-43",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 43,
        "question": "A trader offers to sell a commodity under any of the two schemes mentioned below: Scheme 1: The trader offers two successive discounts of 20% and 12.5% on the sale of each unit. Scheme 2: The trader offers the buyer an option to 'pay for y units, get z units free'. The buyer realizes that if he needs to buy (y+z) units, it does not matter to him which of the two schemes he opts for. Which of the following options gives a correct ordered pair of (y, z)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "(3, 7)",
            "B": "(7, 10)",
            "C": "(10, 7)",
            "D": "(7, 3)"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "(7, 3)",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-44",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 44,
        "question": "If, on a marked price, the difference between selling prices with a discount of 65% and with two successive discounts of 30% and 40% is \u20b9 105, then the marked price (in \u20b9) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 1,650",
            "B": "Rs. 1,050",
            "C": "Rs. 1,500",
            "D": "Rs. 1,320"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Rs. 1,500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T03-45",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-III (Equivalent Discount of Two Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 45,
        "question": "The difference between a discount of 25% and two successive discounts of 15% and 20% on a certain bill was Rs. 28. Find the amount of the bill?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 500",
            "B": "Rs. 400",
            "C": "Rs. 450",
            "D": "Rs. 550"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Rs. 400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T04-50",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-IV (Equivalent Discount of Three Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 50,
        "question": "The single discount equivalent to a series discount of 60%, 70% and 80%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "97.6%",
            "B": "70%",
            "C": "85%",
            "D": "95.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "97.6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T04-51",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-IV (Equivalent Discount of Three Successive Discounts)",
        "question_number": 51,
        "question": "The single discount equivalent to the discount series of 15%, 20% and 5% is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "35.4%",
            "B": "20%",
            "C": "32%",
            "D": "32.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "35.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-56",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 56,
        "question": "The marked price of a bed sheet is Rs. 500. At the time of its sale, two successive discounts of 10% and 5% are available. Find the selling price (in Rs.) of the bed sheet?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 432.50",
            "B": "Rs. 427.50",
            "C": "Rs. 445.00",
            "D": "Rs. 430.00"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Rs. 427.50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-57",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 57,
        "question": "The marked price of a revolving chair is Rs. 15,000. It is available on two successive discounts of 20% and 12%. What is its selling price (in Rs.)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 9560",
            "B": "Rs. 10560",
            "C": "Rs. 9230",
            "D": "Rs. 10230"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Rs. 10560",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-62",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 62,
        "question": "Ramesh gives 15% additional discount along with a discount of 25% on the marked price of a sofa set. If the selling price of the sofa set is \u20b9 12,750, then find the marked price of the sofa set.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9 22,000",
            "B": "\u20b9 23,000",
            "C": "\u20b9 24,000",
            "D": "\u20b9 20,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9 20,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-63",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 63,
        "question": "A shopkeeper charges \u20b91.50 to photocopy a sheet of paper and a discount of 5.5% is given on all photocopies done after 400 sheets. How much will it cost to photocopy 800 sheets of paper?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,160",
            "B": "\u20b91,167",
            "C": "\u20b91,276",
            "D": "\u20b91,176"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91,167",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-64",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 64,
        "question": "On an item, there is an 18% discount on the marked price of \u20b926,000. After giving an additional season's discount, the item is sold at \u20b916,000. How much was the season's discount correct upto two places of decimal?",
        "options": {
            "A": "24.95%",
            "B": "22.45%",
            "C": "24.65%",
            "D": "35.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "24.95%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-65",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 65,
        "question": "If the price item is increased by 70% and then allows a scheme discount of 5% and 20% on this marked price. If price is paid in cash and additional discount of 20% is allowed then what is his gain percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.25%",
            "B": "3.25%",
            "C": "4.36%",
            "D": "3.36%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "3.36%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-66",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 66,
        "question": "The list price of a hand mixer at a showroom is Rs 2,000 and it is being sold at successive discounts of 15% and 10%. What is its net selling price in rupees?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1,530",
            "B": "1,560",
            "C": "1,440",
            "D": "1,600"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1,530",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-67",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 67,
        "question": "A doll is marked for \u20b92,500. A customer pays \u20b91,800 for it. If the customer got a series of two discounts and the rate of the first discount is 10%, then the rate of the second discount is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "18%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-68",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 68,
        "question": "A shopkeeper, on the eve of Diwali, allowed a series of discounts on television sets. Find the selling price of a television set, if the marked price of television is Rs. 1,200 and successive discounts are 15% and 10%.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 945",
            "B": "Rs. 918",
            "C": "Rs. 975",
            "D": "Rs. 965"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Rs. 918",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-69",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 69,
        "question": "Successive discounts of 10% and 20% are given on the purchase of a purse. If the marked price of the purse is Rs. 2,250, find the selling price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 1320",
            "B": "Rs. 1620",
            "C": "Rs. 1290",
            "D": "Rs. 1520"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Rs. 1620",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-70",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 70,
        "question": "A shopkeeper gives a discount of 24% on the marked price. On a special sale day, he offers a coupon of additional 30% discount after the first discount. If the item is sold for \u20b9 7,700.70, what is the marked price (in \u20b9) of the item?",
        "options": {
            "A": "14475",
            "B": "17475",
            "C": "14745",
            "D": "17745"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "14475",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-71",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 71,
        "question": "A product was offered at a 10% trade discount on the marked price. After a cash discount of 10%, the product was sold for \u20b97,290. The marked price (in \u20b9) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "9,000",
            "B": "8,900",
            "C": "8,510",
            "D": "8,720"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "9,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-72",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 72,
        "question": "The price of one shirt is \u20b9700 in a shop, on which 10% discount is available for all customers. An additional 20% discount is there for the customers who pay in cash. What is the amount a customer has to pay for a shirt if he pays in cash?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9 432",
            "B": "\u20b9 504",
            "C": "\u20b9 523",
            "D": "\u20b9 514"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9 504",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-73",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 73,
        "question": "A vendor bought a book marked at \u20b9850 at successive discounts of 20% and 10%, respectively. He spent \u20b955 on transport and sold the book for \u20b9980. What will be his profit percentage (rounded off to 2 decimal places)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "46.93%",
            "B": "50.65%",
            "C": "48.25%",
            "D": "45.65%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "46.93%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-74",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 74,
        "question": "After offering two successive discounts a toy with a marked price of \u20b9150 is sold at \u20b9105. If the value of the first discount is 12.5%, what is the value of the second discount?",
        "options": {
            "A": "21%",
            "B": "18%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-75",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 75,
        "question": "An article is sold for Rs.747 after successive discounts of 17% and x%. If the marked price of the article is Rs. 1,600, what is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "32.26",
            "B": "43.75",
            "C": "22.12",
            "D": "40.28"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "43.75",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-76",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 76,
        "question": "An electronic store owner allows two successive discounts of 20% and 25% on each item. The store has a reward points scheme which enables a customer to get free shopping worth \u20b90.10 on every 1 reward point credited to the customer's account on previous purchases from the store. A customer decides to buy a laptop that is marked at \u20b972,000. What will be its net selling price if he has 2850 reward points to his credit?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b943,200",
            "B": "\u20b942,915",
            "C": "\u20b942,215",
            "D": "\u20b942,942"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b942,915",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-77",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 77,
        "question": "Two successive discounts, each of x% on the marked price of an article, are equal to a single discount of \u20b9331.20. If the marked price of the article is 920, then the value of x is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "20",
            "B": "18",
            "C": "15",
            "D": "25"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-78",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 78,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b91500. If two successive discounts, each of x%, on the marked price is equal to a single discount of \u20b9587.40, then what will be the selling price of the article if a single discount of x% is given on the marked price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91025",
            "B": "\u20b91155",
            "C": "\u20b91170",
            "D": "\u20b91200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91170",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-79",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 79,
        "question": "An article is listed at \u20b97,600 and the discount offered unit is 10%. What additional discount must be given to bring the net selling price to 5814?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "8%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "15%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-80",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 80,
        "question": "After giving two successive discounts, each of x%, on the market price of an article, the total discount is \u20b9259.20. If the marked price of the article is \u20b9720, then the value of x is :",
        "options": {
            "A": "18",
            "B": "24",
            "C": "25",
            "D": "20"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "20",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-81",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 81,
        "question": "After getting two successive discounts, a calculator with a list price for \u20b9900 is available at \u20b9612. If the value of the second discount is 15%, what is the value of the first discount?",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "12.5%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-82",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 82,
        "question": "Three shopkeepers A, B and C marked an identical article at \u20b94820. A, B and C sold their article on successive discounts of 20% and 20%; 25% and 15%; 30% and 10% respectively. Which shopkeeper gives the maximum discount and how much (in \u20b9)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "C, 1780",
            "B": "A, 1735.20",
            "C": "B, 1800",
            "D": "C, 1783.40"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "C, 1783.40",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-83",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 83,
        "question": "At a factory outlet of a footwear company, every item is available at a discount of 10%. Charu selected footwear marked for \u20b9900. While paying the bill, it was found that the footwear was slightly damaged for which she got another discount of 10%. How much did she pay for the footwear?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9720",
            "B": "\u20b9729",
            "C": "\u20b9810",
            "D": "\u20b9801"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9729",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-84",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 84,
        "question": "On an item having a marked price of \u20b91600. Successive discounts of Y% and Z% were offered. As a result, the item was sold for \u20b91056. Which of the options below cannot be a set of values for Y and Z?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Y = 22, Z = 15.5",
            "B": "Y = 4, Z = 31.25",
            "C": "Y = 20, Z = 17.5",
            "D": "Y = 12, Z = 25"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "Y = 22, Z = 15.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-85",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 85,
        "question": "Two offers were being made to Swaroop for a watch with a marked price of Rs.1,600. Either two successive discounts of 20%, or two discounts of 30% and 10% after each other is offered. If Swaroop opted for the better plan over the other, how much more must he have saved?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs.22",
            "B": "Rs.30",
            "C": "Rs.16",
            "D": "Rs.35"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Rs.16",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-86",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 86,
        "question": "A article is sold at three successive discounts of 10%, 20% and 25%. If the selling price of the article is \u20b92,592 then what is the marked price of the article?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95,200",
            "B": "\u20b94,800",
            "C": "\u20b94,900",
            "D": "\u20b95,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b94,800",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-87",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 87,
        "question": "A bronze article having a marked price of Rs.1,000 is sold during a festive season sale after three successive discounts of 20% and 30% and 10%. What will be the amount (in Rs.) to be paid by a customer if he buys the article during the festival season?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs 508",
            "B": "Rs 564",
            "C": "Rs 504",
            "D": "Rs 496"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Rs 504",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-88",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 88,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is Rs. 2,800. It is sold at three successive discounts of 15%, 8% and 5%. Find the selling price of the article (in Rs.).",
        "options": {
            "A": "1997.26",
            "B": "1923.56",
            "C": "2080.12",
            "D": "1890.20"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "2080.12",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-89",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 89,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marked an article at \u20b95,000. The shopkeeper allows successive discounts of 20%, 15% and 10%. The selling price of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,750",
            "B": "\u20b93,000",
            "C": "\u20b92,800",
            "D": "\u20b93,060"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b93,060",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-90",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 90,
        "question": "A cooker is marked at \u20b912,500. The dealer allows successive discounts of 6%, 6% and 4% on it. What is the net selling price of the cooker?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b910,603.20",
            "B": "\u20b910,306",
            "C": "\u20b912,230",
            "D": "\u20b912,320.60"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b910,603.20",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-91",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 91,
        "question": "A coffee maker with marked price Rs.4,000 is available on successive discounts of 15%, 10% and 5%. Find the selling price of the coffee maker.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs.2,900",
            "B": "Rs.2,903",
            "C": "Rs.2,905",
            "D": "Rs.2,907"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Rs.2,907",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-92",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 92,
        "question": "The cost price of an article is \u20b9214. After allowing three successive discounts of 15%, 20% and 10% on its list price, it is sold for \u20b9153. If it is sold at the list price, then the profit (in \u20b9) will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "49",
            "B": "39",
            "C": "36",
            "D": "45"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "36",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-93",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 93,
        "question": "The selling price of an article marked for \u20b910000 after giving three discounts, 20%, 10% and k% is \u20b96120. What will be selling price (in \u20b9) of the same article if a single discount of (k+20)% is allowed?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6500",
            "B": "8500",
            "C": "6800",
            "D": "8000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "6500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-94",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 94,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b9300. It is sold for \u20b9177.84 after giving three successive discounts of 20%, x% and 5%. What is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15",
            "B": "22",
            "C": "24",
            "D": "18"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-95",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 95,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b920,000. The article is sold after three successive discounts for \u20b910,166. The value of the second and third successive rates is 35% and 15%, respectively. What is the value of the first rate?",
        "options": {
            "A": "6%",
            "B": "9%",
            "C": "8%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-96",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 96,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b91,000. It is sold for \u20b9712.89 after three successive discounts on the marked price, one of 10% and two of x% each. What is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15",
            "B": "11",
            "C": "12",
            "D": "13"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "11",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-97",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 97,
        "question": "A tractor manufacturing company sells each tractor for \u20b95,00,000. Assuming that KISAN firm buys 50 tractors from them as a part of an annual contract, the company offers a trade discount of 10% to KISAN and an additional 2% discount if the payment is made within 30 days. What will be the amount payable by KISAN within 30 days for the consignment?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b922,051,000",
            "B": "\u20b922,050,000",
            "C": "\u20b924,050,020",
            "D": "\u20b922,080,100"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b922,050,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-98",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 98,
        "question": "Ramesh purchased some items from a dealer on 19 November 2019. The bill generated was for \u20b95,480. He had also purchased some items on 10 November 2019 having the bill value of \u20b99,800. He cleared both the bills this time and paid the total amount in cash. If the dealer gives a scheme of 2% discount on the payments done within 10 days and 5% for the payments made in cash at the time of purchase, then find the amount paid by Ramesh on 19 November 2019?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b914,850",
            "B": "\u20b914,810",
            "C": "\u20b914,890",
            "D": "\u20b914,950"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b914,810",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-99",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 99,
        "question": "Raghav went to a shopping mall to purchase clothes. He had two coupons with him, but only one can be used on a single day. Using the first coupon, a total discount of 30% could be obtained on the total amount. Using the second coupon, he will get 80% off on the price of the costliest shirt if he buys at least 3 shirts. What is the price at which Raghav can purchase 3 shirts at a minimum price if the prices of the three shirts are \u20b91,250, \u20b91,540 and \u20b91,375?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,760",
            "B": "\u20b92,915.50",
            "C": "\u20b92,775",
            "D": "\u20b92,933"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b92,915.50",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T05-100",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-V (Series Concept)",
        "question_number": 100,
        "question": "The price of a mobile is \u20b920,000. On Sundays, the shopkeeper offers a cash discount of \u20b91,000 on the purchase of the mobile. Further, if someone purchases it through a credit card, he gives 5% additional discount. If someone is purchasing the mobile on a Sunday through a credit card, then how much does he/she have to pay?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b918,350",
            "B": "\u20b918,900",
            "C": "\u20b918,050",
            "D": "\u20b918,500"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b918,050",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-101",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 101,
        "question": "A shopkeeper allows a discount of 15% on an article and still makes a profit of 20%. What does the shopkeeper pay for an article whose marked price is \u20b97,200?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95,100",
            "B": "\u20b95,120",
            "C": "\u20b96,100",
            "D": "\u20b95,100"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b95,100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-102",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 102,
        "question": "An article is marked at \u20b9550. If it is sold at a discount of 40%, then the selling price becomes 10% more than its cost price. What is the cost price (in \u20b9)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs.220",
            "B": "Rs.330",
            "C": "Rs.300",
            "D": "Rs.200"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Rs.300",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-103",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 103,
        "question": "A shopkeeper allows a discount of 20% on the marked price of an item and thus gains 10%. What is the ratio of the cost price to the marked price of the item?",
        "options": {
            "A": "8 : 11",
            "B": "7 : 10",
            "C": "9 : 13",
            "D": "11 : 14"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "8 : 11",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-104",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 104,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marked the price 20% more than its cost price. If he allows a discount of 30%, then find his loss percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "16%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "16%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-105",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 105,
        "question": "An article marked for \u20b9275 is sold at 5% discount. The seller still gains 4.5%. What did he pay for it?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9250",
            "B": "\u20b9125",
            "C": "\u20b9200",
            "D": "\u20b9225"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9250",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-106",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 106,
        "question": "A shopkeeper gives a 10% discount and still earns 10% profit. The marked price of the item is how many times (correct to 2 decimal places) the cost price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.22",
            "B": "1.24",
            "C": "1.28",
            "D": "1.20"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "1.22",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-107",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 107,
        "question": "By selling an article at 66% of its marked price, a merchant makes a profit of 10%. If he sells the article at 80% of its marked price, then the profit percentage will be.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "33 1/3 %",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "33 2/3 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "33 1/3 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-108",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 108,
        "question": "A 35% profit made when a discount of 35% is given on the marked price of an item. When the discount is 45%, then the profit percentage will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "17 1/13 %",
            "B": "11 3/13 %",
            "C": "14 3/13 %",
            "D": "13 3/17 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "14 3/13 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-109",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 109,
        "question": "Anu allows a 20% discount on the marked price of an article and still makes a profit of 25%. If she gains \u20b944.80 on the sale of the article, then the cost price of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9188.80",
            "B": "\u20b9192.80",
            "C": "\u20b9184.20",
            "D": "\u20b9179.20"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9179.20",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-110",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 110,
        "question": "A shopkeeper allows a discount of 22% to his customers and still gains 36%. Find the marked price (in Rs) of an article which costs Rs 1,092 to the shopkeeper.",
        "options": {
            "A": "1,792",
            "B": "2,024",
            "C": "1,872",
            "D": "1,904"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "1,904",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-111",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 111,
        "question": "Ramesh sells an article for Rs 34,440, after allowing an 18% discount on the marked price and still manages to gain 40% profit. If Ramesh sold the article at a 12% discount on the marked price, then what will be his profit, correct to two places of decimals?",
        "options": {
            "A": "50.42%",
            "B": "48.24%",
            "C": "50.24%",
            "D": "48.42%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "50.24%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-112",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 112,
        "question": "A shopkeeper sells an item at 20% discount on the marked price and earns a profit of 90%. If he sells the same item at 40% discount, then his new profit percentage will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "48.2%",
            "B": "45.8%",
            "C": "41.8%",
            "D": "42.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "42.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-113",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 113,
        "question": "By selling an article for Rs 2,160, Prashant allows a 20% discount and earns 28% profit. If the article is sold without any discount, the profit will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "55%",
            "B": "60%",
            "C": "65%",
            "D": "50%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "60%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-114",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 114,
        "question": "The cost price of a fan is Rs 4,400. A merchant wants to make a 24% profit by selling it. At the time of sale, merchant declares a discount of 12% on the marked price. Find the marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 2,600",
            "B": "Rs. 2,060",
            "C": "Rs. 6,200",
            "D": "Rs. 6,020"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "Rs. 6,200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-115",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 115,
        "question": "A shopkeeper offers a 10% discount on dairy products and still manages to make a 20% profit. What is the actual cost (in \u20b9) to the shopkeeper of a dairy product marked \u20b9420?",
        "options": {
            "A": "315",
            "B": "340",
            "C": "350",
            "D": "325"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "315",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-116",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 116,
        "question": "The price of a treadmill is marked at \u20b91,250. A shopkeeper earns a profit of 14% after allowing a discount of 14% on the marked price. Find the cost price (to the nearest rupee) of the treadmill.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9943",
            "B": "\u20b91,043",
            "C": "\u20b9840",
            "D": "\u20b9845"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9943",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-117",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 117,
        "question": "In a showroom, the marked prices of various items are displayed in such manner that after giving a 10% discount to the customers, the owner of the showroom earns a profit of 20%. What is the ratio of the marked price and cost price of each item?",
        "options": {
            "A": "3 : 4",
            "B": "4 : 3",
            "C": "5 : 2",
            "D": "2 : 5"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "4 : 3",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-118",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 118,
        "question": "A retailer buys 50 pens at the marked price of 44 pens. If he sells these pen at a discount of 1% on the marked price, what is profit percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "12.5%",
            "C": "12%",
            "D": "15%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-119",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 119,
        "question": "The marked price of a television set is \u20b918,000. A shopkeeper gives a discount of 40% and makes a profit of 10%. Find the cost price of the television set.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b97,821 3/11",
            "B": "\u20b99,531 5/11",
            "C": "\u20b99,818 2/11",
            "D": "\u20b98,181 1/11"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b99,818 2/11",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-120",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 120,
        "question": "A shopkeeper gives 20% commission on the retail price of one article and earns 5% profit. If his commission is reduced by 10%, then what is his approximate profit percentage? (Nearest integral value)",
        "options": {
            "A": "18%",
            "B": "10%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "8%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "18%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-121",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 121,
        "question": "A shopkeeper earns a profit of 12% on selling a book at 10% discount on the printed price. The ratio of the cost price to the printed price is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "38 : 55",
            "B": "45 : 56",
            "C": "55 : 38",
            "D": "56 : 45"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "45 : 56",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-122",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 122,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marks an article x% above the cost price and sells it by allowing 30% discount on the marked price. If there is a loss of 4.8%, then what is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "36%",
            "B": "30%",
            "C": "40%",
            "D": "60%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "36%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-123",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 123,
        "question": "A dealer sells an article by allowing a 20% discount on its marked price and still gains 12%. If the cost price of the article is 750, then its marked price (in \u20b9) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "1125",
            "B": "1150",
            "C": "1050",
            "D": "1025"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "1050",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-124",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 124,
        "question": "A merchant fixes the sale price of his goods at 42% above the cost price. He sells his goods at a 15% discount marked price. His percentage of profit (rounded off to the nearest integer) is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "21%",
            "B": "35%",
            "C": "27%",
            "D": "42%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "21%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-125",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 125,
        "question": "The cost price and the marked price of an item are \u20b9720 and \u20b9900 respectively. When it is sold at a discount of x%, then profit is 5x/3%. What is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "7 4/7",
            "B": "8 4/7",
            "C": "5 5/7",
            "D": "5 4/7"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "8 4/7",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-126",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 126,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marks an article at a price such that after giving a discount of x%, he gains 20%. If the cost price and the marked price of the article are \u20b9920 and \u20b91472 respectively, then what is the value of x?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18",
            "B": "20",
            "C": "25",
            "D": "30"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-127",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 127,
        "question": "The cost price of a bat is 75% of the marked price. Calculate the gain percentage after allowing a discount of 15%?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25.6%",
            "B": "13.33%",
            "C": "18.16%",
            "D": "21.33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "13.33%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-128",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 128,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is 26% more than its cost price. If a discount of 32% is given, what will be the loss percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "18.64%",
            "B": "15.25%",
            "C": "12.26%",
            "D": "14.32%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "14.32%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-129",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 129,
        "question": "The marked price of 55 items was equal to the cost price of 99 items. The selling price of 56 items was equal to the marked price of 35 items. Calculate the profit or loss percentage from the sale of each item?",
        "options": {
            "A": "15% profit",
            "B": "12.25% profit",
            "C": "12.5% profit",
            "D": "12.5% loss"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "12.5% profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-130",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 130,
        "question": "If the market price of a bag is 25% above the cost price, and a discount of 18% is declared on it, then find the gain percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "1.5%",
            "B": "2.0%",
            "C": "3.0%",
            "D": "2.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-131",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 131,
        "question": "A shopkeeper decides to raise the marked price of an article by 40%. How much percentage discount should he allow to be able to sell the article at the original marked price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "28 4/7 %",
            "B": "31 2/7 %",
            "C": "24 3/7 %",
            "D": "26 3/7 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "28 4/7 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-132",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 132,
        "question": "Gaurav marks his goods 50% above the cost price and offers a discount of 30% on the marked price to his customers. What is his percentage gain?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2%",
            "B": "3%",
            "C": "4%",
            "D": "5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-133",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 133,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is 25% more than its cost price. If a scheme discount of 40% is given, then the loss percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "15%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "30%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-134",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 134,
        "question": "The marked price of an item is 1.4 times the cost price. In order to earn 23.2% profit, what per cent discount can a shopkeeper allow?",
        "options": {
            "A": "13%",
            "B": "17%",
            "C": "15%",
            "D": "12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T06-135",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VI (Mumtaz Concept)",
        "question_number": 135,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b9660. A shopkeeper allows a discount of 20% and still gets a profit of 10%. If he sells it for \u20b9470, his profit or loss percent, correct to two decimal places will be:",
        "options": {
            "A": "Profit 3.06%",
            "B": "Loss 2.08%",
            "C": "Profit 7.59%",
            "D": "Loss 5.43%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "Loss 2.08%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-136",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 136,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is 20 percent more than its cost price. What minimum discount percentage can be offered by the shopkeeper to sell his article so that there is no loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "16.66%",
            "B": "12.56%",
            "C": "15.33%",
            "D": "13.33%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "16.66%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-137",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 137,
        "question": "The marked price of mustard oil is 10% more than its cost price. At what per cent less than the marked price should it be sold, to have no profit and no loss?",
        "options": {
            "A": "9 2/11 %",
            "B": "9 1/11 %",
            "C": "9 3/11 %",
            "D": "9 4/11 %"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "9 1/11 %",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-138",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 138,
        "question": "An article is market at \u20b9450. If it is sold at a discount of 20%, then the selling price becomes 1.5 times of its cost price. What is the cost price (in \u20b9)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "360",
            "B": "240",
            "C": "330",
            "D": "270"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "240",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-139",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 139,
        "question": "The marked price of an article is \u20b910,927. Due to festive season, a certain percentage of discount is declared. Raju buys an article at reduced price and sells it at \u20b910,927 and makes a profit of 11.5%. What was the percentage discount offered?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10.3%",
            "B": "11.3%",
            "C": "11.5%",
            "D": "10.9%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "10.3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-140",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 140,
        "question": "A shopkeeper bought a machine for \u20b94600 and spent \u20b9500 on its repairs and transport. He marked the machine at 8% above the overall cost price. If he sold the machine for \u20b94681.80 after giving x% discount, then the value of x is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "18",
            "B": "15",
            "C": "20",
            "D": "12"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "15",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-141",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 141,
        "question": "A retailer announces a discount of 30% for selling an air-conditioner marked at \u20b992,000. The cost price of the air-conditioner is 70% below the marked price. He offers a further discount of 20% if the buyer presents his membership card of the retailer's store. The profit of the retailer with the membership card scheme is what percentage of the profit of the retailer without the membership card scheme?",
        "options": {
            "A": "62%",
            "B": "65%",
            "C": "70%",
            "D": "74%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "65%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-142",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 142,
        "question": "A shopkeeper buys three varieties of pulses at \u20b9132, \u20b9160 and \u20b9y per kg respectively and mixes them in the ratio 9 : 2 : 1. The marked price per kg of the blended pulses is fixed at \u20b9238, the shopkeeper gives a discount equal to 1/6 of the marked price and still earns a profit of 40%. What is the value of y?",
        "options": {
            "A": "192",
            "B": "200",
            "C": "184",
            "D": "196"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "192",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-143",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 143,
        "question": "Amit and Bilal buy goods for \u20b91,500 and \u20b92,000, respectively. Amit marks his goods up by y%, while Bilal marks his goods up by 2y% and offers a discount of y%. If both make the same profit, then find the value of y?",
        "options": {
            "A": "10.5%",
            "B": "12%",
            "C": "11.5%",
            "D": "12.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-144",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 144,
        "question": "Rohini purchases a Bluetooth headphone set from a wholesale shop for Rs. 1,700 and fixes its marked price at Rs. 2,000. Later, she allows a discount of 40% on its sale. What is her loss or profit percentage (correct to two decimal places)?",
        "options": {
            "A": "25.19% loss",
            "B": "29.41% gain",
            "C": "29.41% loss",
            "D": "25.19% gain"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "29.41% loss",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-145",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 145,
        "question": "An article costs Rs. 1,000 for a salesman. He fixes its marked price as Rs. 1,500. He sells it to a customer at a discount of 20%. He gives a further discount of 10% for each cash payment. Find the percentage of loss or gain that the salesman makes on sale?",
        "options": {
            "A": "gain 8%",
            "B": "gain 10%",
            "C": "loss 8%",
            "D": "loss 10%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "gain 8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-146",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 146,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marks up the price of the oil by 40% and used a faulty machine which measures 15% less. If the shopkeeper gives a discount of 32%, the profit/loss percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "15% Loss",
            "B": "25% Profit",
            "C": "18% Loss",
            "D": "12% Profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "12% Profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-147",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 147,
        "question": "One company is offering a 25% discount on a particular product. Anurag visited a store. He was trying to find a deal that would allow him to save at least Rs 390. How many minimum items should he purchase if each item costs Rs 340?",
        "options": {
            "A": "7",
            "B": "4",
            "C": "6",
            "D": "5"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-148",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 148,
        "question": "A dozen pairs of gloves of Rs 180 are available at a discount of 10%. How many pairs of gloves can be bought for Rs. 54?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2",
            "B": "8",
            "C": "4",
            "D": "6"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "4",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-149",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 149,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marks an article at Rs 150 and sells it at a discount of 25%. He also gives a gift worth Rs 2.5. If he still makes a 10% profit, then the cost price (in Rs) of the article is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "100",
            "B": "175",
            "C": "112",
            "D": "125"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "100",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-150",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 150,
        "question": "What is the discount that Rohan should offer on the remaining Rs 8,000 of a laptop priced at Rs 48,000, given that, he has already given a 12% discount on the first Rs 28,000 and 8% discount on the next Rs 12,000 to match the discount amount of 9.5% given on the total price?",
        "options": {
            "A": "402",
            "B": "420",
            "C": "240",
            "D": "204"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "240",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-151",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 151,
        "question": "A company sells goods at a markup of 25% above the cost price. During a sale, the company offers a 10% discount on the marked price. If the customer pays Rs 540 after the discount, then what was the original cost price of the goods?",
        "options": {
            "A": "Rs. 460",
            "B": "Rs. 450",
            "C": "Rs. 470",
            "D": "Rs. 480"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "Rs. 480",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-152",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 152,
        "question": "A shopkeeper marks up his goods 32% above the cost price and gives a discount of 21% on the marked price. Find his gain percentage on the goods.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4.28%",
            "B": "8.42%",
            "C": "4.82%",
            "D": "8.24%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "4.28%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-153",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 153,
        "question": "A retailer gets a discount of 40% on the printed price of an article. If the retailer sells it at the printed price, his gain percentage is:",
        "options": {
            "A": "66 2/3%",
            "B": "37 3/5%",
            "C": "66 1/3%",
            "D": "33 1/3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "66 1/3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-154",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 154,
        "question": "In a showroom the price of a washing machine is \u20b9650. The customer gets cash discount of \u20b92,000 and gets a scratch card promising percentage discount of 10% to 15%. Determine the difference between the least and maximum selling price of this washing machine.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b93,150",
            "B": "\u20b93,570",
            "C": "\u20b93,200",
            "D": "\u20b93,650"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b93,150",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-155",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 155,
        "question": "The marked price of every item being sold by a wholesaler was \u20b9400. The wholesaler was offering clearance sale under which a customer buying four items paid for one item and further 5% discount on the amount payable under 'Buy 4 Get 1 Free'. What was the effective discount percentage?",
        "options": {
            "A": "30%",
            "B": "25%",
            "C": "28.75%",
            "D": "24%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "24%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-156",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 156,
        "question": "A hotel is giving discount of 12% on room rent. Additionally, the hotel is offering a 5% discount on payment using SBI Silver Card. Find the amount paid by the customer if rent is \u20b91,500 per room per day.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,496",
            "B": "\u20b92,544",
            "C": "\u20b92,508",
            "D": "\u20b92,616"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b92,508",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-157",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 157,
        "question": "In a shop, a discount of 5% is given and if purchase amount is more than \u20b92,000, an additional discount of 10% is given. Find the final amount paid by customer if bill is \u20b92,500.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,500",
            "B": "\u20b92,225.5",
            "C": "\u20b92,375.5",
            "D": "\u20b92,137.5"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b92,137.5",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-158",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 158,
        "question": "If Ram purchases items on which successive discounts of 6%, 8%, and 12% are offered, and he pays \u20b92,550, find the marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,400",
            "B": "\u20b92,500",
            "C": "\u20b92,450",
            "D": "\u20b92,550"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b92,500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-159",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 159,
        "question": "Rakhi purchased a basket, wallet and belt. Discounts were 8%, 10% and 8% respectively. If she paid \u20b9350, find original amount.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9510",
            "B": "\u20b9580",
            "C": "\u20b9600",
            "D": "\u20b9519"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9580",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-160",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 160,
        "question": "Electricity bill paid before due date gives 10% reduction. If reduction is \u20b923, find bill amount.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9230",
            "B": "\u20b9250",
            "C": "\u20b9380",
            "D": "\u20b9520"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b9230",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-161",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 161,
        "question": "Vikram allows discounts of 20% and 10%. If marked price \u20b9600, find profit.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b972",
            "B": "\u20b948",
            "C": "\u20b954",
            "D": "\u20b934"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b954",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-162",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 162,
        "question": "Neeraj gives successive discounts 15% and 20%. If selling price \u20b94,496, find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "12.4%",
            "D": "15.6%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "12.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-163",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 163,
        "question": "Dealer buys article at \u20b9100 and gives successive discounts 10% and 20%. Find marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9576.07",
            "B": "\u20b9581.07",
            "C": "\u20b9576.00",
            "D": "\u20b9581.00"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9581.00",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-164",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 164,
        "question": "Marked price \u20b9600. Two successive discounts 10% and 20%. Find gain percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "18%",
            "D": "20%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "18%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-165",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 165,
        "question": "Marked price \u20b960% above CP. Successive discounts 10% and 20%. Find loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "3.5%",
            "B": "2.4%",
            "C": "3%",
            "D": "2%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "2.4%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-166",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 166,
        "question": "Marked price of 85 items equals cost price of 153 items. Selling price of 100 items equals marked price of 65 items. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12.5% loss",
            "B": "12.5% profit",
            "C": "15% profit",
            "D": "12.75% profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "12.5% profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-167",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 167,
        "question": "Article costs \u20b94,000 and marked \u20b94,400. Discount 25% and extra 15%. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "34%",
            "B": "32%",
            "C": "43%",
            "D": "36%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "34%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-168",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 168,
        "question": "Ram marks goods 35% above CP and gives discounts 40% and 15%. Find overall discount percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "12.75",
            "B": "11.25",
            "C": "11.75",
            "D": "10"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "11.25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-169",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 169,
        "question": "Shop offers discounts 10%, 5%, and 50%. Find cash paid for biscuits costing \u20b930 each.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9670.25",
            "B": "\u20b9608.25",
            "C": "\u20b9675",
            "D": "\u20b9667.05"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9608.25",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-170",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 170,
        "question": "Book marked \u20b9300. Discount and free scheme applied. Find effective discount percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "32%",
            "B": "31.5%",
            "C": "32.5%",
            "D": "32.75%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "32.5%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-171",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 171,
        "question": "A discount of 20% is given for the purchase of two books by a bookseller and a discount of 25% is offered if a customer buys more than two books. A 10% discount is being offered to all the customers on purchase of one book. An additional 5% discount is given to students. Sohan, a student of M.Com, buys a book for \u20b9513. What was the marked price of the book?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9650",
            "B": "\u20b9540",
            "C": "\u20b9600",
            "D": "\u20b9605"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b9600",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-172",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 172,
        "question": "Ramanna purchased raw materials for producing sewing machine of Talbot, 22.5% of the raw materials could not be utilised and got wasted. 80% of the cost of raw materials used was added as manufacturing cost. If Ramanna could sell his product at a price equal to overall profit of 20% after offering a discount of 20%, how many times of the total cost was the raw material purchased?",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.44 times",
            "B": "2.40 times",
            "C": "2.43 times",
            "D": "2.40 times"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "2.40 times",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-173",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 173,
        "question": "A manufacturer announces trade discount of 30% on his products for his dealers. One of the dealers purchased products manufactured by the company at \u20b925,000. What is the amount of trade discount?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b935,000",
            "B": "\u20b945,000",
            "C": "\u20b910,500",
            "D": "\u20b945,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b910,500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-174",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 174,
        "question": "Shopkeeper marks up his price for an item at 25% less offers discount of 15%. The same item is marked at 20% by another shopkeeper and sold at a discount of 12%. Who gets a better deal in terms of % profit and by what percent?",
        "options": {
            "A": "By B, 5.6%",
            "B": "By B, 0.65%",
            "C": "By A, 0.55%",
            "D": "By A, 6.25%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "By A, 6.25%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-175",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 175,
        "question": "A seller offers discount of 12% if total sale price of different products purchased by a single customer is below \u20b93,000, and discount of 15% if total sale value is above \u20b93,000. A shirt costing \u20b9900 and a saree costing \u20b91,900 are sold after discount. How much discount did Ramana get?",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b92,953.60",
            "B": "\u20b93,005.40",
            "C": "\u20b92,645.60",
            "D": "\u20b92,635.60"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b92,645.60",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-176",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 176,
        "question": "On the tag price, seller offers 10% discount and a cashback of \u20b9250. He still earns 10% profit. If cost price is \u20b91,200, find marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91447.44",
            "B": "\u20b91777.44",
            "C": "\u20b91744.44",
            "D": "\u20b91774.44"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91744.44",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-177",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 177,
        "question": "A shopkeeper gives discount of 12% on purchase of 10 kg of sugar. Cost price of sugar is \u20b930/kg and machine weight shows 900 g for 1 kg. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "30.18%",
            "B": "12.0%",
            "C": "22.25%",
            "D": "23.85%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "23.85%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-178",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 178,
        "question": "Dealer sells article at 85% after offering 15% discount. Without discount he earns \u20b925. Find cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9950",
            "B": "\u20b91000",
            "C": "\u20b9900",
            "D": "\u20b91000"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b91000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-179",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 179,
        "question": "Seller gives 8% discount on marked price. He spends \u20b9X on promotion and gets total cost \u20b92,50,000 and marked price is 10% more than cost price. Find X.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7500",
            "B": "3000",
            "C": "6000",
            "D": "4500"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "4500",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-180",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 180,
        "question": "Kavita bought table at 30% discount and sold at 48% increase. If original price \u20b98,000, find extra amount earned.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b95.6%",
            "B": "\u20b9280",
            "C": "\u20b96%",
            "D": "\u20b9360"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9360",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-181",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII (Miscellaneous Questions)",
        "question_number": 181,
        "question": "A bookseller supplies books to a book-seller at a 20% discount on the list price of \u20b91,574.08. If the book seller sells books at the list price and his net profit is \u20b945.40, determine his profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "285.34%",
            "B": "285.52%",
            "C": "273.50%",
            "D": "282.22%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "282.22%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-182",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 182,
        "question": "The ratio of cost price (CP) and marked price (MP) of an article is 4 : 7. A discount of 20% is given on MP and the shopkeeper made a profit of \u20b980. Find the CP of the article.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9190",
            "B": "\u20b9170",
            "C": "\u20b9200",
            "D": "\u20b9180"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "\u20b9170",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-183",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 183,
        "question": "A dealer gives a discount of 7% on the marked price and gives an article free for every 25 articles purchased. Find the increase in marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "38.42%",
            "B": "34.84%",
            "C": "34.48%",
            "D": "38.24%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "34.48%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-184",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 184,
        "question": "Shyam purchased a packet of 16 pens and got 4 pens free. He marked the price 20% more than CP. If he did not allow any discount and sold all pens at this price, find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "37.1%",
            "B": "50%",
            "C": "36.5%",
            "D": "48%"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "37.1%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-185",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 185,
        "question": "Arun purchased 50 kg rice at 15% discount and got 5 kg free. If he sold rice at marked price, find approximate profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "24.7%",
            "B": "25.2%",
            "C": "22.8%",
            "D": "23.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "25.2%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-186",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 186,
        "question": "On purchase of articles worth \u20b910,000, shopkeeper offers flat discount of \u20b9500 and additional 7% discount on credit card. Find amount paid.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b98,835",
            "B": "\u20b99,000",
            "C": "\u20b98,815",
            "D": "\u20b99,300"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b98,835",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-187",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 187,
        "question": "Marked price is 40% above cost price. Selling price is 73 1/2% of marked price. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "2.9%",
            "B": "2.7%",
            "C": "2.6%",
            "D": "2.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "2.6%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-188",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 188,
        "question": "Store declares discount of 60% on one shampoo bottle and same discount on another. Find profit percentage if cost price is 60% below marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "60%",
            "B": "64%",
            "C": "75%",
            "D": "54%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "75%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-189",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 189,
        "question": "Virendra purchased items worth \u20b9400,000 and got discount and paid through credit card including surcharge. Find actual cost including surcharge.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b91,53,000",
            "B": "\u20b91,58,100",
            "C": "\u20b91,63,200",
            "D": "\u20b91,47,900"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "\u20b91,63,200",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-190",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 190,
        "question": "A dishonest trader marks goods 50% above CP and allows 20% discount. He uses faulty weight of 900g for 1kg. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "33%",
            "B": "36%",
            "C": "27%",
            "D": "24%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "36%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-191",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 191,
        "question": "Marked price of chair is 10% more than CP. After 10% discount, selling price \u20b9300. Find loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20%",
            "B": "12.5%",
            "C": "25%",
            "D": "17%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "17%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-192",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 192,
        "question": "Marked prices of trouser and jacket ratio is 1:3. Discount 20% and overall discount 30%. Find jacket discount percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "28.56%",
            "B": "41.25%",
            "C": "33.33%",
            "D": "16.66%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "16.66%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-193",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 193,
        "question": "A shop gives 8% discount and additional 20% if bill exceeds \u20b95,000. Find amount paid for goods worth \u20b96,750.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b96,724",
            "B": "\u20b96,824",
            "C": "\u20b96,624",
            "D": "\u20b96,524"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b96,524",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-194",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 194,
        "question": "Marked price of pen is 25% above CP. After \u20b930 discount, SP \u20b9220. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "10%",
            "B": "15%",
            "C": "20%",
            "D": "17.5%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "20%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-195",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 195,
        "question": "Shopkeeper marks goods 30% above CP and gives 10% discount. Also gives free 1kg sugar worth \u20b970. Find net profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7%",
            "B": "7.2%",
            "C": "6%",
            "D": "6.3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "6.3%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-196",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 196,
        "question": "Shopkeeper gives 18% discount and sells for \u20b948,380. Without discount profit is 18%. Find cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b955,000",
            "B": "\u20b950,000",
            "C": "\u20b948,500",
            "D": "\u20b959,000"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "\u20b955,000",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-197",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 197,
        "question": "Trader sold article for \u20b9440 after 12% discount. Without discount profit 25%. Find cost price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "420",
            "B": "350",
            "C": "400",
            "D": "380"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "400",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-198",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 198,
        "question": "Trader gives 25% discount. If CP increases 30%, find new discount for 15% profit.",
        "options": {
            "A": "4.87%",
            "B": "5.08%",
            "C": "4.32%",
            "D": "5.12%"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "5.12%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-199",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 199,
        "question": "Shopkeeper sold article at 4/5 marked price and suffered 3 1/3% loss. Find profit percent if sold at marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "20",
            "B": "22",
            "C": "18",
            "D": "21"
        },
        "correct_option": "A",
        "answer": "20",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-200",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 200,
        "question": "Marked price is 25% above CP. Discount given and loss 8%. Find discount percent.",
        "options": {
            "A": "25.6%",
            "B": "25.2%",
            "C": "26.8%",
            "D": "26.4%"
        },
        "correct_option": "C",
        "answer": "26.8%",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-201",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 201,
        "question": "Shopkeeper allows 18% discount and still gains 23%. If gain \u20b918.40, find marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "\u20b9140",
            "B": "\u20b9125",
            "C": "\u20b9120",
            "D": "\u20b9146"
        },
        "correct_option": "D",
        "answer": "\u20b9146",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-202",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 202,
        "question": "Trader marks goods 40% above CP. Sells 70% at marked price and rest at 40% discount. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "23.4",
            "B": "24.2",
            "C": "23.2",
            "D": "24.4"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "24.2",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-203",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 203,
        "question": "Marked price of 42 items equals cost price of 70 items. Selling price of 25 items equals marked price of 21 items. Find profit or loss percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "42% profit",
            "B": "29% profit",
            "C": "29% loss",
            "D": "40% profit"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "29% profit",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-204",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 204,
        "question": "Rohan purchased an item with 13.5% discount on cash and 6.25% surcharge on credit card. Paid \u20b940,964. Find marked price.",
        "options": {
            "A": "35700",
            "B": "38752",
            "C": "32988",
            "D": "38554"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "38752",
        "explanation": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "DISC-T07-205",
        "chapter": "Discount",
        "type": "Type-VII",
        "question_number": 205,
        "question": "Retailer buys 220 chocolates at marked price of 198 items and sells each at 3.7% discount. Find profit percentage.",
        "options": {
            "A": "7%",
            "B": "7.2%",
            "C": "6%",
            "D": "6.3%"
        },
        "correct_option": "B",
        "answer": "7.2%",
        "explanation": ""
    }
]